<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<bandPreview startID="">
<interFace buttonLabel="MORE INFO" />
<item id="0">
<artistName><![CDATA[120 DAYS]]></artistName>
<country>N</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Odeon]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Sat, 07 Jul 2012 23:00:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341694800]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341694800]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Electronic dark rock inspired by Manchester and Düsseldorf.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext"> Every now and then temperatures run extremely low in the remote regions of Norway. You can hear it on a band like 120 Days from Kristiansund.</p>
<p class="bodytext">The Norwegians play cold, dark electronic rock that sounds like Kraftwerk’s hometown Düsseldorf in the 70s and Manchester in the 90s.</p>
<p class="bodytext">120 Days do not overburden their audience with a deluge of albums. Instead, the band's sound has been allowed to mature, grown and mutate. With <em>120 Days II<br /></em> (the follow-up to the debut album from 2006) the Norwegians prove that a long maturation process can do good for electronic dark rock. The record bodes well for a rock rave full of laser lights, Norwegian cold degrees and house hypnosis.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Smalltown Supersound/VME</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/5d3bda45e3.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/53e7425e26.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/120-days-1/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="1">
<artistName><![CDATA[THE ABYSSINIANS]]></artistName>
<country>JAM</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Odeon]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Thu, 05 Jul 2012 22:00:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341518400]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341518400]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Roots reggae from when the genre was young.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">The original nobility of reggae invites you to their court at Roskilde Festival. The Abyssinians’ song ”Satta Massagana” from 1969 is regarded by many as the defining hymn of Rastafarian culture.</p>
<p class="bodytext">The core members of the band are grey-haired veterans today. But The Abyssinians continue to spread the message of revolution and their sun-soaked musical genre, which during their career has become a cherished far from the beaches of Jamaica.</p>
<p class="bodytext">The Abyssinians are a must see for any reggae and dub aficionado. Show up and experience the history and some genuine Jamaican legends. Hang around for the beautiful vocal harmonies and the spiritual chanting for Jah, the king of kings.   </p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/d5db6437db.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/354992c32c.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/the-abyssinians/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="2">
<artistName><![CDATA[ADDISON GROOVE]]></artistName>
<country>UK</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Apollo]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Sat, 07 Jul 2012 22:00:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341691200]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341691200]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Hyperkinetic bass music with elements of Chicago and Bristol.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">The influential Brit Antony Williams already made a name for himself on the dubstep scene when he collected scalps under the moniker Headhunter. But it's as Addison Groove that he has made his biggest impact on the bass music scene – especially with the unforgettable &quot;Footcrab&quot;.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Addison Groove combines naughty Chicago-esque clubbing sounds like juke or ghetto house with British bass and dubstep using cool synth themes, trippy 808 drum machines and looped vocal samples.</p>
<p class="bodytext">You have to possess a backside made of stone to be able to sit still when faced with the result of this genre mash-up.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: 50 Weapons / import</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/7329207b0e.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/d2a7e8f9d9.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/addison-groove/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="3">
<artistName><![CDATA[ADRIAN LUX]]></artistName>
<country>S</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Apollo Countdown]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Tue, 03 Jul 2012 22:00:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341345600]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341345600]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Dance pop with a high hit frequency.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Adrian Lux immodestly claims that he cannot write anything but hits. This is more than boasting from a Swedish Adonis.</p>
<p class="bodytext">&quot;Can't Sleep&quot;, &quot;Strawberry&quot; and &quot;Teenage Crime&quot; have already proven their worth on both the charts and the dance floors.</p>
<p class="bodytext">With his carefree blend of house and pop, the young DJ, producer and musician with the high voice has already won over Tiësto, Justice and the Swedish House Mafia.<br /> <br /> Now it's your turn to be convinced.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Ultra / Universal</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="WARM-UP" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/3d9de07fea.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/e048ff2ce4.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/adrian-lux/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="4">
<artistName><![CDATA[AFRICA HITECH]]></artistName>
<country>UK</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Apollo]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Sun, 08 Jul 2012 18:00:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341763200]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341763200]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[British bass sound with an African aftertaste.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Mark Pritchard and Steve Spacek are two experienced and respected lads in progressive electronic music.</p>
<p class="bodytext">With Africa Hitech the two Brits weave together a global-scented sound tapestry that contains traces of not only Africa and the Caribbean but also Chicago and London's steamy nightclubs.</p>
<p class="bodytext">The result is a psychedelic hotchpotch of robotic rhythms, bass, ghost vocals and vitamin-D-rich equator sun. A kind of digital multiple wedding between dubstep, ghetto house and drowsy techno in the middle of the African savannah.</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/9453fafb82.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/c59e0322b1.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/africa-hitech/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="5">
<artistName><![CDATA[ALABAMA SHAKES]]></artistName>
<country>US</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Odeon]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Sun, 08 Jul 2012 20:30:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341772200]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341772200]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Swingin’ soul and rampant R&B from the South.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Few places have defined the sound of the American South as much as the state of Alabama, and few bands manage to combine good old-fashioned greasy soul with genuine R&amp;B as much as Alabama Shakes. </p>
<p class="bodytext">With the debut album Boys &amp; Girls on the move from hype to hit lists, the quartet from Athens, Alabama prove that their musical intensity and sense of tradition have far from suffered from the fact that they are one of the hottest bands at the moment.  </p>
<p class="bodytext">Singer and guitarist Brittany Howard has already been named the next big queen of rock, so don’t miss a tasteful and swinging bite of the South.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Rough Trade / Playground </p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/19bcf9a7a8.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/be416601f9.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/alabama-shakes/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="6">
<artistName><![CDATA[THE ALAEV FAMILY]]></artistName>
<country>ISR/TJ</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Gloria]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Thu, 05 Jul 2012 21:30:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341516600]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341516600]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Central Asian music clan with a multi-cultural sound.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">With foothold in the percussive traditions of Central Asia, several generations of The Alaev Family perform together. The age span is, according to themselves, 15 to 79.</p>
<p class="bodytext">In 1991 the entire Alaev family immigrated from Tajikistan to Israel. You will notice this in the multi-ethnical music, which employs accordions, angry violins and Turkish-sounding scales on the clarinet. The music grooves with more exhilaration than a wedding where half of Tel Aviv is invited.</p>
<p class="bodytext">With The Alaev Family you will get a cheerful demonstration of how ancient family traditions can withstand the tooth of time and be carried forward proudly by younger generations. This is further evidence to the fact that Israel has become the centre of several exciting genre clashes.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: High Fidelity / Import</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/ee3bb94add.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/794f87bbab.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/the-alaev-family/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="7">
<artistName><![CDATA[AMADOU & MARIAM]]></artistName>
<country>MALI</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Orange]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Sun, 08 Jul 2012 19:30:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341768600]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341768600]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[The First Couple of African music.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">In the light of their numerous appearances at Roskilde Festival, we are proud to call Amadou &amp; Mariam – Africa's musical First Couple – true regulars.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Africa, or Mali to be precise, has never sounded as accessible as it does with these blind veterans. The pair unites funk, rock, tribal song and pop in a musical mixture, which is both melodious by Western standards and full of African flavour.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Santigold, TV On The Radio and several other Western VIP's feature on the duo's latest record <em>Folila</em>. A fine example of the blurring of borders in music, which has become a trademark for the duo as well as Roskilde Festival.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Because Music / Warner­</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>2</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/f6cc54f34e.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/b49a2066e3.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/amadou-mariam-1/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="8">
<artistName><![CDATA[SAM AMIDON]]></artistName>
<country>US</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Gloria]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Thu, 05 Jul 2012 19:45:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341510300]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341510300]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[The American song treasury in new clothes.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">The American song treasury is a chest loaded with rubies, jewels and pure gold.<br /> </p>
<p class="bodytext">With ukulele and acoustic guitar as the only accompaniment, Sam Amidon interprets and renews old folk songs and hymns. Only occasionally you get to hear songs by artists such as R. Kelly or Tears For Fears. This New Yorker has promoted a rich music heritage to a new generation.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Experience how rustic songs with the right interpreter can quiver of longing, loneliness and raw wisdom of life as if the ink in the songbook was still wet.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Bedroom Community / import</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/930077f113.png]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/64947c9601.png]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/sam-amidon/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="9">
<artistName><![CDATA[AMSTERDANCE feat. JESSE VOORN, DENNIS CHRISTOPHER and SAM O’NEALL]]></artistName>
<country>NL</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Apollo]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Jul 2012 20:00:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341597600]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341597600]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[House, techno and trance from Amsterdam's finest suppliers.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Under the banner Amsterdance, two enterprising and local-patriotic music lovers have created a concept that brings Amsterdam's red-hot club scene over the Dutch border.</p>
<p class="bodytext">At Roskilde Festival 2012 you can experience shooting star DJ Jesse Voorn who knows how to distribute his progressive house across the continents. His  radio show is listened to in more than 15 countries, and he tours as a  DJ from Miami to Moscow.</p>
<p class="bodytext">During this club extravaganza you can also experience one of Dennis Christopher's raw and powerful DJ sets and Sam O'Nealls innovative and funky ditto.</p>
<p class="bodytext">It will be a night full of an irresistible combination of deep tribal-like beats, minimal  trance-inducing structures. At the same time you sense a pop sensibility amid the edgy  house, techno and trance.</p>
<p class="bodytext">The team behind Amsterdance creates a hot celebration, worthy of Holland's most famous and infamous city.</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/08da2a0a62.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/0e7c71542a.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/amsterdance-feat-jesse-voorn-dennis-christopher-and-sam-oneall/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="10">
<artistName><![CDATA[ANALOGIK]]></artistName>
<country>DK</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Cosmopol]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Thu, 05 Jul 2012 19:15:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341508500]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341508500]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Festive and colourful style confusion.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext"> Analogik's crazy but good-natured blend of wind music, accordion playing, surf and Dixieland jazz is just right for wonderfully absurd and totally unpredictable concerts.</p>
<p class="bodytext">The cheerful hippies proved so at Roskilde Festival in 2009. In 2012 we welcome them back as a well-traveled, more experienced, more bearded, equally nuts ensemble.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Earlier, Analogik looked towards the Balkans. On the coming full length <em>New</em><em> Seeland</em> inspiration is particularly found in Ethiopia. Whichever way you approach this genre-transcending party music, one thing is certain: Analogik is a group of daredevils who have more fun on exotic paths than on the beaten track. </p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Jenka Music / VME</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/2d2de36c5f.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/feaeca1eae.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/analogik-2/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="11">
<artistName><![CDATA[APPARATJIK]]></artistName>
<country>INT</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Orange]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Thu, 05 Jul 2012 01:00:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341442800]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341529200]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Seance from the future led by forces from a-ha, Mew and Coldplay.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">The future has arrived at Roskilde Festival. It is called Apparatjik.</p>
<p class="bodytext">With an until now unseen coupling of pop music, quantum theory and rocket science, the four man super group has ventured into the same regions of the galaxy found in the dreams of only the most daring science fiction authors.</p>
<p class="bodytext">A group containing super producer Martin Terefe and members of Mew, Coldplay and a-ha ensures that the music holds a dream-like, floating sensation as well as highly catchy synth melodies. At the same time it is evident that Apparatjik has put on the space suits and severed the connection to our blue-green world.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Expect yet another unique experiment with the concept of concert at Roskilde Festival – equal parts electronic pop party and revolutionary art installation.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: A:larm</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>2</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/615affa456.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/a7bbb37e0b.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/apparatjik/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="12">
<artistName><![CDATA[ARAABMUZIK]]></artistName>
<country>US</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Apollo]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Thu, 05 Jul 2012 17:00:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341500400]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341500400]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Harsh, instrumental hip hop.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">A session with AraabMuzik is a superior display of virtuoso skills, darkening the future of the guitar solo.</p>
<p class="bodytext">With his beat-up MPC – an advanced drum and sample machine – as a starting point, Abraham Orellana creates harsh, cut-up, MC-free hip hop that mutates between trance, mash-up, dubstep and countless other urban, electronic genres.</p>
<p class="bodytext">&quot;You are now listening to AraabMuzik&quot;, you’re told time and time again on the breakthrough album <em>Electronic Dream</em>. It’s a self-conscious swagger but also a necessary anchorage point in the middle of a hot and schizophrenic show of force.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Duke Productions / import</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/5cf910db85.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/f5c29bea8a.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/araabmuzik/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="13">
<artistName><![CDATA[ARS NOVA]]></artistName>
<country>DK</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Odeon]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Sun, 08 Jul 2012 12:30:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341743400]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341743400]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Classical vocal ensemble performs composers from the 20th century.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Ars Nova gives you a glimpse of another world.</p>
<p class="bodytext">In the middle of Roskilde Festival's many throbbing rhythms and amplified sounds, one of Europe's leading vocal ensembles join in, ready to tickle the senses with an eclectic programme of advanced choral music.</p>
<p class="bodytext">With the acclaimed conductor Paul Hillier at the helm, Ars Nova fills the space with harmony, classical beaut, carousel-rotating loops and hypnotic repetition.</p>
<p class="bodytext">At this Roskilde debut, the honoured ensemble will focus on minimalist works from the 20th century by Terry Riley, David Lang, Steve Reich, Philip Glass and Arvo Pärt.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: DaCapo</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/71585bd8d2.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/7b823718e1.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/ars-nova/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="14">
<artistName><![CDATA[A$AP ROCKY]]></artistName>
<country>US</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Cosmopol]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Thu, 05 Jul 2012 23:00:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341522000]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341522000]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[The new golden boy of New York hip hop.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Rakim Mayers, better known as A$AP Rocky, has rapped his way onto the hiphop VIP list with certainty. And with plenty of reasons for this “pretty motherfucker” to brag. </p>
<p class="bodytext">A$AP Rocky is flamboyant hiphop from a self-assured innovator of the New York school. This golden boy’s songs deals with illegal smoking waxed sports car, Cristal, women thighs and rustled dollar bills. </p>
<p class="bodytext"><em>LiveLoveA</em>$<em>AP</em> consolidated A$AP Rocky’s potential within the wide music press – his mixtape offers several reasons to why you should look forward to this rapper’s Roskilde debut as well. </p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Polo Grounds / Sony Music</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/559377cfff.png]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/c7ee2bec25.png]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/aap-rocky/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="15">
<artistName><![CDATA[BALOJI]]></artistName>
<country>CD</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Cosmopol]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Jul 2012 00:30:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341527400]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341613800]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[European rap with Congolese flavour.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Originally, the impeccably dressed Baloji was a member of the popular hip hop collective Starflam. But after having decided to put life as a musician behind him, his Congolese background came knocking on his door.</p>
<p class="bodytext">The solo debut album <em>Hotel Impala</em> was a response to a letter from his mother back home in Congo. They hadn’t seen each other for about 25 years. The album became a success and placed Baloji in the field of central European African-inspired hip hop.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Congolese funk and raw rumba are ingeniously manifested through soul, rap and Afrobeat in organic hand-played music with French, Swahili and Bantu as native languages; “Afropean” is what this re-emerging musician calls himself. </p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Crammed Dics / import</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/dd204319c4.png]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/c283443dbd.png]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/baloji/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="16">
<artistName><![CDATA[BARONESS]]></artistName>
<country>US</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Odeon]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Jul 2012 16:00:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341583200]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341583200]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Progressive Southern metal.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">The originally black-coloured metal genre has long since exploded in fireworks of colours and genre shifts.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Baroness have with <em>Red Album</em> and <em>Blue Record</em> made a name for themselves as one of the most progressive front-runners of Southern metal, alongside like-minded Roskilde acts such as Mastodon and Kylesa.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Power metal, psychedelia and dirty 70s rock are thrown into the cement mixer, and out comes a refined, majestic and crushingly brutal rock monster.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Baroness master a balancing act that many bands should envy. Their music is full of artiness and curlicues but will still excite the many beer-thirsty rock fans at the festival site.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Relapse / Cosmos Music Group</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/23f3fd1a2a.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/5187fff5c7.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/baroness/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="17">
<artistName><![CDATA[THE BARONS OF TANG]]></artistName>
<country>AUS</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Pavilion]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Sun, 08 Jul 2012 17:00:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341759600]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341759600]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Manic, well executed circus punk.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Forget spinning for a while. The circus punks from The Barons of Tang will make you pogo so hard that the loss of calories will be the same.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Gogol Bordello fans should prepare to point their arms skyward. Fans of Ornette Coleman, Frank Zappa and Mr. Bungle will also appreciate the mastery of instruments and the many changes in genre.</p>
<p class="bodytext">With their mix of polka, hardcore, tango and brass, the insane Aussies create cacophonic concerts that leave the audience bruised, battered – and ready for more.</p>
<p class="bodytext">A manic ride across the plains filled with punk attitude and a gipsy twinkle in the eye.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: The Planet Company / import</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/c0bf6cfb71.png]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/00e5476be2.png]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/the-barons-of-tang/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="18">
<artistName><![CDATA[THE BEARDY DURFS]]></artistName>
<country>DK</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Pavilion Junior]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Mon, 02 Jul 2012 16:00:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341237600]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341237600]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[DIY noise rock.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">The do-it-yourself philosophy, DIY, thrives well in an age when anyone can buy some sparse equipment and release their material online.</p>
<p class="bodytext">The Beardy Durfs are offshoots of this school. The two lads from Copenhagen make broken-up noise rock that mixes white noise with sonic pleasure. From psychedelically shimmering beauty to aggressive, minimal punk.</p>
<p class="bodytext">The Beardy Durfs are nectar from the Copenhagen underground.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Pad and Pen / Target Distribution</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="WARM-UP" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/de8d40e827.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/ea0c17319e.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/the-beardy-durfs/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="19">
<artistName><![CDATA[BEASTIE RESPOND]]></artistName>
<country>DK</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Apollo Countdown]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Tue, 03 Jul 2012 17:30:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341329400]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341329400]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Drum'n'bass-leaning electronic music.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">The Copenhagen-based nightclub Dunkel houses some of the city's most interesting electronic sounds. People, who have visited the club, might have listened to producer Tobias Pedersen who is a house DJ and booking agent for the dark rooms.</p>
<p class="bodytext">The Dane’s rhythms are a mix of electro, techno, dubstep and especially drum'n'bass.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Beastie Respond presents some exciting dark sounds that may soon bring him out of the nightclub darkness and towards an even bigger audience.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Teal</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="WARM-UP" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/4134a36d6d.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/9619f07fd9.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/beastie-respond/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="20">
<artistName><![CDATA[BEHEMOTH]]></artistName>
<country>PL</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Arena]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Sun, 08 Jul 2012 16:30:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341757800]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341757800]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Poland's kings of extreme metal.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Poland is home of more than God-fearing Catholics. The East European country has a respected death metal scene where Behemoth takes the black throne as one of the most controversial and constantly innovative bands. </p>
<p class="bodytext">They are no newbies: Behemoth has put out albums since the early 90s – all of them full of intense nightmares. Nowadays, the corpse-painted Poles are touring internationally with their spectacular live shows while at home the debate rages about the band's anti-Catholic messages. </p>
<p class="bodytext">Behemoth makes the ground tremble with their demonically well-executed and refined extreme metal. </p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Nuclear Blast / Warner</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>2</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/8f1069a7f0.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/0cc554259a.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/behemoth/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="21">
<artistName><![CDATA[BELLOWHEAD]]></artistName>
<country>UK</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Odeon]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Sat, 07 Jul 2012 19:00:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341680400]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341680400]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Neither Portishead nor Radiohead can make the Brits dance like the sound of Bellowhead.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Neither Portishead nor Radiohead can make the Brits dance like the sound of Bellowhead.</p>
<p class="bodytext">The quintessentially English 11-man band has taken the traditional folk music of their motherland and applied a massive touch, which has resulted in Bellowhead being awarded best live band as many as five times at the BBC Folk Awards. </p>
<p class="bodytext">With brass, fiddle, accordion and lute, the atmosphere of old pipe-smoking England is spread instantly. However, the anarchistic virtuoso musicians readily draw on jazz, funk, and marching bands as well.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Bellowhead has played during the intro on <em>The Simpsons</em>, developed their own type of ale and visited Roskilde Festival back in 2006. Now it’s again time to dust off the tweed jacket and shine the dancing shoes.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Navigator / import</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/df3b9113ba.png]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/58d03d5df0.png]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/bellowhead-1/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="22">
<artistName><![CDATA[BERNHOFT]]></artistName>
<country>N</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Arena]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Jul 2012 17:00:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341586800]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341586800]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[A great Scandinavian soul talent.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">In 2011 Jarle Bernhoft has risen to a position as one of the undisputed soul kings of Scandinavia. And the gentleman with the sharp haircut has proven to be much more than just some one-hit-wonder.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Bernhoft’s sublime voice has earlier been one of the greatest characteristics of the rock band Span, but it is as a solo artist that the entire world is about to discover the extent of this great talent.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Backed by an 11-men swinging band, Bernhoft creates a show oozing of sweet soul pop, as if this Norwegian was on first name terms with soul and R&amp;B giants as Curtis, Stevie and Michael.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Kikitépe Cassette/Target Distribution</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/fdb699b109.png]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/8cc737f828.png]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/bernhoft/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="23">
<artistName><![CDATA[BIG K.R.I.T.]]></artistName>
<country>US</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Cosmopol]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Sun, 08 Jul 2012 17:00:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341759600]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341759600]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Semi-nostalgic hip hop from the Southern states.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Mississippi rapper Big K.R.I.T. has been buzzing around the hip hop underground scene for some years, but it is only now that this extremely talented producer and rapper is about to break through.</p>
<p class="bodytext">His critically acclaimed mixtape <em>Return Of 4eva</em> is hip hop in the tradition of the Southern states in the 90s: filled with easy-flowing soul, organic sensations and plenty of parallels to Outkast and Underground Kingz.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Chicks and cars are obvious themes in hip hop, a genre favouring self-assertion rather than self-hatred. To that, Big K.R.I.T. has added social consciousness, self-irony, a sharp tongue and a brilliant flow, features increasing the pleasure of this semi-nostalgic hip hop.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Def Jam / import</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/e9558cd523.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/e02505b1ac.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/big-krit/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="24">
<artistName><![CDATA[BJÖRK]]></artistName>
<country>ISL</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Orange]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Sun, 08 Jul 2012 22:00:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341777600]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341777600]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Front woman of avant-garde pop.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Björk has, like few others, combined broad appeal  with artistic eccentricity. She is at once a musical sorceress with  Icelandic lava flowing through the veins, iconic pop star and electronic  wonder kid. Throughout the last 18 years, each new album has been a  bold move in a new direction, and Roskilde Festival has been one of the  regular stops on her musical travels.</p>
<p class="bodytext">With Biophilia from October Björk again takes a leap forward. Each new song on the album is followed by an app. But like in concert, the visual inventiveness never overshadows the music. Björk proves again that she can harmonise the organic and electronic elements in a personal expression full of adventure, experimentation and melody.</p>
<p class="bodytext">One Little Indian / Universal</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>1</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/7314c2d5f9.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/ae3c3383d3.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/bjoerk-4/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="25">
<artistName><![CDATA[RUBÉN BLADES]]></artistName>
<country>PAN</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Cosmopol]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Sun, 08 Jul 2012 19:00:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341766800]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341766800]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Salsa king and renaissance man.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">The Bronx is the birthplace hip hop. Many people know that. But before then, the beleaguered New York hood was also home of salsa dura – or 'hard salsa' – characterised by its political indignation and the clear African connection in the hard percussion work.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Rubén Blades is 'Mr. salsa dura' and can write several titles on his business card – both lawyer, politician and actor. However, it's as a singer and musician that the Panama legend's star is biggest.</p>
<p class="bodytext">With the characteristic piano riffs, congas and brass, Rubén Blades is ready to start up a pure salsa party.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Import</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>2</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/c077805b70.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/24a358e52e.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/ruben-blades/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="26">
<artistName><![CDATA[BLITZ THE AMBASSADOR]]></artistName>
<country>GHA</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Cosmopol]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Thu, 05 Jul 2012 21:15:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341515700]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341515700]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Hip hop packed with brass and Afrobeat. ]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">“It’s not where you’re from; it’s where you’re at,” Chuck D observes on Blitz The Ambassador’s critically acclaimed album <em>Native Sun</em>. This line from the legendary Public Enemy front man frames the transatlantic hip hop by Blitz The Ambassador pretty well. </p>
<p class="bodytext">Samuel Bazawule was raised in Accra, Ghana, but still manages to rap in double pace, matching anybody in his current hometown of New York.</p>
<p class="bodytext">With his faithful backing band The Embassy Ensemble, this musical mastermind delivers hip hop carried on a golden throne of funky brass music and Afrobeat-inspired guitar. The term Afro-American has rarely been more fitting.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Embassy MVT / import</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/1174fac8ae.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/82bcc793df.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/blitz-the-ambassador/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="27">
<artistName><![CDATA[BLONDES]]></artistName>
<country>US</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Apollo]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Sun, 08 Jul 2012 20:00:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341770400]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341770400]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Cosmic, stoned dance music.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Zach Steinman and Sam Haar only rarely choose the easy way through the labyrinth of electronic dance music.</p>
<p class="bodytext">The Brooklyn duo Blondes weave long, stretched sound patterns, which most of all resemble something from a remote and soothing universe. This is floating mid-tempo techno composed by people apparently more concerned with the seesaw movement of intergalactic space than the rumbling of the dance floor.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Climb aboard with Blondes and imagine yourself dancing slowly through a nebula on the far side of Jupiter.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: RVNG Intl. / import</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/bc44cb7aba.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/2533291c24.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/blondes/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="28">
<artistName><![CDATA[BOMBA ESTÉREO]]></artistName>
<country>COL</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Cosmopol]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Jul 2012 22:30:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341606600]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341606600]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Hot, psychedelic neo-cumbia.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">The South American electronic cumbia scene has experienced an enormous boost in recent years. Bomba Estéreo leads this brightly coloured wave.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Roskilde Festival 2009 was their first encounter with a Western music festival. Today, they are so sought-after that it would turn many a Western rock band green with envy. Roskilde Festival still holds a special place in their hearts – they stayed in the camping area during the entire festival last time they visited – and they are as happy as we are for the reunion.</p>
<p class="bodytext">The Columbians' hot dance music contains, beside cumbia folk music, traces of dub, psychedelic rock and hip hop. <em>Electro tropical </em>is what Bomba Estéreo have named their steaming hot urban sound.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Polen / import</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/47c2b04506.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/b6c9817e7d.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/bomba-estereo-1/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="29">
<artistName><![CDATA[BON IVER]]></artistName>
<country>US</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Arena]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Sat, 07 Jul 2012 23:00:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341694800]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341694800]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Folk in widescreen.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">According to the story, Justin Vernon created the sobbingly beautiful <em>For Emma, Forever Ago</em> in a lonely cabin in the middle of the winter wilderness. </p>
<p class="bodytext">On the self-titled album from 2011 Vernon has extended his sound with a big, well-playing band and appears as a progressive folk artist with a penchant for soft rock, grandiose sounds and instrumental digressions. </p>
<p class="bodytext">The transformation has not reduced Bon Iver’s place in the hearts of audience. The bearded American with the fabulous falsetto is now in top 10 of the hottest Roskilde requests in the company of the biggest stars, stadium bands and legends. </p>
<p class="bodytext">Bon Iver has left the hermitage cabin and really stepped into the spotlight. </p>
<p class="bodytext">4AD / Playground</p>
<p class="bodytext"> </p>]]></description>
<prioritet>1</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/1bc18070c1.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/60e3130be3.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/bon-iver/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="30">
<artistName><![CDATA[BOWERBIRDS]]></artistName>
<country>US</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Gloria]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Sat, 07 Jul 2012 15:00:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341666000]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341666000]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Close-to-nature folk with windblown clothing.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Nature-loving Bowerbirds are part of the wildly diverse and bearded American <em>free folk</em> genre. The duo sings faithful harmonies about flora and fauna making it hard not to drift away in dreams of a clearing in the woods far from the path of others.</p>
<p class="bodytext">The sense of fresh air and organic farming float around these songs, which are typically accompanied by guitar, accordion, violins and just a touch of muffled drums.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Naive and old-fashioned? Maybe. But also containing a strong sense of translation of naturalistic poetry and idyllic, memorable tunes. Bowerbirds sing to the hippie child in all of us.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Dead Oceans / VME</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/72a0364d65.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/ef774b9bd4.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/bowerbirds/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="31">
<artistName><![CDATA[JAKOB BRO]]></artistName>
<country>DK</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Gloria]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Jul 2012 13:00:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341572400]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341572400]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Weightless guitar jazz vs. electronica.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">The internationally acclaimed guitarist Jakob Bro’s weightless jazz is part of an exciting mix with electronica when he and Thomas Knak (Opiate, Future 3, People Press Play) pulls newly composed material in an interesting new direction.</p>
<p class="bodytext">The pieces were originally thought of as simple sketches more than actual songs, but later they have been turned into real compositions and productions in a cut/paste process, which now sets the scene for an upcoming album.</p>
<p class="bodytext">An exciting sneak preview at a crossover between genres and ways of thinking.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Loveland</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/46bc1592f5.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/60b0fb3309.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/jakob-bro/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="32">
<artistName><![CDATA[BÄDDAT FÖR TRUBBEL]]></artistName>
<country>S</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Pavilion Junior]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Sun, 01 Jul 2012 17:30:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341156600]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341156600]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Swedish-to-the-bone punk.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext"><em>Det här är inte New York</em> (this is not New York) is the title of Bäddat För Trubbel's debut album. Damn straight! This is the sound of Malmö's underground punk scene in all its charismatic, proletarian and hungover splendour.</p>
<p class="bodytext">The songs are obviously sung in Swedish with lots of double dots over the vowels, but even in the US they have discovered that the lads' uncomplicated punk can make the language barriers crumble like Wasa crispbread.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Bäddat För Trubbel makes Malmö sound like a pünk capital in its golden age.</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="WARM-UP" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/9f918c9e44.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/fcddd3501b.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/baeddat-foer-trubbel/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="33">
<artistName><![CDATA[CEREBRAL BALLZY]]></artistName>
<country>US</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Pavilion]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Sat, 07 Jul 2012 12:00:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341655200]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341655200]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Classic, testicle-crushing hardcore punk.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Brooklyn has become a mecca for the bespectacled hipster. But the New York hood also has a tradition of angry hardcore.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Cerebral Ballzy seems madly in love with 80s hardcore punk like Black Flag and Minor Threat. The young New Yorkers play aggressively, fast and loud.</p>
<p class="bodytext">This is not a punk band that has memorised Marx's <em>Das Kapital</em>. It’s rather a flock of hungry young lions ready to vanquish pop punk such as Green Day and Blink 182 from the musical world map.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Cerebral Ballzy gives Brooklyn a renaissance as a place where your hipster glasses will be crushed if you head in the wrong direction.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Adult Swim / import</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/062b08c444.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/0bc492327d.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/cerebral-ballzy/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="34">
<artistName><![CDATA[CEREKLOTH]]></artistName>
<country>DK</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Pavilion Junior]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Mon, 02 Jul 2012 20:30:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341253800]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341253800]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Hideous old-school death metal.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">The debut album is still on its way, but already on the EP <em>Halo</em><em> Of Syringes</em> you are convinced about the potential in these students of old-school death metal. They are called Cerekloth. <br /> <br /> Lead singer JBP has a growl so animalistic and full of rottenness that you almost see the maggots come creeping out of his mouth. The rest of the band play just as crushingly tight.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Roskilde Festival 2012 will be yet another metal fest out of the ordinary. Get in shape early with Cerekloth. </p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Hells Headbanger</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="WARM-UP" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/76ac7a48d0.png]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/8cf9362500.png]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/cerekloth/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="35">
<artistName><![CDATA[DJ MILES CLERET]]></artistName>
<country>UK</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Cosmopol]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341253800]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[DJ specialising in Africa, South America and chasing the obscure.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Through Soundway Records Miles Cleret secures the future for loads of golden music from especially Africa and South America. On his small label the fireball gathers obscure funk, blues and soul from the farthest reaches of the two massive continents and invites a new generation of listeners to join in.</p>
<p class="bodytext">A session with this acclaimed collector and musical intermediary can offer anything from highlife and Afro disco to cumbia and calypso.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Miles Cleret has released more than 25 records with exquisite finds and comes to Roskilde Festival with a buffet of the best delicious bites from the collection.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Soundway / import</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/37f4e0ddb7.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/2b3bf128fb.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/dj-miles-cleret/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="36">
<artistName><![CDATA[CLOCK OPERA]]></artistName>
<country>UK</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Pavilion]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Thu, 05 Jul 2012 19:30:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341509400]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341509400]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Advanced electronic pop.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Multi-instrumentalist Guy Connely has been making noise in the corners of the blogosphere for a few years as a remixer and originator of his cut-up 'chop pop' where samples, fragments and collages play an essential part.</p>
<p class="bodytext">This year the alias Clock Opera with the debut album <em>Ways</em><em> To Forget</em> enters the stage as a synth rock band with full-fledged melodies and windy stadium atmosphere. Connely’s expressive vocals soar beautifully over both the open and rich arrangements that still contain the electronic geek’s preference for playful details and abundant wealth.</p>
<p class="bodytext">The melodic, grandiose feeling can make Clock Opera one of the ideal acquaintances for fans of forward-thinking electronic pop.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Moshi Moshi / Universal</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/41c4353bbd.gif]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/61681904eb.gif]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/clock-opera/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="37">
<artistName><![CDATA[COLD SPECKS]]></artistName>
<country>CAN</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Pavilion]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Sat, 07 Jul 2012 19:30:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341682200]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341682200]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Raw, Southern folk.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">’Doom soul’, she calls her music. Canadian act Cold Specks’ bony arrangements sound more like classic, American blues folk with a distinctive singer at the centre.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Close your eyes while the music is playing and you can almost sense cotton-harvesting Southern states of bygone times.</p>
<p class="bodytext">With soft pickings on her acoustic guitar – occasionally accompanied by a little cello and piano – Al Spx creates a goosebumps-inducing atmosphere. Full of dust, patina and longing for deliverance. A brand-new debutant with a voice from the old days.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Mute / Playground</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/169d7db8e3.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/0d1836ac68.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/cold-specks/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="38">
<artistName><![CDATA[COMMIX]]></artistName>
<country>UK</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Apollo]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Sat, 07 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341612000]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341698400]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Drum'n'bass with edge and futurism.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">The visionary drum'n'bass legend Goldie fired the duo Commix towards the stars.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Their original mix of breakbeats, house, jazz and lots more has burst the musical boundaries of drum'n'bass.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Few artists are able to give you chills the way Commix are with their synth and rustling metal sounds, while making you break a hip while trying to follow the deep bass.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Commix will last way past their own sell-by date.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Metalheadz / import</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/9740ac6c56.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/45c2c3e842.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/commix/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="39">
<artistName><![CDATA[CONJUNTO ANGOLA 70]]></artistName>
<country>AGO</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Cosmopol]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Sun, 08 Jul 2012 12:00:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341741600]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341741600]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Sun-soaked guitar delirium led by honourable veterans.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Like many other African countries, Angola has been subject to bitter, regional conflict - among other things the vast number of internal wars strangled the rich, Panafrican musical epoch of the 1970s. A series of veterans are remedying this with Conjunto Angola 70.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Using a golden brown mix of African and Caribbean genres, these masters revive the golden age making you have inner visions of bellbottom pants.</p>
<p class="bodytext">The delirious guitar playing – not least by Teddy N'Singuis who, according to many, is the most skilled six-string player in Angola – steps to the foreground when Conjunto Angola 70 takes you back in time on an ecstatic journey.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Analog Africa / import</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/a9d4dc5f14.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/8650267144.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/conjunto-angola-70/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="40">
<artistName><![CDATA[COPENHAGEN COLLABORATION]]></artistName>
<country>DK</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Arena]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Jul 2012 13:00:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341572400]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341572400]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[A unique musical collaboration with leading bands from the Copenhagen underground.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">We present a unique marathon show, designed especially for Roskilde Festival.</p>
<p class="bodytext">A handful of Copenhagen-based bands has created a joint platform with Copenhagen Collaboration. A union to strengthen the sense of community and the ties that are already thriving in the Copenhagen music underground. Alcoholic Faith Mission, CODY, Sleep Party People, Hellraiserten, Monkey Cup Dress, Stærosaurus, Before the Show, From Sarah, You. You. You. and Ondt and the Gracehoper now live out these sympathetic ideals.</p>
<p class="bodytext">This array of bands weave together a totally unique concert. Focus is on the alternative rock of the first three bands, from melancholic americana to creeping eerieness.</p>
<p class="bodytext">With almost 30 musicians from Copenhagen's alternative scene on stage, you can look forward to a different experience where the numerous musicians enlarge, rethink and reinterpret the collective's songs. Copenhagen Collaboration emphasises a sense of community over individualised consideration and lets the songs flow together in a gigantic multi-concert. Only at Roskilde Festival.</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/703c5dcb3b.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/30c06eaec8.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/copenhagen-collaboration/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="41">
<artistName><![CDATA[COPENHEAVY]]></artistName>
<country>DK</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Apollo Countdown]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Mon, 02 Jul 2012 20:30:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341253800]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341253800]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Hard, bass-heavy electro.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Oscar Rumble and Michael Korch cross beats, bass and bangers under the name Copenheavy.</p>
<p class="bodytext">They are a duo from Copenhagen who is touring all over Denmark and who has achieved a big fan base in short time.</p>
<p class="bodytext">With a starting point in hard electro and dubstep, they make the party boil over.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Copenheavy delivers heavy bass for the masses, and their hot tunes are strained to the breaking point as if the two lads were going for Skrillex' throne.</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="WARM-UP" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/4b3573c1e9.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/446e8a3392.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/copenheavy/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="42">
<artistName><![CDATA[CRIOLO]]></artistName>
<country>BRA</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Cosmopol]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Sat, 07 Jul 2012 18:15:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341677700]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341677700]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Samba-influenced, political rap.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Samba, rap, Afrobeat and soul seamlessly blend together in Criolo's versatile and grandiose orchestrations.</p>
<p class="bodytext">After being practically unknown for years, success has arrived after the Brazilian has turned 30 – and with retroactive effect. The breakthrough album <em>Nó Na Orelha</em> really demonstrates the superiority of Portuguese as a language for rap.</p>
<p class="bodytext">The rapper, commentator and poet Criolo exposes the problems of Brazil, from deforestation to police violence in the favelas. His legendary countryman Caetano Valoso has already recognised Criolo's role as a protester and critic of society.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Sterns / Import</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/74f623c491.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/3dd03c7198.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/criolo/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="43">
<artistName><![CDATA[MIKAL CRONIN]]></artistName>
<country>US</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Pavilion]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Jul 2012 02:00:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341532800]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341619200]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Classic-sounding garage pop songs.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Evergreen tunes on a bed of guitar, bass and drums have thrilled the world since the Beatles took Hamburg as a young band.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Mikal Cronin delivers garage pop songs filled with great melodies and classic songwriting – even if it all is a bit more distorted than when mom and dad were flower children.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Fans of American garage rock will recognise Cronin’s name from The Moonhearts and his collaboration with Ty Segall where the young American has had a great brooding environment for his live-based, raw and melodic songs. </p>
<p class="bodytext">With his debut album<em></em>, Cronin has started a career based on sweet, psychedelic, sometimes noisy music with the catchy song as objective, means and purpose.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Trouble in Mind / import</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/965442d9df.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/b41a6b2cb8.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/mikal-cronin/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="44">
<artistName><![CDATA[CROWBAR]]></artistName>
<country>US</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Odeon]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Jul 2012 02:45:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341535500]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341621900]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Metal heavyweights from New Orleans.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Kirk Windstein will – despite gigs in Down – always remain synonymous with Crowbar who, like few other bands, have incarnated the murky sludge metal genre with their tuned-down riffs, lazy grooves and roaring vocals.</p>
<p class="bodytext">The hefty chaps have retained their metal style since the early 90s, unaffected by any fads. According to the front man, the current lineup is the best in the history of the band.</p>
<p class="bodytext"><em>Sonic Excess In Its Purest Form</em> is the title of one of the band's most famous albums. The title gives a good impression of the bone-crushing embrace which is the epitome of Crowbar.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: eOne / Import</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/7d5368921f.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/786ad35f7a.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/crowbar/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="45">
<artistName><![CDATA[THE CULT]]></artistName>
<country>UK</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Orange]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Jul 2012 19:30:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341595800]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341595800]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Shamanistic rock.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">With a foothold in goth rock and heavy metal and a deep fascination by mysticism and the occult, The Cult have been practicing stadium rock for more than 25 years.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Ian Astbury and Bill Duffy's shamanistic rock band has a long and diverse history. Astbury has also performed with members of The Doors in the band Riders On The Storm.</p>
<p class="bodytext">This year will see the release of <em>Choice Weapon</em>, the first album from The Cult in five years. Duffy's classic riffs and Astbury's powerful presence on stage are the essence of good ol' rock with heavy balls and poetic fire. Think a congregation of The Doors, Black Sabbath and Led Zeppelin on a windy mountaintop.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Join The Cult – there is plenty of room for new converts.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: New Wilderness / VME<br /></p>]]></description>
<prioritet>2</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/2417a4716a.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/ea20b2afe9.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/the-cult-2/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="46">
<artistName><![CDATA[THE CURE]]></artistName>
<country>UK</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Orange]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Thu, 05 Jul 2012 21:00:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341514800]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341514800]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Visit from Robert Smith and his black-clad band.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Few other bands have incarnated the black-clad music scene of the 80s with as wide appeal as The Cure.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Dark-edged albums such as <em>Pornography</em> and <em>Disintegration</em> have secured Robert Smith a legendary status among rock critics. At the same time, The Cure is popular among a wide audience because of hits such as &quot;Close To Me&quot; and &quot;Friday I'm In Love&quot;.</p>
<p class="bodytext">The concert at Roskilde Festival is a great chance to experience the Brits’ grandiose, gothic rock live under the Scandinavian summer's sky.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Look forward to a legendary band that has lifted Roskilde Festival several times earlier with their grandiose, immortal songs from the inner chamber of the soul.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Geffen / Universal</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>1</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/aba81b4872.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/3f5165ec64.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/the-cure-4/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="47">
<artistName><![CDATA[DALGLISH]]></artistName>
<country>US</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Gloria]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Jul 2012 15:00:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341579600]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341579600]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Experimental electronica pioneer.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Chris Douglas has existed in the dark outer reaches of electronic music for 20 years. His music is abstract and labyrinthine but also forward-gazing and quite often astoundingly beautiful.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Throughout a long career using different monikers (among others O.S.T., Dalglish and Rook Vallade), the Berlin resident, nomadic pioneer has explored – and partially developed – genres like IDM, dance-hostile techno and dark ambient.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Dalglish takes us on a journey through a sinister borderland of syncopated rhythms and industrial darkness. The nightmarish soundtrack skitters and leaps chaotically like evil insects in the underground where the sunlight is unable to penetrate. </p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Record Label / import</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/6028ce4515.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/4a6d4677d7.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/dalglish/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="48">
<artistName><![CDATA[DANGERS OF THE SEA]]></artistName>
<country>DK</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Pavilion Junior]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Tue, 03 Jul 2012 16:00:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341324000]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341324000]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Autumn-toned Americana.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Dangers Of The Sea consists of members from several well-known Danish bands. They have found common ground in a shared musical vision. They ensure a high level of country-scented, 70s-nostalgic folk rock songs.</p>
<p class="bodytext">In singer Andreas Bay Estrup's musical universe it as always dusk and the leaves keep on falling. Dangers Of The Sea are disciples of Neil Young's semi-sad school – Nordic Americana on a par with the great talents on the other side of the Atlantic.</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="WARM-UP" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/05598f5df2.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/991977912b.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/dangers-of-the-sea/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="49">
<artistName><![CDATA[DAUGHTER]]></artistName>
<country>UK</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Gloria]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Jul 2012 01:00:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341529200]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341615600]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Intimate, emotional folk.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Elena Tonra, front woman in Daughter, is only in her early 20s. But her downhearted but very expressive songs have enough bittersweet experience to match the American singer-songwriter queen Cat Power.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Her songs are sparsely arranged – often with the acoustic guitar as the only accompaniment. Tonra's delicate voice is so rich in nuances, colours and blues that a big backing orchestra would seem decidedly misplaced in Daughter's minimal but effective folk.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: 4AD / Playground</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/75974841f1.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/4137af2d2d.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/daughter/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="50">
<artistName><![CDATA[DEAD SKELETONS]]></artistName>
<country>ISL</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Pavilion]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Sat, 07 Jul 2012 03:00:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341622800]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341709200]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Psychedelic trance-death-rock.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">&quot;He who fears death cannot enjoy life,&quot; is the basic philosophy of psychedelic, death-embracing trance rock band Dead Skeletons.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Their music is like straying into a maelstrom of roaring, echoing guitars, staring skeleton heads, Buddhist trance and cosmic rock'n'roll. Like Suicide, The Brian Jonestown Massacre and Velvet Underground would sound in front of the gates of Hades, in a desperate attempt to keep the Grim Reaper at bay with a sonic attack.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Dead Skeletons are morbid celebration music for music lovers who prefer black sound waves.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: A Records / import</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/81960b2370.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/fc71ba749a.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/dead-skeletons/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="51">
<artistName><![CDATA[DEATHCRUSH]]></artistName>
<country>N</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Pavilion Junior]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Tue, 03 Jul 2012 19:00:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341334800]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341334800]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Brutal, melodic noise rock.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">The band name originates from an EP by the corpse-painted legends Mayhem. Still Norwegian black metal is just one of many ingredients in Deathcrush.</p>
<p class="bodytext">The trio's unique sound is noise rock spiced up with a bit of dark evil from up North; New Yorker-cool guitar abuse by a band that rips, screeches and tears, while at the same time is unafraid of being catchy. </p>
<p class="bodytext">The verdict made by the already initiated crowd is practically clear-cut: Deathcrush is one of tomorrow's most exciting and cool noise rock bands.</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="WARM-UP" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/6a3d2a2228.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/4f9f5c10a2.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/deathcrush/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="52">
<artistName><![CDATA[DEVILDRIVER]]></artistName>
<country>US</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Arena]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Jul 2012 21:00:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341601200]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341601200]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Uncompromising death metal.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Get the evil spirits out of the system with Devildriver. </p>
<p class="bodytext">Dez Fafara and his companions are deservedly praised for their extensive service at metal venues all over the world. </p>
<p class="bodytext">The American favourites have eaten their way up the food chain as a heavily touring metal band with a penchant for eruptive live concerts, hard-tuned drums and general aggression. </p>
<p class="bodytext">The starting point for the four Californian comrades is pumped-up thrash, hardcore and death metal in well-balanced doses. </p>
<p class="bodytext">Devildriver is just as effective for keeping the demons at bay as the bells the band name refers to. </p>
<p class="bodytext">Roadrunner / Warner</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/83bbd9872c.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/7e486d902f.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/devildriver/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="53">
<artistName><![CDATA[DIG & MIG]]></artistName>
<country>DK</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Pavilion Junior]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Sun, 01 Jul 2012 20:30:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341167400]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341167400]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Simple and catchy pop punk.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Danish band Dig &amp; Mig’s innocent pop punk has taken shape in the Danish punk underground – but the wide audience has quickly caught on.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Sune Wagner from The Raveonettes has produced the duo, and you can easily hear why.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Listening to Dig &amp; Mig like a meeting between the Danish 80s band Rocazino and Ramones – both ultra nostalgic and with the same nerve and attitude as the other great punk bands shooting from the Copenhagen underground right now.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Universal</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="WARM-UP" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/03636b5517.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/121c06b9ca.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/dig-mig/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="54">
<artistName><![CDATA[DJANGO DJANGO]]></artistName>
<country>UK</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Pavilion]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Thu, 05 Jul 2012 17:30:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341502200]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341502200]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Semi-electronic, equatorial tribal rock.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">The cover of Django Django’s self-titled debut album looks like a digitally manipulated, psychedelic tumbleweed floating through the desert towards the listener. The image describes this sought-after and critically acclaimed band’s music very well.</p>
<p class="bodytext">With a sun-soaked mixture of tribal music, fragmented rhythms, semi-electric rock and laid back psychedelia, the young Scotsmen inhabit a universe that brings back memories of both American and British golden pop. Meanwhile there is an exotic atmosphere – as if Django Django is floating away on exotic Bedouin expeditions in the middle of the prosaic, British surroundings.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Because Music / Warner</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/3d8b424237.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/8652dd85ec.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/django-django/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="55">
<artistName><![CDATA[DOMINIQUE YOUNG UNIQUE ]]></artistName>
<country>US</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Cosmopol]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Sat, 07 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341612000]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341698400]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Hip hop wonder girl with a speedy tongue.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Florida's perhaps most beautiful and hottest rapper dreams big as she prepares for world domination. With her fast staccato rap, Dominique Young Unique has placed her name in the corner where young urban queens such as Nicki Minaj, Santigold and M.I.A reign.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Her three mixtapes have caught people’s ears. In addition, Miss Unique has performed with Big Boi, Gucci Mane and N.E.R.D among others. Also, Kanye West has taken notice of the girl with a speedy tongue, who also prepares to create her own fashion collection. </p>
<p class="bodytext">Don’t miss out on this one, boys and girls. Dominique Young Unique is raw, fresh and ready for you to worship her.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Art Jam / Import</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/bab2343fd1.png]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/7847918ce3.png]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/dominique-young-unique/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="56">
<artistName><![CDATA[DR. JOHN AND THE LOWER 911 feat. JON CLEARY]]></artistName>
<country>US</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Arena]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Sun, 08 Jul 2012 14:00:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341748800]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341748800]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[The voodoo rock medicine man is back.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Since the acid-rocking breakthrough with <em>Gris</em><em>-Gris </em>from the late 60s, Dr. John's swampy voodoo funk rock has become an institution.</p>
<p class="bodytext">The great medicine man's latest album <em>Locked</em><em> Down</em> – produced by The Black Keys' Dan Auerbach – is a round of classic swinging roots rock filled with golden Farfisa organ, brass, female choir singers and a well-oiled showy feel.</p>
<p class="bodytext">In the middle of the rocking tunes you also sense the African inspiration, which has always been present with this piano boxer, guitarist and rock guru from Louisiana's steamy swamps.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Dr. John and his band are assisted by another experienced band leader and piano magician from New Orleans, Jon Cleary.</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>2</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/e3969e051b.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/9776ef30b6.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/dr-john-and-the-lower-911-feat-jon-cleary/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="57">
<artistName><![CDATA[DRY THE RIVER]]></artistName>
<country>UK</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Odeon]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Sat, 07 Jul 2012 13:00:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341658800]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341658800]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Folk rock in widescreen.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">When hearing Dry The River, you get a sense of a rustic musician's collective from the US. Even if their nationality is British and the band members' past involves emo and post-punk rather than sensitive folk music.</p>
<p class="bodytext">One thing is certain, though. This is an obvious new acquaintance for all wearers of lumberjack shirts. With richly orchestrated folk rock arrangements, Dry The River plays songs filled with melodrama and views over the steppes. At the same time the band has a muscular nerve, enabling them to stand shoulder to shoulder with the sensitive acts your mom would like and at the same time arm wrestling with punk bands.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: RCA / Sony Music</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/cc3c51dfde.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/ce5f481663.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/dry-the-river/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="58">
<artistName><![CDATA[THE ECHO VAMPER]]></artistName>
<country>DK</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Pavilion Junior]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Mon, 02 Jul 2012 19:00:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341248400]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341248400]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Black new wave.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Imagine Blondie's Debbie Harry bitten by a bat filled with a vampire virus.</p>
<p class="bodytext">That is just about the sound of the blonde but darkened Iza Mortag Freund who with controlled screaming vocals stand on the shoulders of other queens of darkness such as Lydia Lunch and Siouxsie Sioux.</p>
<p class="bodytext">James Brook provides stripped down rock'n'roll, drum machine and 80s synths, taking you back to a sexy goth club deep beneath the city streets.</p>
<p class="bodytext">The Echo Vamper is a must for all fans of haunted, black new wave.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: A:larm</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="WARM-UP" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/277a354228.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/ab965dc633.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/the-echo-vamper/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="59">
<artistName><![CDATA[EL PARAISO presents CAUSA SUI, EL PARAISO ENSEMBLE and PAPIR]]></artistName>
<country>DK</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Pavilion]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Sun, 08 Jul 2012 12:00:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341741600]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341741600]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Thick, cosmic acid from the Copenhagen underground.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext"> The Danish music underground is full of acid and marvelous mushroom shots. El Paraiso is a new Danish record label focusing on experimental, mind-expanding music. </p>
<p class="bodytext">Causa Sui has developed into a cult band. The Danes' 60s-sounding acid rock is full of cosmic jazz, Woodstock feeling and out-there solos so that the psychedelic colours almost run down the walls. </p>
<p class="bodytext">The Copenhagen trio Papir combines machanical krautrock and post-rock and adds a special intensity and ferocity. </p>
<p class="bodytext">El Paraiso Ensemble is a band put together especially for Roskilde 2012 and featuring specially invited guests on a journey into an electronic, remote universe filled with analogue synthesizers and psychedelic guitar grooves. </p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: El Paraiso </p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/0a42b03231.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/58e40adff4.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/el-paraiso-presents-causa-sui-el-paraiso-ensemble-and-papir/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="60">
<artistName><![CDATA[ELEKTRO GUZZI]]></artistName>
<country>A</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Cosmopol]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Jul 2012 21:00:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341601200]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341601200]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Hand-played techno.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">You almost don’t believe it. Elektro Guzzi enjoys the best company on the European electronic scene and plays at all the leading venues of the genre. However, the three Austrians renounce everything that has to do with loops, sequencing and laptops. Elektro Guzzi’s tripping minimal techno is played on bass, guitar and drums.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Their long instrumental sequences mimic the hypnotic 4/4 sensation of techno. At the same time, their music is raw, vibrant and true-to-the-word live. And of course, made for the stage in front of an astonished audience.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Macro / import</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/9d60dd11ad.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/a654f5090b.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/elektro-guzzi/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="61">
<artistName><![CDATA[ELOQ]]></artistName>
<country>DK</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Apollo Countdown]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Sun, 01 Jul 2012 20:30:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341167400]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341167400]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Danish producer and DJ toying with wonky.¬]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">August Fenger is part of the infamous crew surrounding the Danish label Cheff Records, and he's a central figure on the Copenhagen hip hop scene. A Danish music magazine has even called Eloq the Danish capital's own J Dilla.</p>
<p class="bodytext">The Copenhagen producer and DJ has a passion for dusty synths, playstation sounds, helium voices and cut-up drum samples. All in one brew, which gives the challenging fusion of edgy bass music and hip hop rhythms – also known as wonky – a Copenhagen twist.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Cheff</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="WARM-UP" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/a5a1913aa8.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/f47ae50b8b.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/eloq/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="62">
<artistName><![CDATA[EVIDENCE]]></artistName>
<country>US</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Cosmopol]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Jul 2012 15:45:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341582300]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341582300]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Mr. Slow Flow from Dilated Peoples.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">The mainstream audience never gave the new legendary Dilated Peoples the ultimate recognition that the reviews and the respect surrounding them otherwise anticipated. The former graffiti artist Evidence is, on the other hand, the band member with the most successful solo career.</p>
<p class="bodytext">The West Coast rapper from Santa Monica has been given the alias Mr. Slow Flow. His style isn’t snappy but rather laid-back and conversing, which lets you taste every single word of his lyrics as a consequence.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Furthermore, Evidence’s flair for cool productions and his sweetly scented soul atmosphere is more fine-tuned than ever.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Rhymesayers / Target Distribution</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/5490bd5eac.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/5f5b150b70.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/evidence/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="63">
<artistName><![CDATA[LEE FIELDS & THE EXPRESSIONS]]></artistName>
<country>US</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Odeon]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Sat, 07 Jul 2012 03:00:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341622800]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341709200]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Classic soul from the golden age.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">He has previously been called Little James Brown. When you experience the sharply dressed soul crooner and cool cat Lee Fields with his funky backing band, The Expressions, you understand why. This is pure soul.</p>
<p class="bodytext">The same brass-gilded mixture that Sharon Jones and Charles Bradley have previously won over the Roskilde audience with. With a huge song catalogue and a 40-year-long experience under the belt, Lee Fields is nevertheless at the peak of his career.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Well-played classic soul from the golden age with swaying hips, lots of love and a guarantee of hot bodies.</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/5c310c8dcc.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/7c956429d3.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/lee-fields-the-expressions/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="64">
<artistName><![CDATA[FIRST AID KIT]]></artistName>
<country>S</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Odeon]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Sat, 07 Jul 2012 15:00:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341666000]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341666000]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Country folk from the Swedish forests.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">With their American-sounding country folk, First Aid Kit have come far since their last visit at Roskilde Festival in 2009.</p>
<p class="bodytext">The Söderberg sisters have recorded their latest album <em>The</em><em> Lion's Roar </em>in Nebraska where Mr. Bright Eyes, Conor Oberst, was so overawed by the girls' vocal harmonies and stage presence that he ended up doing a cameo on the album.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Despite the success and the new experience, the charm and innocence in the two forest elves' music remain intact. With melodic tunes and enchanting voices, the duo sings about the upcoming adulthood with both sweetness and the melancholy inherent in country music.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Here is comfort, support and gilt-edged songs for souls in need.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Wichita / Target Distribution</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/d0f7b45914.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/7758f7e7ac.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/first-aid-kit-1/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="65">
<artistName><![CDATA[F.O.O.L.]]></artistName>
<country>S</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Apollo Countdown]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Sun, 01 Jul 2012 22:00:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341172800]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341172800]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Tight, hard electro from upcoming Swedish duo.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Fuck Our Ordinary Lives – and start partying!<br /> <br /> F.O.O.L. is one of the hottest names in dirty electronic music right now.<br /> <br /> Rasmus Hermansen and Oliver Nilsson already have thousands of global hungering fans constantly waiting for the next remix, just as the duo - Sweden's equivalent to Justice? – has toured the globe with their explosive shows.<br /> <br /> Tight, neon-coloured electro doesn't get much better than F.O.O.L.</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="WARM-UP" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/599c808414.png]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/4bdd1991a3.png]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/fool/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="66">
<artistName><![CDATA[NILS FRAHM]]></artistName>
<country>DE</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Gloria]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Sun, 08 Jul 2012 19:00:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341766800]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341766800]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Atmospheric piano music.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Nils Frahm’s latest record is called <em>Felt,</em> named after the velvet he used to cover up the piano strings in order to avoid waking his neighbours at night when composing his songs. This awareness of sound characterises the German composer and pianist.</p>
<p class="bodytext">From the piano he creates atmospheric and satisfying soundscapes that insist on the attention of every single nerve ending in your ear. </p>
<p class="bodytext">Nils Frahm is a perfect break from pulsating rhythms and howling amplifiers. His music brings forth inner fantasies of walks in majestic landscapes covered in snow and exquisite neo-classicism, all quite far away from the festival.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Erased Tapes / import</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/f993410eff.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/8358aa3c69.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/nils-frahm/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="67">
<artistName><![CDATA[THE FREDERIK]]></artistName>
<country>DK</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Apollo Countdown]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Mon, 02 Jul 2012 22:00:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341259200]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341259200]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Progressive house from a young Dane signed to deadmau5' label.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Frederik Olufsen is the protégé of Canadian house star Deadmau5', signed to his label mau5trap.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Judging from the first tracks – a bass-heavy mix of electro, dubstep and 8-bit – The Frederick sounds ready to give his mouse-masked label boss a race down to the wire.</p>
<p class="bodytext">A new young hope enters the international electronic club scene. With his EP <em>Heavy Crownage</em> and a performance at Roskilde Festival, the young Dane takes his first step towards a career in the company of the big ones.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Mau5trap</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="WARM-UP" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/01d7851604.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/61dbe9ce99.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/the-frederik/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="68">
<artistName><![CDATA[FRENCH FILMS]]></artistName>
<country>FIN</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Pavilion Junior]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Wed, 04 Jul 2012 17:30:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341415800]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341415800]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Sunshine-saturated indie rock.   ]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Despite the name, Finnish band French Films does not have a special interest in Truffaut or Godard. England – more specifically Manchester – appears to be checked off in their inner music atlas.</p>
<p class="bodytext">In spite of their winter-haunted home, they are not particularly melancholic. Their alternative rock has a youthful appetite for life and a feeling of beach and summer.</p>
<p class="bodytext">French Films are an obvious acquaintance for everyone who is interested in music and wants to have their expectations challenged – and wants to meet a Finnish band that already enjoys international interest.  </p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: GAEA / Import </p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="WARM-UP" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/e324370064.png]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/c04386ed96.png]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/french-films/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="69">
<artistName><![CDATA[LES FRERES SMITH]]></artistName>
<country>FR</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Cosmopol]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Jul 2012 13:45:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341575100]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341575100]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Afrobeat from Paris.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">With their blend of Afrobeat and funk with an ethnic flavour, Les Freres Smith is a well-described name at the Paris venues.</p>
<p class="bodytext">The city of lights is a multi-ethnic melting pot with especially many African emigrants, and the Pan-African atmosphere is easy to feel at the brothers' hot concerts, which will probably make Fela Kuti and James Brown high-five in the Hereafter.</p>
<p class="bodytext">If you were at the Kuti sons' multi-funk blast last Roskilde summer on the Arena stage, you're probably hungry for more. Les Freres Smith is at least one of the answers to your prayers.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Comet / import</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/79ba712bdc.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/d6fcd88e2f.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/les-freres-smith/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="70">
<artistName><![CDATA[FRIENDLY FIRES]]></artistName>
<country>UK</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Arena]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Sun, 08 Jul 2012 18:30:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341765000]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341765000]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Electronic summer pop.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Piña Colada and Hawaiian shirts go well with Friendly Fires. </p>
<p class="bodytext">The British band has already proven its qualities as a live band on our Odeon stage in 2009. At that time they had found inspiration in Talking Heads and LCD Soundsystem. </p>
<p class="bodytext">On 2011's <em>Pala</em> the sound is more tanned, more tropical, and more umbrellas have been put in the cocktail than before. The starting point is disco, funk and pop. Friendly Fires aim with jubilant enthusiasm for a sexy, electronic stadium sound that reaches out to dancing shoes in the back row. </p>
<p class="bodytext">With dreamy synths, Caribbean flavour and a hardworking front man, Friendly Fires are ready to deliver an undiluted, purely distilled summer party. </p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: XL / Playground</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/fa2e13ee73.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/d6ed9bceaa.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/friendly-fires-1/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="71">
<artistName><![CDATA[FRITJOF & PIKANEN]]></artistName>
<country>S</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Apollo Countdown]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Mon, 02 Jul 2012 17:30:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341243000]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341243000]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Dubstep-leaning electronic music in Swedish.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext"> The musical chemistry was apparently present from the beginning with Fritjof &amp; Pikanen. They met to create a remix together and decided to become a duo shortly after.<br /> <br /> Fritjof's Swedish-language lyrics revolve around their everyday life, Stockholm and love. With Pikanen’s melodic and effective dubstep arrangements, the music is well suited for both partying and ordinary days.</p>
<p class="bodytext">The general Swedish touch has not prevented the duo from receiving critical acclaim from abroad. Tek 9 - an experienced gentleman in British urban bass music - has already remixed the duo.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: EMI</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="WARM-UP" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/695d1b51b1.png]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/7bb1e39749.png]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/fritjof-pikanen/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="72">
<artistName><![CDATA[GENTLEMAN & THE EVOLUTION]]></artistName>
<country>DE</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Arena]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Jul 2012 23:30:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341610200]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341610200]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[European reggae superstar.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Although he was born far from Kingston Town, Gentleman has captured a large audience with his European hybrid of reggae, dancehall and R&amp;B.</p>
<p class="bodytext">The German-born rasta soul is also appreciated in Jamaica. He has made several trips to the island and won the respect of the country's musicians. At the same time he encourages his large, international audience to remember the reggae genre's message of universal love and diversity.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Gentleman comes to Roskilde with his big band The Evolution as a solid backing.</p>
<p class="bodytext">A sunny summer party filled with rocking riddims, shouts for tolerance and Caribbean flavour awaits.</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/a69b866067.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/6aa124149e.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/gentleman-the-evolution/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="73">
<artistName><![CDATA[GHOSTIGITAL]]></artistName>
<country>ISL</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Apollo Countdown]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Wed, 04 Jul 2012 17:30:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341415800]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341415800]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Digital, mad ride from former Sugarcubes vocalist.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Einar Örn from The Sugarcubes is (at least) just an uncompromising soul as his former band colleague Björk.</p>
<p class="bodytext">After a long musical break, the vocalist now collaborates with sound artist Curver under the moniker Ghostigital.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Ghostigital is a bloody nose to anyone who imagines Iceland as the home of knit sweaters and lovely, ethereal music. A crazy ride over volcanic plains with a sound of industrial, abstract hip hop and disorienting samples. Masterly madness.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Ipecac / import</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="WARM-UP" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/a7f78b2754.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/aa90c5ad3a.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/ghostigital/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="74">
<artistName><![CDATA[GIRAFFAGE]]></artistName>
<country>US</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Apollo]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Sun, 08 Jul 2012 14:00:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341748800]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341748800]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Summer-hot electronica.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Charlie Yin enters the electronic scene in great style with Giraffage.</p>
<p class="bodytext">The American's soothing music laps comfortably in a daze of daydreams and melancholy. With warm synthesizers he conjures saltwater-hazy memories of summer holidays in an impressionistic sound as if the music was recorded on analogue cassette tapes years before the young multi-instrumentalist and producers date of birth.</p>
<p class="bodytext">At the same time, the solar-heated, electronic tracks carry enough challenging rhythms and quirky details, making this music for both ears, nostalgia and the mind.</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/155f1817b7.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/d2c4c1930d.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/giraffage/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="75">
<artistName><![CDATA[GIRLSEEKER]]></artistName>
<country>DK</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Pavilion Junior]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Wed, 04 Jul 2012 14:30:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341405000]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341405000]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Gritty and punky synth pop.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">With synths, guitar and effects-drenched, deep vocals, Girlseeker have in their own minimal way made their mark as a new exciting band from the Copenhagen punk underground.</p>
<p class="bodytext">With a no-frills style, Girlseeker inhabits a sound space that is equal parts arrogant, arty post-punk and 80s-kitschy pop taste, perhaps inspired by Americans such as Ariel Pink and John Maus. However, Girlseeker pave their own way with strangely beautiful and gritty synth pop.</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="WARM-UP" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/45a788aa3e.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/84ac970333.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/girlseeker/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="76">
<artistName><![CDATA[GOSSIP]]></artistName>
<country>US</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Orange]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Jul 2012 17:00:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341586800]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341586800]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Pure diva pop.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Lip-glossed, glamorous disco pop has been a part of Gossip’s sound for long. Even when the trio had rock guitar and leather jackets on the menu. However, the chart-embrace has not been realised as uncompromisingly as on 2012's A Joyful Noise on which pop seems to have taken over after punk.</p>
<p class="bodytext">In this anorexic age of ours, Gossip has a refreshing, iconic front woman in the monumental Beth Ditto. A wonderful voice and a diva as well, who can seduce the audience and sing her lungs out, so that the queen throne of pop ought to be hers pretty soon. </p>
<p class="bodytext">Columbia / Sony Music</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>2</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/a946b8d5f2.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/112b354123.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/gossip-1/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="77">
<artistName><![CDATA[GOVERNOR OF ALASKA]]></artistName>
<country>DK</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Pavilion Junior]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Wed, 04 Jul 2012 16:00:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341410400]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341410400]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Young, noisy math rock.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Please welcome one of Denmark's new promising names in noisy, experimental math rock.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Governor of Alaska is only two men tall on stage. With guitar and drums they create a tight spectacle filled with quirky rhythms, metallic crust and rumbling, instrumental thunderclaps.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Experimental Afropunk, is how the duo defines the music – the violent beats hit hard when Thor and Hans release the brake and ride towards the stratosphere.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Red Tape</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="WARM-UP" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/0e85cd7847.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/1a3accc366.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/governor-of-alaska/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="78">
<artistName><![CDATA[GRIEVES & BUDO]]></artistName>
<country>US</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Cosmopol]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Jul 2012 15:45:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341582300]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341582300]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Poetic, realistic hip hop.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Grieves have recently become part of the alternative hip hop label Rhymesayers, which Slug from Atmosphere was part of founding.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Listening to the 2011album <em>Together/Apart</em>, it is obvious that Grieves belong in this company. Here you find social-realist hip hop, filled with substance abuse, domestic violence and sorry fates.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Budo’s organic production casts a pleasant light over this dark backdrop. The result is a humanistic hip hop sound filled with the pungent flavour of lived life.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Hip hop from a scarred soul with a story to tell – and a must for everyone who witnessed Atmosphere win over Roskilde Festival in 2011.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Rhymesayers / Target Distribution</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/74c4383ecc.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/71c72c15de.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/grieves-budo/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="79">
<artistName><![CDATA[GURRUMUL]]></artistName>
<country>AUS</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Gloria]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Sun, 08 Jul 2012 15:00:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341752400]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341752400]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Folk-pop from the indigenous Australia.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext"> Geoffrey Gurrumul Yunupingu has already been hailed as one of Australia's – perhaps the world's – most incredible voices.<br /> <br /> With an acoustic guitar and his tenor as primary travel companions, the blind aboriginal heads out on musical wanderings through his country's, his clan's and his own history. Brutally beautiful in their melodic and classic simplicity.<br /> <br /> Gurrumul's own story has just started on a celebrated chapter. Everyone from Sting to music magazine Rolling Stone have expressed their deep appreciation. However, you shouldn't let this sudden stardust distract you from the deep-rooted and uncorrupted qualities in these gorgeous nature songs. </p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Dramatico / Playground</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/dd0e95268b.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/119f4466e6.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/gurrumul/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="80">
<artistName><![CDATA[H2O]]></artistName>
<country>US</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Pavilion]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Sun, 08 Jul 2012 15:30:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341754200]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341754200]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Melodic NYC hardcore.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">New York – especially Queens and Brooklyn – has presented countless legendary hardcore punk bands with a penchant for shouting vocals, fast drumming and metallic riffs.</p>
<p class="bodytext">90s veterans H2O are exponents of the more melodic part of the genre's family tree where the crushing heaviness doesn't exclude a pop hook you can remember after leaving the concert.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Meanwhile, front man Toby Morse is an advocate of the <em>straight</em><em>-</em><em>edge</em> lifestyle. Even though the music and the environment is raw you can easily reach far without the use of substances.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Bridge Nine / import</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/5078dce025.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/893ea07a7f.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/h2o/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="81">
<artistName><![CDATA[HAMADCHA SUFI TARIQA OF ESSAOUIRA]]></artistName>
<country>MAR</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Gloria]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Sat, 07 Jul 2012 02:45:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341621900]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341708300]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Arabic trance music with origins back in the golden age of Islam.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Every Sunday you can get cured by the music brotherhood of Hamadcha Sufi Tariqa in the Moroccan port town Essaouira. </p>
<p class="bodytext">In the town’s ancient medina the locals gather to obtain a purifying trance by the force of the music or maybe even by the help of Allah. An equivalent magical experience is now taking place at Roskilde Festival. </p>
<p class="bodytext">With their Arabian oboes, exotic major scales and persistent percussion rhythms the Moroccans create a unique space that is both timeless and drags you down through the centuries. The roots of this music reach more than 500 years back in time and are part of the mystic and poetic sufi tradition of Islam.</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/9c99f5def9.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/32cfd1286d.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/hamadcha-sufi-tariqa-of-essaouira/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="82">
<artistName><![CDATA[HANK3]]></artistName>
<country>US</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Odeon]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Jul 2012 18:00:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341590400]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341590400]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Punk'n'country from legendary Hank Williams' grandson.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">&quot;I'm here to put the dick back in Dixie and the cunt back in country,&quot; sings Hank3. The job description is clear for this tattooed cowboy: Nashville's cosy country is going down.</p>
<p class="bodytext">The spirit of grandfather Hank Williams, Johnny Cash and other icons of the rural music is best translated with outlaw punk'n'country, full of beer foam, gunpowder and engine oil.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Hank3's concerts range from classic country with slide guitar, fiddle and banjo to the cowpunk incarnation Hellbilly. Recently, the rebel’s doom/thrash metal band Assjack has even finished the concerts.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Roskilde Festival has courted the maladjusted wretch of country music for a number of years. Hank3 incarnates Nashville after dark, when the well-behaved songwriters have gone to bed.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Target Distribution</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/967626dc33.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/0a0c0cf1fe.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/hank3/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="83">
<artistName><![CDATA[HELSINKI POETRY]]></artistName>
<country>DK</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Pavilion Junior]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Tue, 03 Jul 2012 20:30:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341340200]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341340200]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Noise-poppy world tour. ]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">The capital of Finland is not the only place where Helsinki Poetry has its starting point. Ebbe Frej and Rune Vigil use different cities around the world as the centre of their songs. </p>
<p class="bodytext">The tour around the world takes place on a magic carpet of pleasant noise – like a more accessible version of My Bloody Valentine, guided by Vigils high vocals.</p>
<p class="bodytext">The mood and choice of colour in the noise-poppy songs vary depending on whether we are in fairytale-like &quot;Marrakech&quot; or rainy &quot;Manchester&quot;.</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="WARM-UP" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/406ca055f1.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/28f8986349.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/helsinki-poetry/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="84">
<artistName><![CDATA[JULIA HOLTER]]></artistName>
<country>US</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Gloria]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Sat, 07 Jul 2012 13:00:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341658800]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341658800]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Atmospheric avant-garde pop.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Julia Holter is an acquaintance of the more sophisticated kind, with her inspiration from and references to avant-garde composition music, poetry, art films and theatre.</p>
<p class="bodytext">However, there is still an element of accessible pop music in the many-sided instrumentation of the American’s compositions. The playfulness, the excess of detail and the transitions between anything from synthesizers to cembalo, from beauty to eeriness, is invested in a melodious material that can be related to in countless ways.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Julia Holter creates ambitious avant-garde pop saturated with atmosphere, which rewards the willing and attentive listener to a great degree. Great art is hidden here in outwardly timid music.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: RVNG Intl. / import</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/436105243a.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/eacf3b9037.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/julia-holter/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="85">
<artistName><![CDATA[HOSPITALITY]]></artistName>
<country>US</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Pavilion]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Sun, 08 Jul 2012 19:00:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341766800]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341766800]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Restless, cute summer guitar pop.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">&quot;I don’t know how to write conventional songs,&quot; says Hospitality's lead singer and guitarist Amber Papini in an interview. Good, you’re tempted to say.</p>
<p class="bodytext">The Brooklyn trio's treatment of alternative guitar pop structures is playful and restless without losing any sunshine-blurry, sweet and – you guessed it – hospitable elements.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Laid-back summer nostalgia and edgy details are no opposites with Hospitality. They sing about New York and life as a wage slave on a number of lovely songs that will definitely be appreciated by fans of pop full of melancholy.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Merge / Import<br /></p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/0e8d408f6d.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/028bdcb0c6.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/hospitality/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="86">
<artistName><![CDATA[SIVERT HØYEM]]></artistName>
<country>N</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Odeon]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Sat, 07 Jul 2012 01:00:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341615600]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341702000]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Dramatic songs in minor from a dark mind.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Madrugada was one of Norway's biggest rock bands. Back in the band’s heyday, you really paid attention to vocalist Sivert Høyem’s baritone that made you think of a Norwegian cousin of Nick Cave or Michael Stipe from R.E.M.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Høyem still produces grandiose Scandinavian rock full of inner drama. On the Norwegian’s fourth album, <em>Long Slow Distance</em>, he has found inspiration in surprising places (Høyem mentions German kraut rock and French pop as some of them), and the synthesizer often knocks on the door in Høyem’s stormy songs in minor.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Hektor Grammofon / EMI</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>2</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/486b9068be.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/7499f49231.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/sivert-hoeyem/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="87">
<artistName><![CDATA[I GOT YOU ON TAPE]]></artistName>
<country>DK</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Arena]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Jul 2012 19:00:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341594000]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341594000]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Grandiose pop rock with solid melodies.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext"><em>Church of the</em><em> Real</em>, is the title of I Got You On Tape's new album. Grandiose and self-assured – just like the music.</p>
<p class="bodytext">With a sporadic disco inspiration, church organ and catchy choruses, the well-playing four-piece ensures an even more grandiose atmosphere than ever before.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Jacob Bellens' authoritative voice is just one of many aces up the sleeve with this band. Relaxed and unforced they deliver poppy rock songs that seizes the key to the audience's beating heart.</p>
<p class="bodytext">I Got You On Tape retakes Roskilde Festival as a band that risen significantly from the ranks. The Danes are well on their way to becoming central on the Nordic alternative scene.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Tigerspring / Universal</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/4b584bdf11.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/93e150584b.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/i-got-you-on-tape-1/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="88">
<artistName><![CDATA[ICONA POP]]></artistName>
<country>S</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Pavilion Junior]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Mon, 02 Jul 2012 22:00:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341259200]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341259200]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Chic electro pop.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">You can almost hear it in the name. Icona Pop aims to create chic, sophisticated electro pop songs.</p>
<p class="bodytext">The photogenic duo with the honey-like voices attracted all kinds of buzz in the blogosphere with the EP <em>Nights</em><em> Like This</em>, which is rich on crystalline pop, bubbling synths and catchy choruses.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Icona Pop might become Scandinavia's next pop sensation in the tradition of Robyn, Annie and even Ace of Base.</p>
<p class="MsoNormal"> </p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="WARM-UP" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/a25e45a823.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/5c25b183c3.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/icona-pop/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="89">
<artistName><![CDATA[INDIANS]]></artistName>
<country>DK</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Pavilion Junior]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Tue, 03 Jul 2012 14:30:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341318600]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341318600]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Psychedelic pop in widescreen.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Forget all about bloody scalps. Copenhagen-based Indians will steal lots of beating hearts.</p>
<p class="bodytext">The mysterious band played its first concert in February. In one of few, scarce messages to the outside world, Indians describe the music as magical, dreamy and poetic.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Indians' songs overflow with psychedelic beauty in widescreen. The first smoke signals suggest a band with a laid-back ease of writing alternative pop hymns.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: TWIMM / Playground</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="WARM-UP" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/f7a5f62682.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/94218f8326.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/indians/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="90">
<artistName><![CDATA[DAWDA JOBARTEH]]></artistName>
<country>GAM/DK</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Pavilion Junior]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Sun, 01 Jul 2012 14:30:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341145800]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341145800]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Kora virtuoso residing in Denmark.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">He is tipped to be one of the future stars of the global music scene.</p>
<p class="bodytext">With the praised debut album <em>Northern Light Gambian Night</em>, Dawda Jobarteh combines virtuoso kora harp playing with a sensibility that is both Nordic and jazzy –most likely a product of many years as a resident in Copenhagen where he has played with many of very best musicians from the Nordic jazz scene.</p>
<p class="bodytext">With Dawda Jobarteh, Pavilion Junior gets a different, extra sunny glow.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Sterns</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="WARM-UP" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/361a975eb9.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/9b1709e0dd.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/dawda-jobarteh/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="91">
<artistName><![CDATA[JONATHAN JOHANSSON]]></artistName>
<country>S</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Odeon]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Sat, 07 Jul 2012 21:00:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341687600]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341687600]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Romantic and catchy Swedish-language pop.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">It's easy to be a little jealous of the Swedes. Nobody can make pop like them.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Take Jonathan Johansson, Sweden's new champion in romantic and soulful pop. With his Swedish lyrics and tasteful 80s-leaning arrangements, Johansson has also conquered pop hearts all the way across the Atlantic. He stylishly and coolly distills romance and soul into black shiny pop songs, making both fans of Depeche Mode and New Order cheer.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Jonathan Johansson continues the Swedish tradition of writing superior, slightly melancholic pop songs.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Hybris / A:larm</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/c166a2c2bc.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/af1dea6eb4.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/jonathan-johansson/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="92">
<artistName><![CDATA[JUPITER & OKWESS INTERNATIONAL]]></artistName>
<country>CD</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Cosmopol]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Jul 2012 02:30:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341534600]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341621000]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Adventurous, funky sunshine pop.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">For practically a lifetime, Jupiter Bokondji has worked hard to show how the ethnic diversity in DR Congo can result in something other than civil war.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Okwess International is a band of talented young people from the provinces in the war-ravaged country. Together, they play adventurous sunshine pop with the healing zebola dance as a starting point.</p>
<p class="bodytext">With Jupiter – &quot;the rebels' general&quot; – in front, the well-playing band tells the story of a Congo that doesn't rhyme with distress, drought and death. Jupiter &amp; Okwess International provides access to a golden palace of music where funk, party and guitar tones rule.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: All Other / import</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/c0130f3e87.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/10520a826c.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/jupiter-okwess-international/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="93">
<artistName><![CDATA[PAUL KALKBRENNER]]></artistName>
<country>DE</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Arena]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Sat, 07 Jul 2012 01:30:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341617400]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341703800]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Figurehead of the Berlin techno scene.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Over the past 15 years, he has steadily been promoted to the genre's premier league. Today, Paul Kalkbrenner's name is written in big letters at explosive, electronic parties throughout Europe.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Kalkbrenner's dream of creating his own danceable techno started in the 90s on Berlin's hot dance floors. However, things didn't really take off until the 00s.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Since the job of soundtrack composer and leading actor in the cult film <em>Berlin Calling,</em> Paul Kalkbrenner has become some kind of figurehead for the Berlin techno scene. The 2011 album <em>Icke</em><em> Wieder</em> cements the German's talent for creating beautiful and harmonious minimal techno.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Now the Berliner beats move to Roskilde Festival. Brace yourself for an electronic party in widescreen, which will probably put the German in the company of former Roskilde conquerors such as Trentemøller and Tiësto.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Paul Kalkbrenner Musik / VME </p>]]></description>
<prioritet>2</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/4fb55700ea.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/2b33710258.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/paul-kalkbrenner/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="94">
<artistName><![CDATA[KELLERMENSCH]]></artistName>
<country>DK</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Orange]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Thu, 05 Jul 2012 18:00:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341504000]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341504000]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Massive outsider rock.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">”Although you belong in the dark below, you can easily rise and shine quickly,” we wrote in 2010 when Kellermensch had transformed from Pavilion Junior pupa in 2009 to a pitch-black butterfly.</p>
<p class="bodytext">These words also hold true in 2012 when the band is winning new fans over – internationally as well – with their hard-hitting rock filled with crushing guitars, clenched fists and melodic tastiness.</p>
<p class="bodytext">The Danes inhabit an existentialistic knocked-over space where metal, Russian literature and alternative rock naturally form a part of the same formula.</p>
<p class="bodytext">We welcome back Kellermensch who now inhabit the top floor of Danish rock.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Universal</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/096bedbf5a.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/c40469f1b2.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/kellermensch-2/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="95">
<artistName><![CDATA[KESI]]></artistName>
<country>DK</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Apollo Countdown]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Wed, 04 Jul 2012 22:00:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341432000]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341432000]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Copenhagen’s bad boy of hip hop.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">With grainy YouTube videos and lots of ghetto attitude, Kesi and his crew have been part of setting the agenda for Danish hip hop.</p>
<p class="bodytext">On their own, these young troublemakers have  created some of the most raw and lively rap heard in the kingdom. The language is Danish through and through. Musically, they are especially inspired by English grime hip hop’s scratchy sound.</p>
<p class="bodytext">With Benny Jamz’ pounding productions as a toxic background, Kesi is a must if you want get an impression of ​​Danish hip hop anno 2012.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Universal</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="WARM-UP" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/34c514bc5c.png]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/9e5960bace.png]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/kesi/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="96">
<artistName><![CDATA[KHALAZER]]></artistName>
<country>DK</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Apollo Countdown]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Wed, 04 Jul 2012 16:00:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341410400]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341410400]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Chaotic, colourful, Danish-language hip hop.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">In a bright green collision of impressions, smells and ideas, Dr. Lazerlyde from Danish band Analogik puts together sound bits, string riffs and samples, which sounds af if they are taken from Bollywood, Nintendo, London's deepest club basements and old radio programmes.</p>
<p class="bodytext">On top of this mix, Khal Allan delivers thoughtful, baroque rap lyrics, which have given him a unique status in the Danish hip hop underground.</p>
<p class="bodytext">A brilliant word juggler has found a companion who can give him the right backing.</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="WARM-UP" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/2851199e57.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/97c227d0e5.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/khalazer/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="97">
<artistName><![CDATA[KLUMBEN & RASKE PENGE]]></artistName>
<country>DK</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Pavilion Junior]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Sun, 01 Jul 2012 22:00:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341172800]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341172800]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Dancehall in Danish.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Life at Copenhagen bars and takeaway joints now has a perfect soundtrack with Klumben &amp; Raske Penge, who raps about life in their hometown in a mixture of Jamaican, sun-drenched grooves and Danish social realism.</p>
<p class="bodytext">The two dancehall darlings are everywhere on the radio and online with the single &quot;Rundt&quot;. The track proves how easily you can philosophise about life and big ideas while going grocery shopping around the corner.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Danish dancehall rarely sounds better than this.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Cheff Records / Kontrafon</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="WARM-UP" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/0a232b2c1c.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/f5b8d47012.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/klumben-raske-penge/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="98">
<artistName><![CDATA[SANDRA KOLSTAD]]></artistName>
<country>N</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Apollo Countdown]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Mon, 02 Jul 2012 16:00:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341237600]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341237600]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Norway's new electro pop princess.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Norway has a new electro pop princess. Her name is Sandra Kolstad and she has an almost absurdly firm grip on producing frosty, electronic pop.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Norwegian critics have already fallen in love with Kolstad's futuristic robot disco, which may very well soon catapult the Norwegian towards international fame.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Kolstad's music is sophisticated and artistically ambitious but also with hooks and choruses, which are just waiting to take permanent residence in your brain.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Trust Me / import</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="WARM-UP" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/15c7fd536f.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/855f929bf8.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/sandra-kolstad/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="99">
<artistName><![CDATA[KORALLREVEN]]></artistName>
<country>S</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Apollo]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Sun, 08 Jul 2012 16:00:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341756000]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341756000]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Tropical dream pop.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Daydreaming about a gorgeous tropical island is hardly unusual in the windswept Scandinavia.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Korallreven has translated the longing for the azure horizon and the gentle sway of fan palms to electronic, semi-instrumental dream pop.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Marcus Joons was in Samoa when the idea for the project arose. Together with his friend Daniel Tjäder he has long since taken blogs and international music media.</p>
<p class="bodytext">The mission is coconut-scented, tropically yearning songs where your ears are bathed in nostalgic synths, Caribbean rhythms and soothing female voices.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Korallreven is a perfect journey south without double bookings, noisy tourists or disappointing weather forecasts.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Acéphale / A:larm</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/abd7e3eaf6.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/7765e85b08.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/korallreven/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="100">
<artistName><![CDATA[KRAFTKLUB]]></artistName>
<country>DE</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Odeon]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Thu, 05 Jul 2012 18:00:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341504000]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341504000]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Enthusiastic, German-language indie rock.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">With a firm grip on melodic, alternative rock, Kraftklub has charmed the rock-loving audience in Europe's most populous nation.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Lead singer Felix Brummer’s sparklingly witty, German-language lyrics crawl over a soundtrack that sounds a bit like Franz Ferdinand or The Clash with <em>weißbier</em> in the blood and thinly disguised chart ambitions.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Many kilometers south of Berlin, Kraftklub have created their own intelligent and party-like rebel music. The southern German musketeers like to wear college jackets, belts and polo shirts when they skewer the metropolitan bourgeoisie.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Universal</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/e91e43933b.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/82491cd0f2.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/kraftklub/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="101">
<artistName><![CDATA[ALISON KRAUSS & UNION STATION feat. JERRY DOUGLAS]]></artistName>
<country>US</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Arena]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Sat, 07 Jul 2012 16:00:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341669600]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341669600]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[The bluegrass queen from Illinois.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Having spent over 25 years in the business and won just as many Grammys, bluegrass queen Alison Krauss is a relaxed, unpretentious legend, only in her early 40s.</p>
<p class="bodytext">The North American belle brings really good company. The honoured Dobro guitarist Jerry Douglas helps her conquer the Roskilde stage, and the rustic band Union Station includes Dan Tyminski who did George Clooney's singing voice in <em>O</em><em> Brother, Where Art Thou?</em></p>
<p class="bodytext">Alison Krauss' lavish voice makes every song from her lips a true delight. Even if the subjects are typically about heartache and endless sorrow, there is always a twinkle in her eye between the banjo and fiddle sounds.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Rounder / Universal</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>2</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/ff6111fc04.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/b8a68929fb.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/alison-krauss-union-station-feat-jerry-douglas/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="102">
<artistName><![CDATA[KRIGET]]></artistName>
<country>S</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Gloria]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Sat, 07 Jul 2012 19:00:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341680400]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341680400]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Dystopian jazz punk trio.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Drum, bass and saxophone distorted beyond recognition is not the most obvious setup for dystopian rock'n'roll. Nevertheless, Kriget creates a very distinct expression due to this rather unusual instrumental trio.</p>
<p class="bodytext">The three Swedes' mechanical, pared-down but also playful free-form jazz often have references to Germans such as Peter Brötzmann and D.A.F.<br /> </p>
<p class="bodytext">But one of the best things about this music is its immediacy. Kriget can deliver a thunderclap that will shake your head. Get ready for some instrumental future music that is rawer and more to the bone than an x-ray.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: EMI Sweden / Import</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/493db92a36.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/b4e822d956.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/kriget-1/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="103">
<artistName><![CDATA[KÚRA]]></artistName>
<country>ISL/DK</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Apollo Countdown]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Tue, 03 Jul 2012 19:00:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341334800]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341334800]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Electronica on volcanoes.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Copenhagen's electronic scene and Iceland's lush nature melt together like neon-coloured lava when Kúra is playing.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Child of nature Fanney Ósk Thórisdóttirs's voice rests on the chilled, rumbling electronic production (guitarist and programmer Rasmus Liebst is the trio's Danish member), which is the epitome of big city melancholy from the nightclubs' lower floors – an inspiration could be UK band Everything But The Girl.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Kúra's sound is a tempting, Nordic darkness.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Nordic Music Society / VME</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="WARM-UP" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/def2b57d40.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/d4b60bd220.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/kura/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="104">
<artistName><![CDATA[LARSEN & FURIOUS JANE]]></artistName>
<country>DK</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Pavilion]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Sat, 07 Jul 2012 13:30:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341660600]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341660600]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Intelligent, well-written indie rock.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Torsten Larsen and his squires ought to be mentioned when looking up the term 'critic's favourite' in a Danish dictionary.</p>
<p class="bodytext">With a solid grasp on songwriting, Larsen &amp; Furious Jane have created a handful of albums that uses well-written, absolutely non-Danish sounding indie rock to explore the rather disgruntled mood as it sounds coming from a group of Danes.</p>
<p class="bodytext">It's sensitive, subtle and purged of stadium rock manners. An obvious acquaintance for fans of The Walkmen and other bitter-about-life male bands. Larsen &amp; Furious Jane's days as a well-kept secret should be over soon. As long as Torsten Larsen promises not to give up the dark outlook, which lights up on each of the band's releases.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Tip: the band gives away their two latest albums Zen Sucker and Dolly as downloads on <a href="http://www.momowave.org/" target="_blank" >momowave.org</a></p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/b883732852.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/9efecc35ad.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/larsen-furious-jane/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="105">
<artistName><![CDATA[LINKOBAN]]></artistName>
<country>DK</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Pavilion Junior]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Wed, 04 Jul 2012 20:30:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341426600]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341426600]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[The Danish grime scene's new crown princess.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">The crown princess on the Danish grime scene is called Linkoban. This sharp, new acquaintance ensures that Lucy Love is not the only Danish female representative of the rap genre originating from the UK.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Linkoban's show draws on Japanese horror in the vein of <em>The Ring</em> and <em>The</em><em> Grudge</em>. Her first track &quot;Like This&quot; suggests a new exciting acquaintance for anyone with a penchant for dirty urban pop that makes Copenhagen rhyme with London. </p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Superbillion / Playground</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="WARM-UP" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/ded93f09e5.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/401319d11d.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/linkoban/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="106">
<artistName><![CDATA[LITURGY]]></artistName>
<country>US</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Pavilion]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Sat, 07 Jul 2012 01:00:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341615600]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341702000]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Virtuoso black metal.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">In the more conservative (black) metal circles, Brooklyn’s Liturgy has created controversies by means of their every-day appearances and undergraduate mindset. However, in spite of their appearances, the music is still none the less scathing and chaotic.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Liturgy’s black metal overflows with the biting cold of an ice winter that makes your legs tremble and leaves your mouth dry.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Hunter Hunt-Hendrix’ unnatural screaming vocals are dishearteningly like a howling homeless whirlwind. The founder’s abuse of both guitar and vocal cords is matched by a band that unites the genre’s primal scream with an instrumental equilibrism you mostly encounter in jazz, mathrock and modern music compositions.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Thrill Jockey / VME</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/13a5619ad9.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/98484eea11.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/liturgy/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="107">
<artistName><![CDATA[LONE]]></artistName>
<country>UK</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Apollo]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Thu, 05 Jul 2012 18:45:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341506700]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341506700]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Cosmic techno rave.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">On a dense stream of albums, Matt &quot;Lone&quot; Cutler has developed his own imaginative mix of rave, hip hop, funk, techno and star-glittering synthesizers.</p>
<p class="bodytext">The clubby party sensation has recently been upgraded. At the same time, the Brit’s experimental approach toys with the typical dance floor beat and creates a memorable experience. Even for those who prefer not to shake a leg.</p>
<p class="bodytext">It’s evident on the critically acclaimed 2012 release <em>Galaxy Gardens</em> on which the many flavours, colours and shades are perfectly balanced atop the looped rhythms.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Magic Wire / import</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/b0c7b34e46.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/1e17e4ac17.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/lone/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="108">
<artistName><![CDATA[THE LOW ANTHEM]]></artistName>
<country>US</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Pavilion]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Sat, 07 Jul 2012 17:30:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341675000]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341675000]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Rustic Americana.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Old US flags wave over The Low Anthem’s rustic songs.</p>
<p class="bodytext">The band had a minor breakthrough with <em>Oh My God, Charlie Darwin</em>, which made a larger audience discover the Providence band’s richly orchestrated blend of rhythm &amp; blues, country, blues rock and pastoral folk.</p>
<p class="bodytext">On 2011's <em>Smart Flesh</em> the band sounds more subdued than before. This rule has exceptions, however, for instance with the 9-11 rock hymn &quot;Boeing 737&quot;.</p>
<p class="bodytext">The Low Anthem place themselves confidently on the mountain peaks of the American rock tradition. Their songs are full of lofty solitude, campfires and fresh mountain air.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Bella Union / Cooperative</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/368e81fff3.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/8d7492017f.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/the-low-anthem/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="109">
<artistName><![CDATA[M83]]></artistName>
<country>FR</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Arena]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Sat, 07 Jul 2012 20:00:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341684000]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341684000]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Ecstatic, monumental synthrock.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Finally, we have M83 back at Roskilde Festival to bathe our ears in grandiose sci-fi sounds.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Anthony Gonzalez’ latest magnum opus – the double album <em>Hurry Up, We’re Dreaming</em> – makes M83's previous releases sound rustic and simple.</p>
<p class="bodytext">80s-happy synths and bombastic noise rock float in an upward maelstrom with the Milky Way's outer provinces as the final destination – like keyboard whiz Jean-Michel Jarre would have sounded if he were backed by My Bloody Valentine.</p>
<p class="bodytext">M83 has delivered one of the ultimate dreamy soundtracks of this millennium. Over the top – and damn proud of it.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Naïve / Playground</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>2</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/43e2bc9bdb.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/196ec70886.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/m83-1/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="110">
<artistName><![CDATA[MAC MILLER]]></artistName>
<country>US</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Arena]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Sat, 07 Jul 2012 14:00:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341662400]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341662400]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Upbeat hip hop with pop flavour.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">In the time of mixtapes and with the use of Twitter, Mac Miller has conquered the young hip hop scene just like his bro Wiz Khalifa.</p>
<p class="bodytext">With his debut album <em>Blue</em><em> Slide Park</em> this white kid has achieved such high sales numbers that his name is now molded in solid gold. Already before the album was released, Mac Miller's live shows experienced massive interest, also in the Nordic countries.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Mac Miller’s light and often bubbly hip hop is packed with summer vibes as well as thoughts and dreams of girls and fame. Carefree and with a positive aura this pride of Pittsburgh aims for an even greater entourage.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Rostrum / Import</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>2</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/3fc5d491ef.png]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/3c56557d1d.png]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/mac-miller/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="111">
<artistName><![CDATA[MACHINE HEAD]]></artistName>
<country>US</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Orange]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Sun, 08 Jul 2012 17:30:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341761400]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341761400]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Californian thrash metal heroes.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">”Let freedom ring with the shotgun blast!”</p>
<p class="bodytext">Many metal fans probably still goosebumps when they hear this call from Machine Head’s debut album <em>Burn My Eyes</em>.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Machine Head have crushed their way through the 90s and 00s with a metal sound that is both varied and brutal. On stage it is equally clear that Rob Flynn is a friend of the metal people – many probably remembers Machine Head’s raw Roskilde concert in 2007.</p>
<p class="bodytext">The Californian heroes have become exponents of progressive, melodic thrash metal that will never rest until all fists are in the air.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Roadrunner / Warner</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>2</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/48e27b6bc2.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/8c96842f55.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/machine-head-2/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="112">
<artistName><![CDATA[MACKLEMORE AND RYAN LEWIS]]></artistName>
<country>US</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Cosmopol]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Jul 2012 15:45:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341582300]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341582300]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Sincere, emotional hip hop.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Seattle's hiphop mascot is no longer called Sir Mix-A-Lot. Macklemore is the name in 2012. At home he is close to owning the keys to the city, and the rest of America is also about to catch up on the white rapper's genuine hip hop.</p>
<p class="bodytext">The Seattle hero sends an erect middle finger to the conservative souls of the genre. Here you get to hear samples from The Killers and Red Hot Chili Peppers, a showdown with Nike in &quot;Wings&quot; and tribute songs to something as un-hip hop a sport as baseball.</p>
<p class="bodytext">With producer and beat smith Ryan Lewis aboard, Macklemore treats us with different emotional hip hop that can hijack many hearts – even outside of hip hop circles.</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/aefbec3af5.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/da4217ad06.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/macklemore-and-ryan-lewis/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="113">
<artistName><![CDATA[MAGTENS KORRIDORER]]></artistName>
<country>DK</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Orange]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Sun, 08 Jul 2012 15:00:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341752400]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341752400]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Danish-language rock anthems.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">This Danish band enjoys great popularity in their home country. And the fan base continues to grow when they deliver their catchy, straight-from-the-pub rock that skillfully channels 70s protest rock, from Danish favourites Gasolin' to The Clash.</p>
<p class="bodytext">The 2011 album <em>Imperiet falder</em> portrays a society on a collision course, but with Johan Olsen's empathic and powerful vocals at the centre you always feel safe and in good hands.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Magtens Korridorer delivers efficient, Danish-language rock you almost can sing along to, even without knowing the Danish language.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Universal</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>2</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/1bb56b45e9.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/ee35dd9918.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/magtens-korridorer-1/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="114">
<artistName><![CDATA[MAJOVCI GROUP]]></artistName>
<country>MKD</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Gloria]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Sat, 07 Jul 2012 23:00:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341694800]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341694800]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Alien wedding music from the mountain village of Galicnik.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Galicnik in western Macedonia has its own summer festival. Each year during the festival, a particularly lucky couple are married during a Galicka wedding – a ceremonious event, which includes the entire mountain village. </p>
<p class="bodytext">This ceremony is accompanied by a unique form of wedding music, an almost trance-like sound played on a zurla – a kind of obo with the same sound as bagpipes – and giant tapan drums. </p>
<p class="bodytext">Majovci Group’s music and band members are direct descendants of this tradition, which dates back more than a thousand years. With this fascinating dance orchestra, you’ll get an exotic breath of air from Eastern Europe’s colourful past.</p>
<p class="bodytext"> </p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/495aef31bc.gif]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/539e20018c.gif]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/majovci-group/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="115">
<artistName><![CDATA[MALK DE KOIJN]]></artistName>
<country>DK</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Orange]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Jul 2012 01:00:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341529200]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341615600]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Raving, Danish-language hip hop.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Hail the Danish hip hop heroes. Malk De Koijn’s nearly-legendary ‘we’re back, did you miss us’ concert at Roskilde Festival in 2009 was a true triumph that could stand alongside the greatest moments in over 40 years of festival history.<br /> <br /> The ‘welcome back’ roar will reverberate in 2012 when the Danish hip hop darlings deliver a new show at one of their absolute favourite playgrounds.<br /> <br /> Malk De Koijn fearlessly skips about in the hip hop genre and the Danish language, making neither look like itself. And with a new raving classic out, <em>Toback to the Fromtime</em>, everything suggests that 2012 will be another landmark year for this trio of sharp-tongued super men.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Langestrand Fladhjul / Target Distribution</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>2</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/cb7c035e12.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/5a9ee289f3.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/malk-de-koijn-3/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="116">
<artistName><![CDATA[MARTYN]]></artistName>
<country>NL</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Apollo]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Thu, 05 Jul 2012 20:30:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341513000]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341513000]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Challenging mix of dubstep, techno and house.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Martyn was originally regarded as a promising name in bass-heavy dubstep. Today, the Dutch producer and DJ sounds more like a type that will not put up with a single musical label.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Dubstep, techno, UK funky and drum'n'bass intersect in a transatlantic genre fusion where Detroit, London, Chicago and Berlin are just some of the electronic metropolises popping out.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Martyn is the right choice for anyone desiring a dance party full of vitamins.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Brainfeeder / import</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/441aa85669.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/9df1f71517.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/martyn/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="117">
<artistName><![CDATA[MASH UP INTERNATIONAL]]></artistName>
<country>S</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Apollo Countdown]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Sun, 01 Jul 2012 19:00:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341162000]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341162000]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Global, tropical sounding genre fusion.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Robert Dinero, Uffie Ice and Money Mats Norman constitute Mash Up International, one of the hottest names on the Scandinavian club scene right now.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Like Roskilde Festival, they mix music from far and near, and even farther. The DJ and producer group mentions kuduro, baile funk, cumbia, dancehall and kwaito as some of the points of references.</p>
<p class="bodytext">With Gnucci Banana as a vocalist in tiger stripes, they have given Miike Snow's &quot;Animal&quot; new life. A remix like this is a good example of the colourful mood and the humor that the three Swedes use to conquer the club scenes.</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="WARM-UP" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/b666af6da7.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/458fcc66bd.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/mash-up-international/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="118">
<artistName><![CDATA[THE MEGAPHONIC THRIFT]]></artistName>
<country>N</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Pavilion]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Jul 2012 12:00:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341568800]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341568800]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Elevated noise rock with melodious warmth.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">When a band names its second album after itself, it often indicates that the members have found the quintessence of their sound. It is indeed the case for The Megaphonic Thrift.</p>
<p class="bodytext">The Norwegian four-piece has taken giant strides forward since 2009 when they released promising noisy tones and played on our Pavilion Junior stage.</p>
<p class="bodytext">With the second album, these Norwegians have slit a crack in the universe from where melodious noise rock with an often psychedelic edge flows.</p>
<p class="bodytext">At the same time, the band is able to write concise melodies. The New Yorker-cool, and slightly exhausted, male voice of Richard Myklebust is challenged by the angel-like, ethereal female voice of Linn Frøkedal.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Tuba / Pad and Pen</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/477c3c0585.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/a3f1f80304.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/the-megaphonic-thrift-1/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="119">
<artistName><![CDATA[MEW]]></artistName>
<country>DK</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Orange]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Sat, 07 Jul 2012 01:30:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341617400]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341703800]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Fairytale-like and melodic rock.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Few Danish bands have had as great success home and abroad as Mew.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Mew has developed a unique sound where Jonas Bjerre's choirboy vocals are the human anchor point in a tornado of sophisticated, dreamy, often hard-hitting rock. Amidst these rugged sounds the band has even written some catchy-as-ever choruses that make even pop fans cherish this band.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Mew's concert at Roskilde Festival 2012 is one of very few played this this summer. A unique chance of a reunion with an Roskilde favorite – perhaps even with treats from their upcoming album.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Evil Office / A:larm</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>1</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/eed0be215a.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/34552523f3.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/mew-5/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="120">
<artistName><![CDATA[MODESELEKTOR]]></artistName>
<country>DE</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Apollo]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Thu, 05 Jul 2012 22:30:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341520200]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341520200]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Genre-distant techno duo.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">The live performance is the most holy call for Modeselektor.</p>
<p class="bodytext">After having been brought up in the restriction-rich DDR, the partnership Gernot Bronsert and Sebastian Szary constantly tear down mental Berlin walls with their bubbly musical alchemy consisting of equal amounts of techno, hip hop, IDM, UK bass, crunk and countless other genres.</p>
<p class="bodytext">The borderline schizophrenic, almost epilepsy-inducing style changes and the totally crazy party are drawn with bright-coloured spray paint across the modus operandi of Modeselektor.</p>
<p class="bodytext">A concert with these two Germans is a life-affirming celebration of the inexhaustible potential of music and the shudder of the body when a really deep bass thunders.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Monkeytown / VME</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/8938b45d19.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/cace98cd49.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/modeselektor/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="121">
<artistName><![CDATA[JANELLE MONÁE]]></artistName>
<country>US</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Arena]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Thu, 05 Jul 2012 23:30:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341523800]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341523800]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Alternative R&B princess returns to Roskilde.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">On rare occassions, Roskilde Festival introduces the same artist two years in a row. Sometimes, however, we are happily forced to make exceptions.<br /> <br /> Janelle Monáe's Roskilde debut in a packed Cosmopol tent last year was a dizzying triumph, which demonstrated how memorable Roskilde history is written year after year. We can hardly wait to reexperience this great talent.<br /> <br /> Janelle Monáe combines futuristic soul, R&amp;B, hip hop and rock in a show, which is a treat for both androids, dancing girls and music-snobbish lads.<br /> <br /> In 2012 it will be even bigger and with a new batch of songs loaded in the spaceship.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Bad Boy / Warner</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>2</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/5851a25ece.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/41460695d7.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/janelle-monae-1/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="122">
<artistName><![CDATA[R. STEVIE MOORE]]></artistName>
<country>US</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Gloria]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Sun, 08 Jul 2012 17:00:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341759600]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341759600]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Cult figure and DIY pioneer.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">With his mildly psychedelic, eccentric pop music, R. Stevie Moore could have been part of the same royal line as Van Dyke Parks, Frank Zappa and Kevin Ayers.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Instead he has chosen to record his more than 400 highly varied releases at home and earned a minor (read: way too small) name as the spiritual ancestor of modern DIY artists such as Guided By Voices and Ariel Pink.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Having spent a lifetime as the secret idol of various alternative rock bands, this silver-grey underground legend is finally ready for some spotlight.</p>
<p class="bodytext">R. Stevie Moore is &quot;the godfather of home recording&quot; – an independent, overlooked original whom the zeitgeist is slowly catching up on.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Cherry Red / import</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/ba37c1ec2b.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/dc7161fd39.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/r-stevie-moore/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="123">
<artistName><![CDATA[MOHAMMAD REZA MORTAZAVI]]></artistName>
<country>IRN</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Gloria]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Sun, 08 Jul 2012 13:00:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341745200]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341745200]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Drum solo virtuoso.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Drums are useful as more than just a rhythmic backbone.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Since childhood, Mohammad Reza Mortazavi has been remarkably talented with the Persian handheld drum known as the tombak. With shimmering strokes and finger techniques, the Iranian creates a new world of sounds and effects. Delicate and refined but so massive and explosively talented that you almost feel tempted to pinch your arm.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Mortazavi conjures up an almost narrative thread with his simple instrument and puts any theories about the limited capabilities of the drum to shame. </p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Flowfish / import</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/7d2b08e35c.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/a5fec14eaf.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/mohammad-reza-mortazavi/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="124">
<artistName><![CDATA[MUTINY ON THE BOUNTY]]></artistName>
<country>LUX</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Pavilion]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Sat, 07 Jul 2012 23:00:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341694800]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341694800]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Technical, hard-hitting post-hardcore.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Do you like your guitar rock progressive, hard-hitting and technical? Like, for instance, At the Drive-In, The Mars Volta and similar intelligent rock bands? </p>
<p class="bodytext">In that case, we just may have your new favourite band playing at Roskilde 2012. Mutiny On The Bounty rips your heart out with some tearing post-hardcore. </p>
<p class="bodytext">It's not just well-executed and with more ideas in one song than many bands use on an entire album. It is also brutally beautiful, melodic guitar rock that will appeal to everyone who digs music with both balls and brain. </p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Redfield / Import</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/80c6fcae12.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/d381c8a296.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/mutiny-on-the-bounty/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="125">
<artistName><![CDATA[NASUM]]></artistName>
<country>S</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Odeon]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Sun, 08 Jul 2012 18:30:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341765000]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341765000]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Bloody, misanthropic grindcore.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Roskilde Festival is – as a longstanding home of extreme metal – naturally included on Nasum’s farewell tour. </p>
<p class="bodytext">The Swedish band is responsible for some of the most exquisite musical punishments of the fast grindcore genre. Their music is more churning and sickening than a series of graphic chainsaw massacres. The often ultra-short sonic attacks have made Nasum one of the genre's finest. </p>
<p class="bodytext">The band's vocalist Mieszko Talarczyk died during the tsunami in 2004. Keijo Niinimaa from the grind mates Rotten Sound now delivers the vocals instead. </p>
<p class="bodytext">As they emphasise themselves: this is no corny reunion. Just a worthy farewell from a recognised grind band that will leave a smoking black hole in the middle of the genre map. </p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Relapse / Cosmos Music Group</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>2</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/69f8ed6495.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/4723e04c03.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/nasum/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="126">
<artistName><![CDATA[NELSON CAN]]></artistName>
<country>DK</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Pavilion Junior]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Mon, 02 Jul 2012 17:30:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341243000]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341243000]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[All-female post-punk.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Nelson Can plays rough, tearing post-punk. &quot;Spontaneously, not so much bullshit,&quot; they say themselves.</p>
<p class="bodytext">The all-female band consists of Signe, Selina and Tami who has released the catchy whistle single &quot;Apple Pie&quot; and taken the first step toward a wider audience.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Get ready for loud songs filled with attitude and lots of exclamation points but also poppy sweetness and powerful girl charm in the sparsely arranged songs.</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="WARM-UP" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/090dd1dbac.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/2322dbb9ad.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/nelson-can/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="127">
<artistName><![CDATA[NIKI & THE DOVE]]></artistName>
<country>S</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Odeon]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Jul 2012 01:00:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341529200]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341615600]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Icy synth pop.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Niki &amp; The Dove from Stockholm have already made ​​a big impression outside of Scandinavia with their opulent synth pop.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Malin Dahlström’s vocals with the thick Swedish accent are cold and chic. Gustaf Karlöf’s swarming arrangements are both compact, sophisticated and the perfect backdrop for the duo's melodic songs.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Niki &amp; The Dove are a duo on the way up, and they may very well be the scoop of the year for anyone who enjoys the likes of Björk, The Knife or Oh Land.</p>
<p class="bodytext">The duo's live shows are known to be spectacular extravaganzas where the two Swedes’ theatric past doesn’t really shows.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Sub Pop / Universal</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/2a4fc837bb.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/1cdd80d6e7.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/niki-the-dove/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="128">
<artistName><![CDATA[NIKLAS]]></artistName>
<country>DK</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Cosmopol]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Sat, 07 Jul 2012 12:30:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341657000]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341657000]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Mysterious, home-grown pop star.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">With his face hidden in dark shadows and a series of YouTube hits, Niklas has become one of today's hottest, totally home-grown pop acts.</p>
<p class="bodytext">The mysterious, Swedish-raised rapper and pop singer does not show his face in any of his videos. Still it's clear that Niklas has a remarkable talent for creating hits full of Danish-language rap, syrupy sweet synths, 90s disco and power-flirtatious funk attitude.</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/9b9af908dd.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/050477fff9.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/niklas/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="129">
<artistName><![CDATA[NORTHERN STRUCTURES]]></artistName>
<country>DK</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Apollo Countdown]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Mon, 02 Jul 2012 19:00:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341248400]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341248400]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Copenhagen techno with international stature.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Lasse Buhl and Troels B-Knudsen are proud children of the environment surrounding the Copenhagen venue Culture Box – a Danish, if not Nordic, epicentre of techno and electronic music.</p>
<p class="bodytext">With an original starting point on the drum'n'bass scene, the lads have delved into more straightforward techno. The duo's Nordic sound has been so convincing that the, in techno circles, semi-legendary label Sonic Groove has invited them into their fold.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Northern Structures are a good example of the fact that Copenhagen can compare with techno capitals such as Berlin and Detroit.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Sonic Groove</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="WARM-UP" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/dfe6ccd4e5.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/204d83b047.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/northern-structures/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="130">
<artistName><![CDATA[OF THE WAND AND THE MOON]]></artistName>
<country>DK</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Pavilion]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Jul 2012 20:00:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341597600]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341597600]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Gloomy folk noir.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">European dark folk or neo-folk is with its minor chords, march rhythms and melancholic vision not a genre that gets much attention.</p>
<p class="bodytext">One of the most prominent bands of the darkened, cultural-pessimistic genre is Of The Wand And The Moon.</p>
<p class="bodytext"><em>The Lone Descent</em> from 2011 frames the mood of an occult mass deep inside a North European forest lit up by torches. But according to the musical mastermind, inspiration is also found in 60s icons such as Lee Hazlewood and Serge Gainsbourg.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Of The Wand And The Moon is beautiful doom music filled with catchy melodies and dark atmosphere.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Heidrunar Myrkrunar / VME</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/02c792a254.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/8eec244493.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/of-the-wand-and-the-moon/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="131">
<artistName><![CDATA[ONEOHTRIX POINT NEVER]]></artistName>
<country>US</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Gloria]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Jul 2012 03:00:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341536400]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341622800]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Progressive, experimental electronica.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext"> With a number of challenging releases – most recently <em>Replica</em>, based on samples from old TV ads – Daniel Lopatin has placed his curious nickname centrally on the experimental, progressive electronica scene.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Using samples, effects, loops and synths, the Brooklyn-based composer/producer flips, bends, pushes and curls his piled-up musical structures out of shape and focus until cosmos and chaos blend together.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Oneohtrix Point Never is a hefty sound bombardment filled with colours, dark acid, earthquaking vibrations and ideas. </p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Editions Mego / Cooperative</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/05b747d405.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/54ed69ee30.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/oneohtrix-point-never/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="132">
<artistName><![CDATA[ORQUESTA TÍPICA FERNÁNDEZ FIERRO]]></artistName>
<country>ARG</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Cosmopol]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Thu, 05 Jul 2012 17:30:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341502200]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341502200]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Modern tango played by young men with a revolutionary spark.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">The 12-piece Orquesta Típica Fernández Fierro has given the lifeblood-dripping tango a revolutionary update and is hitting the spot in Argentina as well as the rest of the world. </p>
<p class="bodytext">Here's a rare chance to experience swelling emotions, sensual glow and the classical 2/4 time of tango by a group of casually clad tangueros who grab the tango genre by the throat with a ferocious and punk-like attitude.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Experience the drama of tango, unrefined beauty and poetry, which could not have been made at any other time in history – fresh from the streets of Buenos Aires.</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/374af2dc27.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/444e490cbc.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/orquesta-tipica-fernandez-fierro/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="133">
<artistName><![CDATA[OWINY SIGOMA BAND]]></artistName>
<country>UK/KEN</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Cosmopol]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Sat, 07 Jul 2012 14:00:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341662400]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341662400]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[London high-fives Nairobi.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">The traditional songs of Kenya are given a gleam of today’s London with Owiny Sigoma Band.</p>
<p class="bodytext">In 2009, a group of London-based lads (their resumé includes the art-funk band Elmore Judd and Gorillaz) went to Nairobi to jam with the local musicians, originating in the traditions of the Luo people. The result was so appealing and funky that the influential world music pusher, DJ and radio host Gilles Peterson signed the band. </p>
<p class="bodytext">The focal point of the music is a special Kenyan harp called the nyatiti. The English musicians spar attentively, humbly and instinctively with the Africans’ hypnotic music. </p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Brownswood / import</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/e4367cf157.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/1b9baf1c9b.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/owiny-sigoma-band/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="134">
<artistName><![CDATA[PENGUIN PRISON]]></artistName>
<country>US</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Cosmopol]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Sat, 07 Jul 2012 01:30:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341617400]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341703800]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Festive and intelligent dance pop with lots of positive vibes.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Chris Glover is not likely to be grateful for the financial crisis (who is, anyway?) but his single &quot;Don't Fuck With My Money&quot; hardly could have come out at a better time.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Penguin Prison, Glover's mysterious alias, didn't just hit the spirit of the times spot on with this single. The New Yorker specialises in bubbly, positive, intelligent, hipster-approved party music with equal tastes of Hot Chip, Daft Punk and Justin Timberlake.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Despite the single, Penguin Prison remains the perfect cure for you if you want to party, flirt, dance and forget financial troubles for a while.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Stranger / import</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/40736b67ee.png]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/de39fcc604.png]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/penguin-prison/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="135">
<artistName><![CDATA[PERFUME GENIUS]]></artistName>
<country>US</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Gloria]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Thu, 05 Jul 2012 23:00:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341522000]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341522000]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Delicate and moving piano ballads.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">A melancholic voice and a battered piano are the starting point.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Perfume Genius digs the simple set-up, and it's hard not to get sucked into Mike Hadreas’ universe of simple minor chords and shattered destinies.</p>
<p class="bodytext">The bright angelic voice from Seattle writes piano ballads so beautiful and winged that you almost see the ill-fated characters from the songs walk past you. The new album <em>Put Your Back N 2 It</em> is even more direct in its choice of subject than its predecessor – it often touches upon homosexual love, addiction and suicide.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Perfume Genius is almost shockingly direct in his lyrics, and the music is filled with wonderful melancholy.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Matador / Playground<br /></p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/f9aaed97ee.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/917355ddb0.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/perfume-genius/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="136">
<artistName><![CDATA[CELSO PIÑA]]></artistName>
<country>MEX</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Cosmopol]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Jul 2012 19:30:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341595800]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341595800]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Cumbia pioneer and accordion veteran.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">&quot;El Rebelde del Acordeón&quot;, &quot;El Rey de la Cumbia Colombiana&quot;. Celso Piña enjoys many honourable nicknames in the Spanish-speaking world.</p>
<p class="bodytext">The Mexican veteran is one of the main architects behind the cumbia genre's renaissance in Latin America. In recent years, the tropical sunshine music has also provided the basis for countless fiestas at Roskilde Festival.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Piña gives the old Colombian genre an electronic touch while incorporating everything from ska to rap in his urban, groundbreaking sound.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: La Tuna / import</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/c48ff63e6f.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/af415d05e2.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/celso-pina/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="137">
<artistName><![CDATA[KIMMO POHJONEN / SAMULI KOSMINEN and PROTON STRING QUARTET]]></artistName>
<country>FIN</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Pavilion]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Sat, 07 Jul 2012 15:30:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341667800]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341667800]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Futuristic music for accordion, strings and samples.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Known to many as the Jimi Hendrix of the accordion, Kimmo Pohjonen transforms the mariner’s instrument of choice into an avant-garde contraption from the future.</p>
<p class="bodytext">With an experienced group of strings and sample/percussion magician Samuli Kosminen behind him, the energetic front man creates a cross-dressing total experience that is equal parts modern compositions, manipulated electronics and strange art rock.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Samples, loops and classical strings are elegantly united with Pohjonen’s ecstatic and crude grip on the accordion. </p>
<p class="bodytext">A trippy experience for all musical daredevils who like to travel far from the mainland of music.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Ondine / import</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/45996d5cd2.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/44acbf7aee.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/kimmo-pohjonen-samuli-kosminen-and-proton-string-quartet/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="138">
<artistName><![CDATA[PRETTY LIGHTS]]></artistName>
<country>US</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Apollo]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Sat, 07 Jul 2012 02:30:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341621000]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341707400]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Versatile, electronic master of chaos.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext"> We have a treat for fans of brostep, mashup, glitchhop – or the musical language-impaired who simply needs a ride in the genre carousel where the mirror ball is always spinning and the seasick hip hop beats just continue.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Pretty Lights make the dance floor sizzle with his visuals-marinated shows where Derek Vincent Smith from his laptop creates a psychedelic party full of 2012 sensation, acidy cut-ups, recycled chorus fragments, mutated dubstep and lazer-cut beats.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Following the tradition of DJ Shadow, Pretty Lights shows how to steal left, right and centre while still mixing his own, radioactively luminous brew. </p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Pretty Lights Music</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/dc3beb7d61.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/c05cb717d4.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/pretty-lights/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="139">
<artistName><![CDATA[PUNCH BROTHERS]]></artistName>
<country>US</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Pavilion]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341525600]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341612000]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Bluegrass visionaries on the rise.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">According to music legend T Bone Burnett, Chris Thile – frontman and mandolin visionary in Punch Brothers – may very well be to bluegrass music what Louis Armstrong was to jazz.</p>
<p class="bodytext">With their banjo, guitar, mandolin, fiddle and upright bass, Punch Brothers may look like your classic homegrown bluegrass band. But this quintet is undeniably contemporary, and their folk sound doesn’t prevent them from flirting intensively with jazz, pop and alternative rock.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Experience yourself why Punch Brothers are being called the future of bluegrass by the good people of Memphis, the stronghold of this traditional and authentic genre.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Nonesuch / Warner</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/e10fd9a055.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/0593a3dd9a.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/punch-brothers/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="140">
<artistName><![CDATA[LEE RANALDO]]></artistName>
<country>US</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Odeon]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Jul 2012 21:00:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341601200]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341601200]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Guitar geek from Sonic Youth.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Lee Ranaldo has been a core member of genre-defining noise rock band Sonic Youth for 30 years. The band is now on hiatus, and it has given Ranaldo time to complete his solo project, which was started back in 2010.</p>
<p class="bodytext">As a guitarist Ranaldo has been at the intersection between experimental minimalism and alternative rock. He recently released his first song-oriented solo album <em>Between The</em><em> Times And The Tides</em>.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Together with Sonic Youth drummer Steve Shelley and Alan Licht, among others, he has built on a musical universe based on classic, alternative rock. No radio-friendly songs here, but an obvious joy of playing the music he does best.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Matador / Playground</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>2</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/ab02cb5c34.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/95ab0f93d8.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/lee-ranaldo/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="141">
<artistName><![CDATA[RANGLEKLODS]]></artistName>
<country>DK</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Cosmopol]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Jul 2012 12:00:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341568800]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341568800]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Dark baritone pop mixed with experimental electronica. ]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Under the name of Rangleklods, Esben Andersen leads the way between organic songwriting and the electronic music’s cooler universe.</p>
<p class="bodytext">On the debut album <em>Beekeeper,</em> Rangleklods demonstrates how to create dark-edged, melodious baritone pop using the computer’s musical platform. Techno, trip hop, IDM and many other more synthetic genres flow constantly in the underground of this artist's universe.</p>
<p class="bodytext">The electronic sophistication is only one side of the coin with Rangleklods whose music is made just as much for the stage as for laptop in the bedroom.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Sound of Copenhagen / A:larm</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/6eb8880b50.gif]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/36abbb22b4.gif]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/rangleklods/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="142">
<artistName><![CDATA[RED FANG]]></artistName>
<country>US</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Odeon]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Jul 2012 14:00:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341576000]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341576000]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Beer-thirsty bulldozer rock.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">The members of Oregon's perhaps most beer-thirsty hard rock band all have a past in a variety of lesser-known outfits. With Red Fang they believe they have found the ultimate goal of their many years in the holy service of the riff.</p>
<p class="bodytext">The 2011 album <em>Murder The Mountains</em> gives good insight into what awaits Roskilde Festival’s hordes of hops-hungry rock fans this summer: a testosterone-driven update of Black Sabbath, Melvins and Kyuss. A party for everyone convinced that The Lord not only has a long beard but also a checkered shirt, a spiked belt and a can of beer in his hand.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Relapse / Cosmos Music Group</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/065bd2f9eb.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/178d8ca806.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/red-fang/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="143">
<artistName><![CDATA[REDWOOD HILL]]></artistName>
<country>DK</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Pavilion Junior]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Sun, 01 Jul 2012 16:00:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341151200]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341151200]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Dark-minded post metal.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Nordic, heavy and depressive are in some contexts almost synonymous.</p>
<p class="bodytext">This is definitely the case with Redwood Hill – a new razor-sharp five-piece from Copenhagen who thunders with post-metal of the both minor chord-melodious and brutal kind.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Redwood Hill, who's releasing the debut album in 2012, is a promising acquaintance for fans of intelligent metal and Scandinavian dark-mindedness. </p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="WARM-UP" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/1e5b84915f.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/3263aeb983.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/redwood-hill/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="144">
<artistName><![CDATA[REFUSED]]></artistName>
<country>S</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Arena]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Sat, 07 Jul 2012 18:00:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341676800]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341676800]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Advanced, legendary hardcore.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext"><em>The Shape Of Punk To Come</em> – one of the hardcore genre's undisputed masterpieces – resulted in Refused splitting up while this hand grenade of an album cemented their status as a central and widely influencing band.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Now the Swedes make up for lost time. Fans of metal, punk and (post-)hardcore have gaped at the chance of experiencing this favourite band on stage where they, reportedly, are even more intense than on album.</p>
<p class="bodytext">We are looking forward to delighting both old and new fans with high-level hardcore. Packed with rhythmic complexity, daring and violent kamikaze attacks on everything conformist in this world.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Epitaph / Cosmos Music Group</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>2</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/862dacc7db.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/3fad9ecf08.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/refused/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="145">
<artistName><![CDATA[ROCKWELL]]></artistName>
<country>UK</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Apollo]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Sat, 07 Jul 2012 20:00:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341684000]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341684000]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Hot, young drum'n'bass.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">In a matter of short time, Rockwell has become one of the most wanted artists on the drum'n'bass scene – with bookings at both the London bass temple Fabric and wherever the music is playing hard and hot in Saint Petersburg.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Rockwell has a distinct flair of making the dance floor boil over with his fierce beats. And according to an interview, the Brit spends months working on all the intricate details on a single track.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Rockwell is predicted to be one of the next big acts by anyone with just the slightest sense of drum'n'bass. Show up while you still have a chance to see him from the front row.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Shogun Audio / import</p>
<p class="bodytext"> </p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/641b0b50ab.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/290c436dd7.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/rockwell/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="146">
<artistName><![CDATA[THE ROOTS]]></artistName>
<country>US</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Orange]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Sat, 07 Jul 2012 17:00:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341673200]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341673200]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Organic hip hop with a politically beating heart.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Many people call The Roots the best live band of hip hop for their swing and rock band feeling. Deservedly so.</p>
<p class="bodytext">The hard-working hip hop collective from Philadelphia make their instruments glow and sound just as organic and authentic as a crackling vinyl record.</p>
<p class="bodytext">?uestlove, Black Thought and co lead the way when it comes to hip hop packed with hot neo-soul, social indignation, humour, funk and improv-minded jazz.</p>
<p class="bodytext">The Roots rarely visits Europe nowadays, and they play at Roskilde Festival exclusively in Scandinavia.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Def Jam / Universal</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>1</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/1a109beb64.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/55dedbe708.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/the-roots-2/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="147">
<artistName><![CDATA[CHRISTINA ROSENVINGE feat. CHRIS BROKAW & REFREE]]></artistName>
<country>E/US</country>
<scene><![CDATA[]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341673200]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Spanish singer accompanied by Mr. Sadcore himself.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">In the course of three decades as a performing artist, Christina Rosenvinge has become an experience artist who has progressed from teenage pop idol to a respected alternative artist in Spain.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Her characteristic vocals are reminiscent of both Stina Nordenstam and Cat Power. She has a loyal audience in Spain but has never performed up North.</p>
<p class="bodytext">For this unique, first concert in Denmark, she is accompanied by sadcore legend Chris Brokaw of Codeine and the Catalan troubadour Refree.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Warner Music Spain / import</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/5b6f9b8a07.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/cf04bde044.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/christina-rosenvinge-feat-chris-brokaw-refree/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="148">
<artistName><![CDATA[ROVER]]></artistName>
<country>FR</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Gloria]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Jul 2012 19:00:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341594000]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341594000]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Lyrical pop revolving around a fantastic voice.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Timothée Régnier’s passport may be French but his history indicates why his stage name “Rover” isn’t a coincidence.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Returned from Lebanon, Rover spent a whole stormy winter, like another Bon Iver, writing and instrumentating songs in a dilapidated house.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Rover has already mesmerised fans of lyrical pop in France with his fantastic voice, which has been compared to Anthony Hegarty’s.</p>
<p class="bodytext">When singing, the well-travelled Frenchman’s English is practically flawless and can be traced back to his childhood years in New York.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Rover’s first full album is on its way in 2012.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Wagram / Target Distribution</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/732611b807.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/d0b4346024.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/rover/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="149">
<artistName><![CDATA[ROYCE DA 5’9”]]></artistName>
<country>US</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Cosmopol]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Sun, 08 Jul 2012 14:00:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341748800]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341748800]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[The unsung master of Detroit hip hop.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">He has shared the stage with Eminem in the duo Bad Meets Evil, worked as ghost writer for Dr. Dre and is part of the super group Slaughterhouse. Yet, Royce Da 5’9” has only made a name for himself in narrow circles. </p>
<p class="bodytext">With the comeback album <em>Success Is Certain </em>he stages the big breakthrough. Here the experienced rapper authoritatively puts his skills as a MC on display. </p>
<p class="bodytext">After some turbulent years, Ryan Montgomery is ready to take the stage and prove why he is one of America's undeservedly overlooked rappers. </p>
<p class="bodytext">Come and witness a true hip hop resurrection. The time has come. </p>
<p class="bodytext">Shady / Universal</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/607a0710d9.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/0543ce0c39.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/royce-da-59/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="150">
<artistName><![CDATA[RUM 37]]></artistName>
<country>DK</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Pavilion Junior]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Tue, 03 Jul 2012 22:00:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341345600]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341345600]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Ultra-Scandinavian, Danish-language rock.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Danish-language rock thrives these days. Take Rum 37, for instance, who plays wistful guitar rock with echoes of other Scandinavian-tongued bands such as Kent and Love Shop.</p>
<p class="bodytext">The band's first EP demonstrates a firm grasp of the Nordic, blue-toned songwriting tradition.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Kristian Helmuth sings with intensity about his Copenhagen, the fluidity of life and the sun that burns a hole in the dark clouds.</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="WARM-UP" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/001bf4b6c3.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/6d24819325.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/rum-37/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="151">
<artistName><![CDATA[SAGE FRANCIS]]></artistName>
<country>US</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Cosmopol]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Jul 2012 15:45:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341582300]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341582300]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Protest hip hop from white pioneer.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">With his literary aura and often political choice of topic, Sage Francis is far from the hip hop mainstream.</p>
<p class="bodytext">The indie rapper from Rhode Island has, if anybody, been one of the pioneers when it comes to weaken the distinction between alternative rock, poetry slam and hip hop.</p>
<p class="bodytext">On the latest album <em>Li(f)e</em>, the protest hip hopper raps on top of an instrumental backing that has more in common with swampy, white roots rock than chocolate-brown soul or R&amp;B. Particularly organised religion gets a clout on the head, but Francis’ well-told stories don’t spare himself.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Sage Francis rarely plays live nowadays. Don’t miss a rapper who knows his Bob Dylan and Tom Waits as well as his Public Enemy.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Strange Famous / import</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/387b59c443.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/5b41e28cc8.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/sage-francis/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="152">
<artistName><![CDATA[SANTIGOLD]]></artistName>
<country>US</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Arena]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Sun, 08 Jul 2012 20:30:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341772200]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341772200]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Hyperurban new wave.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">As far back as in 2008, Roskilde Festival had its eye on Santigold who with great self-confidence treated the audience at the Cosmopol stage with her chic mix of R&amp;B, dub, new wave and hyperurban pop.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Now the follow-up to her debut album is finally on its way, and judging from the reception of her current single, the mainstream audience has missed her as much as we have. The catchy tune “Disparate Youth” seems to have become one of the defining tunes of 2012 already.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Santigold is one-of-a-kind and a style icon in the vein of Karen O and M.I.A., and we are proud to present this hot, entertaining artist for the second time at this early point in her, most likely, long career.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Atlantic / Warner</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>2</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/f7c100d562.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/fa84bffb93.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/santigold/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="153">
<artistName><![CDATA[MATHILDE SAVERY]]></artistName>
<country>DK</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Pavilion Junior]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Mon, 02 Jul 2012 14:30:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341232200]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341232200]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Very young singer-songwriter.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">18-year-old Mathilde Savery has made quite an impression with a minimum of means. With a strong, personal voice and a firm grip around her acoustic guitar, the young singer has already captured her first hearts. Many more await ahead.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Mathilde Savery sounds confident and determined to bring her folk songs out to a big audience. This year she enters the studio to record her debut album.</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="WARM-UP" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/2a20be7f2f.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/34761dcb70.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/mathilde-savery/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="154">
<artistName><![CDATA[THE SHINS]]></artistName>
<country>US</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Arena]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Thu, 05 Jul 2012 18:00:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341504000]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341504000]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[The alternative pop princes are back. ]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">It's been five years since The Shins last played at Roskilde Festival. In 2012, James Mercer's band rises again with new band members – and probably with a few tricks from Broken Bells, Mercer's collaboration with Danger Mouse.</p>
<p class="bodytext">The Shins play sunshine-filled guitar pop with gilt-edged tunes, a little eccentricity and self-destructive attitude. At the same time, the band's new incarnation seems more comfortable in the stadium spotlight than before.</p>
<p class="bodytext">The Shins are not just an underground band that has overtaken many mainstream bands. The American band is  also an educational acquaintance for older festival-goers who think that no one writes songs like Paul McCartney and Brian Wilson nowadays.</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>2</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/3adacbd38c.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/6689db12d6.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/the-shins-1/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="155">
<artistName><![CDATA[SHINY DARKLY]]></artistName>
<country>DK</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Pavilion Junior]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Tue, 03 Jul 2012 17:30:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341329400]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341329400]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Garage rock with leather jacket and shades.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Shiny leather jacket darkness permeates everything when Shiny Darkly turns on the amplifiers.</p>
<p class="bodytext">With a well-developed understanding of classic, dirty garage rock riffs, these three young lads have already – on a basis of few exquisite songs – convinced the Danish music press, the picky underground and the equally choosy label Crunchy Frog about their potential.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Shiny Darkly’s dark rock'n'roll is perfect for anyone who feels that the clock is always just a few minutes to midnight.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Crunchy Frog</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="WARM-UP" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/cdb51cdb1f.png]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/5a3b3ddaa8.png]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/shiny-darkly/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="156">
<artistName><![CDATA[SHLOHMO]]></artistName>
<country>US</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Gloria]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Sun, 08 Jul 2012 21:00:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341774000]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341774000]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Delicate, atmospheric electronica.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Henry Laufer – the real name behind Shlohmo – is a child of the same Los Angeles that has delivered former Roskilde artists such as Gonjasufi and The Gaslamp Killer.</p>
<p class="bodytext">He is only in his early 20s but he is soon-to-be recognised as one of the stars in the major city's underground.</p>
<p class="bodytext">The young beat smith cuts into a personal niche with his delicate, electronic music. The music is based on several thresholds, including abstract hip hop, nature programme soundtracks in the vein of Boards of Canada and post-London dubstep.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Shlohmo is the sound of an unruly, creative Los Angeles. A music mecca in its own right next to New York.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Friends of Friends / import</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/a32f6261ba.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/c4b67beb74.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/shlohmo/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="157">
<artistName><![CDATA[SLENG]]></artistName>
<country>DK</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Apollo Countdown]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Wed, 04 Jul 2012 20:30:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341426600]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341426600]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Grime hip hop with attitude and clenched fists.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">The Copenhagen hood Nørrebro is no longer the sole destination for fans of homegrown grime hip hop. The Copenhagen suburb Vangede is also worth namedropping among fans of Danish-language, sharp-tongued rap.<br /> <br /> Sleng consists of two high school lads, Aesthetic &amp; Larry, full of attitude. They have embraced the originally British hip hop variety and have already become major players on the scene. YouTube and Facebook have been the right channels to create a solid fanbase.<br /> <br /> Sleng’s pared, angular songs are filled with witty blows and clenched fists. Sensitive souls better go in hiding.</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="WARM-UP" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/1de1f37b8e.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/1929bcbb74.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/sleng/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="158">
<artistName><![CDATA[SLOWOLF]]></artistName>
<country>DK</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Pavilion Junior]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Wed, 04 Jul 2012 19:00:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341421200]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341421200]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Sumptuous, electronic pop.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Andreas Asingh's new solo project is shrouded in secrecy and mystery.</p>
<p class="bodytext">It's obvious, however, that Asingh knows how to produce electronic falsetto pop songs that could get both disco godfather Giorgio Moroder and pet shop boy Neil Tennant to shout with joy.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Don't think that Slowolf is only for people who love crisp synths and light vocals. The coming debut album contains a visit from hip hop king Raekwon from Wu-Tang Clan.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Slowolf / A:larm</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="WARM-UP" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/90e53040c5.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/fc82c5580d.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/slowolf/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="159">
<artistName><![CDATA[SPECKTORS]]></artistName>
<country>DK</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Cosmopol]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Sat, 07 Jul 2012 03:00:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341622800]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341709200]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Clubby Copenhagen slum hip hop with a party guarantee.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Danish-language hip hop is a stoned city full of rocking beats.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Using Shanksville as an imaginative place, Specktors fill their self-titled debut album with twaddling strokes of genius about pubs, apocalyptic hangovers and tribal tattoos.</p>
<p class="bodytext">On a sizzling bed of clubby electro, the troublemakers shits between cheeky, silly and benighted.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Specktors are the guarantors of a hip hop party full of attitude. 2012 also offers a new album from the four nightclub pirates.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: EMI </p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/41a5c4c3d9.gif]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/bdc223b254.gif]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/specktors/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="160">
<artistName><![CDATA[SPECTOR]]></artistName>
<country>UK</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Pavilion]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Jul 2012 22:00:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341604800]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341604800]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Quintessential British pop.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">2012 may very well be <em>the </em>year for Spector.<br /> <br /> Front man Fred MacPherson is in his early 20s but has already been in several bands. As the lead singer of Spector the equation seems to be solved. And now things are really speeding up.<br /> <br /> The suit-clad boys have been called London's answer to The Strokes, but judging from the first singles the five-piece sounds more like a new shoot off the same branch as Roxy Music, Pulp and The Killers.<br /> <br /> Spector has the right mix of youthful zest for life, quintessential British weltschmerz and humorous tongue in cheek to go far.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Luv Luv Luv / Universal</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/c18c8a74df.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/afb8821c42.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/spector/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="161">
<artistName><![CDATA[SPILLEMÆNDENE]]></artistName>
<country>DK</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Gloria]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Sat, 07 Jul 2012 17:00:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341673200]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341673200]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Danish-language, poetic folk.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">With a point of departure in the ballad and folk tradition, Spillemændene conquer their own baroque, literary universe.</p>
<p class="bodytext">The lyrical universe is filled with equal parts pathos and humour, ands the songs in major reveal a great passion and understanding of the classic songwriting craft.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Nicolai Elsberg has a sonorous voice and is an original storyteller, like a young Danish version of Leonard Cohen.</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/079c0a0983.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/556593e31a.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/spillemaendene-4/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="162">
<artistName><![CDATA[SPLEEN UNITED]]></artistName>
<country>DK</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Arena]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Jul 2012 02:30:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341534600]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341621000]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Melancholic, euphoric dance party.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">The rock band Spleen United seems to have disappeared. From the ashes rises a changed creature. An all electronic, neon-coloured rave band for people who – even on the dance floor – demand a shot of melancholy in the music to get their feet to move.</p>
<p class="bodytext">With <em>School of</em><em> Euphoria</em>, these depressive young lads of pop throw themselves completely into the arms of electronic dance music that makes the mirror balls spin in synthesized ecstasy.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Their 2012 sound is at the same time light as helium and weighed on by the same depression that gave the band its name.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Spleen United still feels pain deep down inside but the euphoria of dance music has also become a steady partner.</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>2</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/13adb9f9cb.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/a270cb7386.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/spleen-united-2/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="163">
<artistName><![CDATA[SPOEK MATHAMBO]]></artistName>
<country>ZA</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Cosmopol]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Sat, 07 Jul 2012 16:00:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341669600]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341669600]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Gloomy hip hop prince from the Johannesburg townships.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Imagine an acid trip in Soweto, Johannesburg after midnight, translated into music. That's just about the sound of Mathambo.</p>
<p class="bodytext">With a grimy mix of electro, rap, South African house and dystopian bass music –genreless &quot;township tech&quot;, he calls it himself – this dark hip hop prince will soon become a new name on the global guerilla pop scene, led especially by M.I.A.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Spoek Mathambo is claustrophobic but danceable midnight music, filled with robotic beats and rough ghetto sounds.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Sub Pop / Target Distribution</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/4b4157f69b.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/88bae5f49a.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/spoek-mathambo/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="164">
<artistName><![CDATA[BRUCE SPRINGSTEEN & THE E STREET BAND]]></artistName>
<country>US</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Orange]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Sat, 07 Jul 2012 21:00:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341687600]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341687600]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[One of the biggest rock icons takes Orange Stage.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Get ready for some ”Glory Days” at Roskilde Festival when Bruce Springsteen takes the iconic main stage. Having this denim-clad superhero on Orange Stage is no longer a dream scenario. </p>
<p class="bodytext">In 2012, he and his faithful E Street Band will fill a summer’s night with poetic rock songs about New Jersey, the hopelessness of blue-collar working days and life on empty small town streets when you are born to run. </p>
<p class="bodytext">Bruce Springsteen's influence on rock history can hardly be overstated. Without this masterful songwriter and storyteller, younger bands such as Arcade Fire and The  National would not sound the way they do. </p>
<p class="bodytext">Regardless of age and knowledge of Bruce Springsteen, it is practically a civic duty to experience this artist who – despite his simple and unpretentious craft – towers up on the rock horizon. </p>
<p class="bodytext">Columbia / Sony Music</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>1</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/dce9656473.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/164336e2a2.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/bruce-springsteen-the-e-street-band/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="165">
<artistName><![CDATA[SPRUTBASS]]></artistName>
<country>N</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Apollo Countdown]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Tue, 03 Jul 2012 16:00:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341324000]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341324000]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Synthetic funk from Norway.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Scandinavia has recently developed its own electronic underground dance genre. It is called skweee and is an odd distortion of British bass music and electro funk, typically performed on outdated computer equipment.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Mr. Sprutbass, Eivind Henjum, claims that he and the people from the Dødpop label have created skweee 2.0 – a special variant of the sound from Norway.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Look forward to some morbid electronics – of fierce, freaky and genre-founding kind.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Død Pop / import</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="WARM-UP" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/68248d7520.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/2079e84f25.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/sprutbass/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="166">
<artistName><![CDATA[STAFF BENDA BILILI]]></artistName>
<country>CD</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Cosmopol]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Sat, 07 Jul 2012 20:15:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341684900]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341684900]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Life-affirming rumba from the depths of the Kinshasa slums.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">They excited on our Cosmopol stage with a great funk party in 2010 when all skeptical misgivings were groundless.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Staff Benda Bilili is a group of Congolese polio survivors in wheelchairs who, despite poverty and disease, have developed a stripped-down but smiling mix of rumba, soul and <em>congotronics</em>. A contagious musical acquaintance filled with insisting rhythms and compelling call-response vocals.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Staff Benda Bilili steadily moves upwards on the global music scene. The sympathetic and always impeccably dressed band conquers Roskilde Festival again. </p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Crammed Discs / import</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/f341c3d726.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/d4af8e5275.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/staff-benda-bilili-1/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="167">
<artistName><![CDATA[DJ STATIC w/ TEMU, BLOOD SWEAT DRUM+BASS and GUESTS]]></artistName>
<country>DK</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Arena]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Sun, 08 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341698400]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341784800]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Danish hip hop extravagance with over 80 participants.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">&quot;The backbone of hip hop is the DJ.&quot;</p>
<p class="bodytext">Simply put and very apt for this extravagant setup where DJ Static leads a 27-piece big band and plays his coming album <em>Rolig Under Pres</em> in its entirety.</p>
<p class="bodytext">It’s an album, and a concert visited by Danish acts such as Jokeren, Peter Sommer, Orgi-E, Per Vers, Raske Penge and Swedish rapper Promoe – among many more.</p>
<p class="bodytext">The huge setup has over 80 musicians, rappers and singers and is seasoned with hip hop classics, breakdance and freestyles</p>
<p class="bodytext">A unique show created especially for the best audience in Europe.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Playground</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/5979129ef0.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/e32a4761cc.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/dj-static-w-temu-blood-sweat-drum-bass-and-guests/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="168">
<artistName><![CDATA[SUICIDE SILENCE]]></artistName>
<country>US</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Pavilion]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Sun, 08 Jul 2012 21:00:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341774000]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341774000]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Uncompromising deathcore.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">With three albums under the belt, Suicide Silence are uncompromising and persistent young lions from the metal scene.</p>
<p class="bodytext">The third release is called <em>The Black Crown</em>. Here they overwhelm a growing crowd of disciples with deathcore, filled to the brim with growling and screaming vocals, manic intensity and explosive energy.</p>
<p class="bodytext">The band has learned from the busy touring schedules and has taken the most brutal parts from the previous albums. They have constructed an even fiercer beast that, according to the band, &quot;attacks, attacks, attacks&quot;.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Show up and take some beatings from a fast-paced hard sound from a confident band who is ready to take the lead.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Century Media / EMI</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/ef67867d53.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/4d65135c74.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/suicide-silence/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="169">
<artistName><![CDATA[THE SWAY MACHINERY]]></artistName>
<country>US</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Gloria]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Sat, 07 Jul 2012 00:45:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341614700]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341701100]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Jewish cantor singing mixed with global, eclectic beats.
]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Jeremiah Lockwood has the spiritual Jewish music as a starting point for his tradition-bound project The Sway Machinery. He plants the chanting, vibrating cantor singing in a gaudy flowerbed of African, East European and Middle Eastern sounds.</p>
<p class="bodytext">At the same time, the interplay and the brass band guarantee a playful and rocking atmosphere, lifting the ancient music traditions to a higher level of funk and Afrobeat-like music.</p>
<p class="bodytext">The many musical impulses, inspirations and impressions will ensure that The Sway Machinery will be an unpredictable visit to the synagogue.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Jdub / import</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/ed78d2fd63.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/df8f3f6a94.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/the-sway-machinery/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="170">
<artistName><![CDATA[JULIUS SYLVEST]]></artistName>
<country>DK</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Apollo Countdown]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Tue, 03 Jul 2012 20:30:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341340200]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341340200]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Copenhagen DJ with preference for global beats.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext"> With a preference for kuduro, cumbia and other global beats, Julius Sylvest – who is also a part of the DJ crew Lortehænderne – is obviously a DJ after Roskilde Festival's multi-coloured musical heart. And we are not alone in our opinion.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Reportedly, Diplo has also given this Dane a nod of acknowledgement.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Julius Sylvest guarantees Hawaiian shirt-patterned, electronic festivities filled with insisting rhythms and Caribbean heat.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Palms Out Sounds</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="WARM-UP" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/c7bad34f0d.png]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/1645204632.png]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/julius-sylvest/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="171">
<artistName><![CDATA[TALK NORMAL]]></artistName>
<country>US</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Gloria]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Sat, 07 Jul 2012 21:00:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341687600]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341687600]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Cacophonic and cool girl band.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Through their basic combination of beauty-insulting guitar playing and minimalistic drumming, Talk Normal revive New York as the capital of musical noise as it once was in the early 80s under the banner of no wave.</p>
<p class="bodytext">The Brooklyn duo – consisting of Sarah Register on guitar and Andrya Ambro on drums – rips through songs that sparkle with dissonance, energy and wildness.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Being completely non-dogmatic and cool, Talk Normal sets a noisy agenda that once more makes jarring guitars sound fresh, frothing and dangerous.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Rare Book Room / import</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/1ce5f39be3.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/f35a8d97af.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/talk-normal/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="172">
<artistName><![CDATA[TEAM ME]]></artistName>
<country>N</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Pavilion Junior]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Wed, 04 Jul 2012 22:00:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341432000]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341432000]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Majestic, big orchestrated indie pop.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">As the band name suggests, Team Me was just supposed to be Marius Hagen's solo/side project. Instead, things sped up.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Today the six-piece Team Me is one of Arcade Fire's most obvious rivals. The Norwegian media have hailed the band's debut album <em>To the</em><em> Treetops</em> as one of the best in Norway.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Team Me plays grandiose indie pop, and the catchy, joyful and majestic songs have international potential. At the same time, the Norwegians have an unmistakable Scandinavian sound as if they shared helium with Mew and Lukestar.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Propeller / import</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="WARM-UP" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/4f54d72e35.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/afd54cb71a.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/team-me/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="173">
<artistName><![CDATA[JØRGEN TELLER & THE EMPTY STAIRS feat. LAZARA]]></artistName>
<country>DK/BEL</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Gloria]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Jul 2012 23:00:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341608400]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341608400]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Chaos-free-rock with a visiting Belgian drummer.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">With two drummers – Tobias R. Kirstein as a regular feature and Belgian Lazara visiting – Jørgen Teller &amp; The Empty Stairs become an experience out of the ordinary.</p>
<p class="bodytext">And with this well-established underground phenomenon, ‘the ordinary’ is already the deepest well of punk rock. Presenting a combination of improvisation and psychedelic energy the guitarist Jørgen Teller, bassist Søren Gorm and the rest of the entourage short-circuit your mind with beautiful noise where the entrance to heaven is sprinkled with rusty nails and tricky pitfalls.    </p>
<p class="bodytext">Jørgen Teller is a Danish Captain Beefheart who is ready to let the willing into his fold.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Rillbar</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/dde4723504.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/a668d8ca3c.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/joergen-teller-the-empty-stairs-feat-lazara/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="174">
<artistName><![CDATA[TER HAAR]]></artistName>
<country>DE</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Pavilion]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Jul 2012 18:00:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341590400]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341590400]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Complex but accessible post-rock.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Berlin's equivalent to Battles, Ter Haar, started out as an instrumental band, which you feel in the musicality and attention to detail in all of the trio’s songs. </p>
<p class="bodytext">The ambition is edgy, complex post-rock that makes you want to dance rather than count time signatures. A difficult balance that Ter Haar achieves on the album <em>Delta</em> where guitarist Philipp Koller makes his debut as a vocalist. </p>
<p class="bodytext">Ter Haar is a treat for both your brain and dancing shoes and proof that challenging music doesn’t need to be without a sense of humor.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Sinnbus / Import</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/a6b31018de.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/89368dbcd1.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/ter-haar/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="175">
<artistName><![CDATA[TERAKAFT]]></artistName>
<country>MALI</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Odeon]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Sun, 08 Jul 2012 14:30:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341750600]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341750600]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[The next big desert blues phenomenon.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Roskilde Festival brought the Sahara desert blues to Europe with Tinariwen who played their first concert outside of Africa here. Now we present Terakaft, another big orchestra from the sandy plains.</p>
<p class="bodytext">The band has previously shared members with Tinariwen, and Terakaft means caravan in the blue people's, the Tuareg, language.</p>
<p class="bodytext">When you hear the music you can almost feel the desert sun burn down on the wrapped-up musicians.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Look forward to some sunshine-saturated Bedouin rock full of thirst, spirituality and shimmering electric guitar sounds.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Harmonia Mundi / import</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/24e4710a8b.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/34e38ea4d1.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/terakaft/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="176">
<artistName><![CDATA[TODAY IS THE DAY]]></artistName>
<country>US</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Odeon]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Thu, 05 Jul 2012 20:00:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341511200]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341511200]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Style-defining mind-fuck metal.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Don't be fooled by the optimistic and 'seize the day'-ish band name. Today Is The Day is a brutal, sonic pummeling, which will leave even the most hardened metalheads with deep scars on their souls and big grins on their faces.</p>
<p class="bodytext">With legend, riff wizard and daredevil Steve Austin at the helm, Today Is The Day is a style-defining and cultish band of the extreme.</p>
<p class="bodytext">With jagged rhythms, metallic brutishness and a geeky attention to detail, these veterans carve their own bloody niche in today's metal scene.</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/1b31678dd6.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/250e427c74.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/today-is-the-day/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="177">
<artistName><![CDATA[THE TODDLA T SOUND]]></artistName>
<country>UK</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Cosmopol]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Sat, 07 Jul 2012 22:30:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341693000]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341693000]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[British-Caribbean dance party with a Sheffield prodigy at the helm.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Sheffield's own Toddla T has DJ’ed longer than he has been able to obtain a driver's licence. Today he is a well-established British DJ act, for instance at the hot London club Fabric and on BBC Radio 1.</p>
<p class="bodytext">With The Toddla T Sound, the prodigy enters the stage. Based on the two albums <em>Skanky Skanky</em> and <em>Watch Me Dance</em>, Toddla T now goes all the way with a show featuring a sonic vortex of dancehall, house, garage and countless other dance genres from both Great Britain and the Caribbean.</p>
<p class="bodytext">The Toddla T Sound is packed with bass, lights and visuals. A calorie-burning session that simply requires you to dance.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Ninja Tune / VME</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/7bbd729b8e.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/4b226850de.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/the-toddla-t-sound/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="178">
<artistName><![CDATA[TOUCHY MOB]]></artistName>
<country>DE</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Gloria]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Jul 2012 21:00:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341601200]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341601200]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Folk with Berliner beats.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">How would Kraftwerk’s robots sound if they grabbed the acoustic guitar? Touchy Mob presents an idea of this scenario.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Despite the band name, this is an austere solo project where the bearded Ludwig Plath with his acoustic guitar, a little electronics and angular time signatures  create a personal sound that alternates between organic warmth and cold electronic dystopia.</p>
<p class="bodytext">With few means Touchy Mob creates his very own &quot;folk techno&quot;. An odd musical variety, which still makes fully sense when experienced live.</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/05b39ac522.png]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/abbe0d18a1.png]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/touchy-mob/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="179">
<artistName><![CDATA[BOUBACAR TRAORÉ]]></artistName>
<country>MALI</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Pavilion]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Jul 2012 16:00:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341583200]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341583200]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Intimate, bittersweet blues.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Having played for over 40 years, Boubacar Traoré (also called Kar Kar, the dribler, in his football-playing youth) makes his Roskilde debut, and not one day too soon. Actually, it's a minor legend whom we can finally welcome at Roskilde Festival.</p>
<p class="bodytext">With a voice that sounds like it has slow-ripened in the sun, Traoré plays the blues with the acoustic guitar as the main accompaniment. Humble and intimate music, often frayed by melancholy.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Don't miss a meeting with a West African veteran whose status in his native country is on par with Ali Farka Touré.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Lusafrica / import</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/8b72c7ce49.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/d8d2ca3cc2.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/boubacar-traore/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="180">
<artistName><![CDATA[TRASH TALK]]></artistName>
<country>US</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Pavilion]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Thu, 05 Jul 2012 21:30:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341516600]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341516600]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Hardcore riots by one of the genre's most talked-about bands.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">You shouldn’t really use too many words to describe a band such as Trash Talk. With this kind of hardcore band, it's all about getting into the eye of the storm and sweat off a few pounds.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Screaming, vocal cord-wrecking voices and aggressive riffs dominate Trash Talk’s ultra short and unmelodious punk songs that often transform band and audience into one giant monster with arms and legs sticking in all directions.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Lead singer Lee Spielman is undoubtedly one of hardcore’s most hardworking front figures. His energy and dedication has already made him semi-mythological in the genre’s circles.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Trash Talk Collective / import</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/91c0ee95a6.png]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/748213bbb1.png]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/trash-talk/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="181">
<artistName><![CDATA[TUNE-YARDS]]></artistName>
<country>US</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Odeon]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Sat, 07 Jul 2012 17:00:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341673200]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341673200]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Schizo-pop with African aftertaste.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Merrill Garbus has thoroughly studied the great cookery book of pop. However, it seems that she has read it backwards and upside down. </p>
<p class="bodytext"><em>WHOKILL</em>, the second album under the moniker tUnE-yArDs, has made the woman with the androgynous African voice the new prodigy of mad pop. A sister-in-spirit of Animal Collective, Björk and Dirty Projectors. </p>
<p class="bodytext">Garbus' music waddles and hobbles charmingly out there, high-fiving East Africa, R&amp;B, hip hop and avant-garde along the way. A kind of sunshine pop for hyperactive, playful people with paint in the face and pumping blood full of glucose. </p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: 4AD / Playground</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/6bd679405f.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/d9ca7c1e27.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/tune-yards/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="182">
<artistName><![CDATA[ULIGE NUMRE]]></artistName>
<country>DK</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Pavilion Junior]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Sun, 01 Jul 2012 19:00:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341162000]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341162000]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Lovesick rock from young Copenhageners.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Ulige Numre has achieved an immediate recognition from the audience, a recognition that many similar bands can only dream of. Their debut single “København” has been the dark month’s soundtrack to many Scandinavians.</p>
<p class="bodytext">The young lads are in their early 20s, but they play lyrical, lovesick Danish-language rock with a confidence and stage presence as if they were an older and more experienced band.</p>
<p class="bodytext">They’re delightful proof that good songwriting is still relevant to a wide audience.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Auditorium / A:larm</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="WARM-UP" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/5a0e98843f.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/6f64bc9561.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/ulige-numre/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="183">
<artistName><![CDATA[THE VACCINES]]></artistName>
<country>UK</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Odeon]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Jul 2012 23:00:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341608400]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341608400]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Essential and energetic rock.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">British band The Vaccines have marched straight into the hearts of both the music press and audience.</p>
<p class="bodytext">The formula behind their music is a tried and tested one, but nonetheless very effective: catchy rock that just about contains the quintessence of every band of quality ever to grace the loudspeakers of any Ramones-poster-decorated teenage room.</p>
<p class="bodytext">The band has in a disarmingly self-ironic manner called their debut album <em>What Did You Expect From The Vaccines?</em> The answer to their question is: great things, judging from the many hits on the album. These Brits are sure to meet the expectations on their follow-up album, due later this year.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Columbia / Sony Music</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/5fb0154376.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/85b91da473.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/the-vaccines/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="184">
<artistName><![CDATA[MAÏA VIDAL]]></artistName>
<country>FR</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Gloria]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Thu, 05 Jul 2012 17:45:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341503100]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341503100]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Accordion-playing Parisienne.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Paris calls for a soundtrack of accordion, glockenspiel and sweet charm.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Maïa Vidal is a worldling with New York, Montreal and Barcelona as her home turfs, but her primarily English-language songs bring about a feeling of the city of lights.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Her music is rich on classic Seine atmosphere. Meanwhile, the singer is not afraid to include a cover of punk idols Rancid whom she has previously paid tribute to on an entire EP.</p>
<p class="bodytext">The well-traveled Parisienne uses accordion, guitar, violin and various toy instuments in her both playful and nostalgic universe.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Crammed Discs / Cosmos Music Group</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/29fad7b4e5.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/5a15ff6bcb.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/maia-vidal/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="185">
<artistName><![CDATA[SOFFIE VIEMOSE]]></artistName>
<country>DK</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Apollo Countdown]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Sun, 01 Jul 2012 17:30:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341156600]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341156600]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Melancholic pop on a bed of playful electronica.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">With academy studies in electronic music as the ballast, Soffie Viemose is about to unfold her name as one of Denmark's most promising acts in semi-experimental electronica.<br /> <br /> The young producer and singer's delicate electronic arrangements contain a creeping sadness. At the same time, the many details show a playful mind at work. With her wistful voice and the evocative lyrics at the centre, here’s a treat for both fans of abstract electronica and melancholic pop.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Polar / Playground<br /></p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="WARM-UP" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/ae572e4dd3.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/f33c51accd.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/soffie-viemose/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="186">
<artistName><![CDATA[VAAGSBYGD HANDY]]></artistName>
<country>N</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Apollo Countdown]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Wed, 04 Jul 2012 19:00:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341421200]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341421200]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Outsider hip hop from the Norwegian province.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Coming from <em>down south</em> – southern Kristiansand, Norway, to be more specific – it can be hard to make yourself heard when producing Norwegian-language, British-inspired grime hip hop.</p>
<p class="bodytext">However, Vaagsbygd Handy has managed to do just so where Norwegian, British and Jamaican currents meet. With an East London edge and a motley array of words, Vaagsbgd Handy shows the way with unruly hip hop full of humour, heavy bass, Caribbean <em>riddims</em> and a well-developed sense of the absurd. </p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="WARM-UP" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/98197c690e.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/1ab4f1005d.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/vaagsbygd-handy/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="187">
<artistName><![CDATA[WAR FOR YOUTH]]></artistName>
<country>DK/S</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Apollo Countdown]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Sun, 01 Jul 2012 16:00:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341151200]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341151200]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Raw, industrial synths.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">The Copenhagen punk scene experiences quite a boost these days with Iceage as the internationally noted figurehead. The scene is still small. Everyone knows each other.</p>
<p class="bodytext">War For Youth is a constellation put together for Roskilde Festival, a cross between War and even-minded Lust For Youth.</p>
<p class="bodytext">The two bands have in common industrial icy synths, effects-drowned vocals and an indefinable sense of something new and dangerous. Raw, nihilistic and misplaced – like only the darkest and strangest alleys in Scandinavia sound right now.</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="WARM-UP" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/76d046276d.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/8550b3d516.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/war-for-youth/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="188">
<artistName><![CDATA[WARBRINGER]]></artistName>
<country>US</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Pavilion]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Sat, 07 Jul 2012 21:30:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341689400]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341689400]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Retro thrash from California.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Thrash metal has enjoyed a renaissance where metal lovers brought into the world several years after Slayer’s Reign in Blood have discovered the genre's potential.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Warbringer belongs to this wave and obviously adore 80s metal elements such as gas-guzzling tempos, long hair and wind-swept guitar solos.</p>
<p class="bodytext">But the Californian band is not just a tribute to bygone times. Hardened by intense touring and sweaty moshpits since 2004, the L.A. thrashers’ brutal songs mutate in new ways – often with a destructive undercurrent of death metal and newer, more progressive tendencies.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Century Media / EMI</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/d40f79ea7c.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/d25520849b.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/warbringer/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="189">
<artistName><![CDATA[DANYEL WARO]]></artistName>
<country>REU</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Gloria]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Jul 2012 17:00:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341586800]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341586800]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[The biggest ambassador of Maloya music.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Réunion lies east of Madagascar in the Indian Ocean. The tiny dot on the map has its own, original music. The ritualistic droning style of Maloya was created by the descendants of black slaves and has a strong appeal to the sense of independence in the islanders.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Despite his partially French origin, Danyel Waro is one of the most outstanding ambassadors of this culture.  The islanders love him as a unique musician, poet, storyteller, freedom fighter and commentator.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Waro's mission is not to make Maloya easily digestible and streamlined for the global audience. He creates a magical presence with this percussion-based music from his native home, which at times can seem to overtake and overwhelm your senses. </p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: L'Autre Distribution / import</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/5a7304de05.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/ffda29f91f.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/danyel-waro/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="190">
<artistName><![CDATA[WEEDEATER]]></artistName>
<country>US</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Odeon]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Jul 2012 12:00:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341568800]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341568800]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Crushing Southern groove.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">In 2012 we’re giving you another dietary supplement from the swampy US Southern states, filled to the brim with toxic heavy metal and questionable types of tobaccos. The initiated call it sludge.</p>
<p class="bodytext">You could also simply describe Weedeater’s sound as a groovy cross between AC/DC and Black Sabbath, played by a group of bong heads with a Dixie flag hanging in the rehearsal room.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Front man &quot;Dixie&quot; Dave and his cronies are without a doubt good-natured Southern folks – the band's first album was called <em>... And Justice For Y'all</em> with a howdy to Metallica's classic. The music, however, is a deadly mixture of fast riffs, whipped drums and growling vocals.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Southern Lord / import</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/55fc1903a5.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/46ee764f7e.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/weedeater/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="191">
<artistName><![CDATA[JACK WHITE]]></artistName>
<country>US</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Orange]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Jul 2012 22:30:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341606600]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341606600]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[One of the most important rock voices and guitarists of the new millennium.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">The White Stripes helped kick-start rock again a little over 10 years ago. With inspiration from particularly blues and garage rock, Jack White showed us all how much magic you can produce with vocals, guitar and a drum rhythm from the missus.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Having expanded his repertoire with the super rock groups The Raconteurs and The Dead Weather, Jack White now takes the stage himself, and the first live shows reveal an artist at the peak of his career. Ready with songs from the new solo album, <em>Blunderbuss</em>, and picks from the rich back catalogue.</p>
<p class="bodytext">With a bigger band, the old songs are given a new wealth and weight. The new songs are potent rock noir, full of more than 50 years of music history.</p>
<p class="bodytext">With Jack White, the reawakening of the classic rock tradition continues.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: XL / Playground</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>1</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/5eea96d18f.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/6f6ec33188.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/jack-white/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="192">
<artistName><![CDATA[LARS WINNERBÄCK]]></artistName>
<country>S</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Odeon]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Sun, 08 Jul 2012 16:30:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341757800]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341757800]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Popular Swedish rock singer.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Sweden's perhaps most popular rock singer nowadays is called Lars Winnerbäck, a sharp observational troubadour with a bulging song catalogue and a huge ecstatic crowd celebrating him as one brightest shining lights of the Swedish songwriting tradition.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Loaded with his poetic lyrics and acoustic guitar, he is in many ways the epitome of the classic folk singer.</p>
<p class="bodytext">However, the Linköping pride is in no way musically stagnant or conservative. On his latest album <em>Tänk om jeg ångrar mig, och sen ångrar mig igen,</em> synthesizers and electric guitars move away from the ballad tradition, which has previously been the popular Swede's domain.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Universal</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>2</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/82a674afc2.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/3b8d2705ae.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/lars-winnerbaeck/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="193">
<artistName><![CDATA[WIZ KHALIFA]]></artistName>
<country>US</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Arena]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Thu, 05 Jul 2012 20:30:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341513000]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341513000]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Laid-back and poppy hip hop.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">You've probably heard &quot;Black and Yellow&quot;, which has been a huge hit on the radio almost everywhere. With this festive and poppy tribute to his local NFL team, Wiz Khalifa went straight for the mainstream heart of the wide audience and gave both Drake and Lil Wayne a fight for their money about being the young generation's biggest hip hop hero. </p>
<p class="bodytext">The tattooed rapper from Pittsburgh is not as new to the game as his birth year (1987) might indicate. In the course of numerous mixtapes and other releases Cameron Jibril Thomaz has expanded his fan base with a persistence, energy and dedication, which also shows during live shows as a true contrast to his cannabis-seasoned and laid-back hip hop. </p>
<p class="bodytext">Atlantic / Warner</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>2</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/519c909342.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/51bd37e7a1.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/wiz-khalifa/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="194">
<artistName><![CDATA[YELAWOLF]]></artistName>
<country>US</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Cosmopol]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[Sun, 08 Jul 2012 15:30:00 +0200]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[1341754200]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[1341754200]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Aggressive southern hip hop.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Alabama has no reputation as a hip hop mecca compared to Los Angeles or Detroit. At least not yet.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Yelawolf is one of the southern state city's new ambassadors and has, despite his skin colour, been the new black for some time in the global hip hop club.</p>
<p class="bodytext">A skinny country boy brought up on Lynyrd Skynyrd, but with an aggressive, vicious and virtuous rap style that places him just as much in the company of Tech N9ne as Eminem.</p>
<p class="bodytext">He is signed to the latter's Shady Records and the comparisons with this pioneer are inevitable.</p>
<p class="bodytext">However, make no mistake of Yelawolf. His music reeks of petrol, crunk, dope and white trash attitude, so you know it is made by a genuine Dixie.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Shady / Universal</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/54c3f8322e.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/d77fb8272b.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[uk/band/singleband/yelawolf/]]></link>
</item>
</bandPreview>