<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<bandPreview startID="">
<interFace buttonLabel="MORE INFO" />
<item id="0">
<artistName><![CDATA[ACTION BRONSON]]></artistName>
<country>US</country>
<scene><![CDATA[]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[New Yorker gourmet hip hop.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">The bearded word juggler Action Bronson has a past as a gourmet chef, but has put palette knife and carving fork aside to devote himself to rap. Too bad for the hungry mouthes in Queens, New York. Good for the international hip hop community.</p>
<p class="bodytext">This immigrant son knows how to serve rap that will draw in all fans of true New Yorker hip hop faster than a lobster bisque reaches the boiling point.</p>
<p class="bodytext">With great confidence, Action Bronson stands on the shoulders of Ghostface Killah and the rest of the Wu-Tang Clan as his rap takes him away from the kitchen and straight onto the hip hop scene.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Vice / import</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/ad52595628.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/c5ac1b4112.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/action-bronson/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="1">
<artistName><![CDATA[AGE COIN]]></artistName>
<country>DK</country>
<scene><![CDATA[]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Steel-grey, paranoid industrial]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Copenhagen’s darkest underground, with the store and label posh isolation as a platform, keeps on producing new crisscrossing constellations within (post) punk and industrial. Age Coin is a duo of members from Lower and Vår, their music describes, according to themselves, what it’s like “when you’re feeling really low in a corner of the club”. With foggy, industrial soundscapes, they create bleak scenarios where the dim techno rhythm is hovering like an abstract threat of annihilation. A massive darkness built from steel and shabby electronics.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Posh Isolation</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/f60b47a9b7.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/b17189612e.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/age-coin/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="2">
<artistName><![CDATA[AIRBOURNE]]></artistName>
<country>AU</country>
<scene><![CDATA[]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[24 carats worth of testosterone rock]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">The Aussie-rockers Airbourne hold the balls of rock music in as firm a grip as their countrymen AC/DC. The soon to be released album <em>Black Dogs Barking</em> is likely to be as chemically cleansed of ballads, bullshit and unnecessary shifting accords as the earlier ones. But great albums are one thing. As always the stage is the only place to experience these guys sing about Jack D, wicked blondes and amber ales. Airbourne plays rock with riffs like bolts of lightning and grinding guitar solos. Look forward to meeting these guys, who obviously had a healthy amount of hops and motor oil mixed into their baby food.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Roadrunner / Warner</p>
<p class="bodytext"> </p>]]></description>
<prioritet>2</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/9d6f6abe61.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/f8228a525f.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/airbourne/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="3">
<artistName><![CDATA[AJUNA]]></artistName>
<country>DK</country>
<scene><![CDATA[]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Nordic metal for black souls]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">For years Ajuna have been hatching and brooding in the cellar depths: In 2013 exciting things are happening for the quintet who have a new EP, <em>Prisoners Of The Sun</em>, due to cast a dark spell during spring. The Copenhagen band plays crushingly chaotic metal with a Nordic touch, finding room for both depressive beauty and marrow-shattering aggression. Black metal and technical hardcore are just some of the genres Ajuna uses in their attempt to set your ears and nerve system on fire. </p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/f60b47a9b7.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/b17189612e.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/ajuna/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="4">
<artistName><![CDATA[ANGEL HAZE]]></artistName>
<country>US</country>
<scene><![CDATA[]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Hard-hitting hip hop amazon.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">“Destruction, sadness, &amp; experiencing what it is to suffer.”</p>
<p class="bodytext">This is how Angel Haze lists her primary sources of inspiration. Yet, her aggressively delivered hip hop is quite an encouraging acquaintance.</p>
<p class="bodytext">The young woman caused a stir with her version of Eminem's &quot;Cleaning Out My Closet&quot; in which she – brutal as a torrential wound – raps about a sexual assault.</p>
<p class="bodytext">But despite her childhood demons, the amazon from Detroit has no intention of throwing in towel nor microphone in the ring. &quot;I run New York,&quot; is the chorus from her signature song. We bet she includes Roskilde when she drops by.</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/779ab0e05b.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/af323173ff.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/angel-haze/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="5">
<artistName><![CDATA[ANIMAL COLLECTIVE]]></artistName>
<country>US</country>
<scene><![CDATA[]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Ecstatic experimental pop.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">The residents of Animal Collective – Avey Tare, Panda Bear, Geologist and Deakin – have pushed pop music into a whole new dimension on a number of deeply curious albums, latest on <em>Centipede Hz</em> from 2012.</p>
<p class="bodytext">The Americans' music – inspired by avant-garde and minimalist art music – sounds like a batch of children high on sugar let loose behind synthesizers, microphones and drums. Playfulness and joy of music in all colors of the rainbow.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Below the turbulent soundtrack a pop heart beats, not unlike that of Beach Boy Brian Wilson's.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Animal Collective is a wild celebration of the potential of music – sparkling with life and alien forms.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Domino / Playground</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>2</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/0966d68314.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/5e4ba3edfc.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/animal-collective-1/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="6">
<artistName><![CDATA[ANAAL NATHRAKH]]></artistName>
<country>UK</country>
<scene><![CDATA[]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Obscene, godless extreme metal
]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">In a black cloud of fear and nausea, the extreme metal duo Anaal Nathrakh attacks everything good, light and beautiful in this world. With elements of black metal, melodious death metal and grindcore, the two Brits blur the edges for where the punishment ends and the relief begins. </p>
<p class="bodytext">When Mick Kenney and David Hunt perform, they are usually backed up by guest performers on stage to match the attack of guitar and guttural growling on their albums. Anaal Natrakh will devour your nerve endings like a drugged up fighter dog.  </p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/af5b410ec6.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/92ab3b3634.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/anaal-nathrakh/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="7">
<artistName><![CDATA[BAAUER]]></artistName>
<country>US</country>
<scene><![CDATA[]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Electronic wiz kid from Brooklyn.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">With its lion roars and insistent bass, &quot;Harlem Shake&quot; is the hottest stuff right now at all the trendsetting clubs.</p>
<p class="bodytext">The artist behind the song calls himself Baauer. He’s one of the exponents of trap, one of the possible successors of dubstep.</p>
<p class="bodytext">As a one-man army onstage, he blends house, southern hip hop and bass music in his own instrumental rehash.</p>
<p class="bodytext">This promising boy wonder confidently steps into a constantly mutating musical arena. Reputable electronic names such as Rustie, Flosstradamus and Diplo have noticed Baauer.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: LuckyMe / Import</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/f4e0f3903f.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/15c2c37b2d.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/baauer/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="8">
<artistName><![CDATA[BABY IN VAIN]]></artistName>
<country>DK</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Pavilion Junior]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Melodious 90’s heavy rock.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="p1">They aren’t old enough to remember the 90s, yet they still manage to take you back to a point in time and a place that feels a lot like smoky backstreet bars in Seattle with sticky floors and no aircon, but a maxed out sound system and Bill Clinton on the flickering telly behind the bar swearing his innocence.</p>
<p class="p1">Baby in Vain have found their inspiration in dragging stoner-rock and grunge, and Benedicte, Lola and Andrea’s songs manage to be a charming mix of rattling and reckless, yet tuneful, harmonies delivered with a 2 finger salute-attitude.</p>
<p class="p1">Baby in Vain is a heavy but loving shot of grungy rock right into your central nervous system.</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/47fdc77ca6.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/d8b74b0437.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/baby-in-vain/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="9">
<artistName><![CDATA[BADUME’S BAND & SELAMNESH ZEMENE]]></artistName>
<country>ET/FR</country>
<scene><![CDATA[]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Funk with Addis Ababa in the blood]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">The 60s and 70s was a very special period in Ethiopian music. In the new millennium music collectors have discovered and distributed this musical treasure of golden funk, jazz, afrobeat and soul. The music of this period in time has a distinct beat, which is not found in James Brown or Fela Kuti. Clearly Badume’s Band is in love with the glory days and though the nine man ensemble consists of Frenchmen they let their saxophones glitter as a backing band for the grand old man of the musical golden age; Mahmoud Ahmed. Led by the Ethiopian singer Selamnsh Zeimene Badume’s Band recreate the Addis Ababa of 1970. Together they embody not just a past but also a future of Ethiopian, urban music.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Innacor / Import</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/725dc6d19c.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/8dcf724787.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/badumes-band-selamnesh-zemene/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="10">
<artistName><![CDATA[AZEALIA BANKS]]></artistName>
<country>US</country>
<scene><![CDATA[]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[The hip-hop queen of the Internet]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">She achieved star status before the world (i.e. the Internet) had even finished listening to a single song from this dirt dropping MC and singer. The EP <em>1991</em> took it’s name from Azealia Banks’ birth year. Soon everybody realised that pure talent was entering the stage through the cloud of hype, beefs and buzz. Azealia Banks departs from hip hop to create her very own regime – commanding other genres of music to kneel before her superior flow, wit and edge. 2013 may be a year even more important than 1991: This year will see the release of Banks’ debut album and she will show Roskilde Festival the stuff she is really made off.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Interscope / Universal</p>
<p class="bodytext"> </p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/07edda7064.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/04de8a4108.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/azealia-banks/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="11">
<artistName><![CDATA[TOMAS BARFOD]]></artistName>
<country>DK</country>
<scene><![CDATA[]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Electronic Jack-Of-All-Trades]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Some best know him as the drummer and producer in WhoMadeWho. But Tomas Barfod is an important figure through his work in Filur, Jatoma and lately the critically acclaimed solo album <em>Salton Sea</em> as well. On the album the Los Angeles-based wiz kid dives into an electronic universe in which house, techno and ambient can be found alongside typical ear candy like ”November Skies”. Tomas Barfod is one of the prides of Denmark’s electronic scene. His diversity and ability to create alien worlds of sound gives him a well-deserved spot on the throne next to Trentemøller.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Friends of Friends</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/aca2bfd41a.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/0153953184.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/tomas-barfod/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="12">
<artistName><![CDATA[NILS BECH]]></artistName>
<country>NO</country>
<scene><![CDATA[]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Decadent Big City pop]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">The Norwegian singer Nils Bech crosses the boundaries between art, compositional music and pop. He sings in a delightfully affected manner with an almost ostentatious Scandinavian accent: Imagine a cross between Antony Hegarty and Jens Lekman and you are not far off. On the album <em>Look Inside</em> Nils Bech has firmly set his classically trained vocals in an impressionistic dream world of baroque, electronic pop, which is artistically ambitious, intricately details and sound like it has been composed among drag queens in glittering satin. Divulge in a trip trip into the decadent, purple maelstrom accompanied by a grandiose, characteristic voice.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Fysisk Format / Import </p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/5a5217272a.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/3dab2873d2.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/nils-bech/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="13">
<artistName><![CDATA[BENDIK]]></artistName>
<country>NO</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Pavilion Junior]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Ice-cold, Scandinavian pop]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="MsoNormal">”Blåsar Vekk” (blowing away), Bendik call one of their tunes. And the title actually fits this band's alternative pop. </p>
<p class="MsoNormal">The three Norwegians hover in the same air space as Mew and fellow Norwegians Lukestar, admiring the view.</p>
<p class="MsoNormal"> Bendik are keen on combining the grandiose with icy harmonies, inducing the sensation of a chilly Northern wind. </p>
<p class="MsoNormal">At the same time, Bendik differ from their Scandinavian contemporaries, applying a more electronic touch. Silje Hastensen’s powerful vocals are mostly surrounded by windswept, frostbitten synths. </p>
<p class="MsoNormal">Label: Riot Factory / Import</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/90d3dfc7d1.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/2b9180e41a.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/bendik/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="14">
<artistName><![CDATA[BINÄRPILOT ]]></artistName>
<country>NO</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Apollo Countdown]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Pixilated dance music]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Its Game Over to uninspired dance music. Binärpilot has moved to next level already. </p>
<p class="bodytext">Web designer Alexander Støvers dedicates his jams to “robots, geeks, hackers, and nerds of this world”, and the Norwegian’s home-produced tunes sound like a steroid-pumped soundtrack to old, flashing computer games of pixilated plumbers saving the world. </p>
<p class="bodytext">The intergalactic space travels of Binärpilot have more laser and meteor showers than 100 superheated console adventures.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Microhertz / Import</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/a40a457995.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/454a7dae94.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/binaerpilot/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="15">
<artistName><![CDATA[BIXIGA 70]]></artistName>
<country>BR</country>
<scene><![CDATA[]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Afrobeat Sao Paolo-style]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Sao Paolos Bixiga 70 lend their name from afrobeat legend Fela Kuti’s backingband Africa 70. No coincidence. This funky collective of no less than 10 Brassilians sure know their way around afrobeat. Furthermore, they throw a host of other Latin American rhythms, tones and traditions into the high waters, making anything possible – especially the horn and percussion are duelling to blow you away if you do not start dancing your way through this light blue flood of funk, cumbia, samba, TBC… A mix of genres full of 70es groove and fire in the loins.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Traquintana/Import</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/0424832278.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/2b2a1d01b5.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/bixiga-70/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="16">
<artistName><![CDATA[BLACK REBEL MOTORCYCLE CLUB]]></artistName>
<country>US</country>
<scene><![CDATA[]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Noisy rock’n’roll in sunglasses and leather jacket]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">”Whatever Happened To My Rock ’n’ Roll”, asked BRMC back in 2001 as they, along with The Strokes and The White Stripes, helped rock music find its spark once again. Seven records later – and now with Danish drummer Leah Shapiro along for the ride – they have become acclaimed rock ambassadors. Their moody songs combine classic Americana with British noise rock in a cloud of fuzz guitars, black exhaust fumes and snarling beat poetry. Time to mount your bike and race along: <em>Specter At The Feast </em>from 2013 finds the band with a tight grip around their beloved rock’n’roll.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Abstract Dragon / Cooperative</p>
<p class="bodytext"> </p>]]></description>
<prioritet>2</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/361506eb1d.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/98c5f2b83c.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/black-rebel-motorcycle-club-1/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="17">
<artistName><![CDATA[JAMES BLAKE ]]></artistName>
<country>UK</country>
<scene><![CDATA[]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Electronic R&B with pounding human heart]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">He inhabits a brand new music universe, James Blake, a remote region where heart pounding soul, folk and R&amp;B share molecules with dubstep, hip hop, ambient and shiny electronica. 24-years-old, he is a major voice in a generation unburdened by genres. James Blake had the Cosmopol stage filled to the brim during his last visit in 2011: This year we provide a bigger stage for unfurling Blake’s latest album, <em>Overgrown</em>. The sophomore album finds the quiet Brit blurring the borders between organic and electronic dimensions even more. </p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: 1-800 Dinosaur / Universal</p>
<p class="bodytext"> </p>]]></description>
<prioritet>2</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/bbab7e84a6.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/8c568ced03.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/james-blake-1/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="18">
<artistName><![CDATA[BLOOD COMMAND]]></artistName>
<country>NO</country>
<scene><![CDATA[]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Melodic post hardcore]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">With a feisty mix of belligerent girl vocals and searing guitar works Blood Command attack and conquer the overall male dominance of post hardcore. The band is not all about the gore, though. They lose the aggression, inspired by bands such as Fugazi, At the Drive-In and Refused, here and there in favour of melodies and pretty minor key guitars. Several places lead singer Silje Tombre and her platoon actually dive voluntarily into the catchy pop chorus. Blood, sugar and bile combined in a perfect Molotov cocktail. </p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Fysisk Format / Import</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/047417f774.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/ad5e9cae46.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/blood-command/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="19">
<artistName><![CDATA[THE BLUE ANGEL LOUNGE]]></artistName>
<country>DE</country>
<scene><![CDATA[]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Midnight blue psych rock]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">They named themselves after the club where German goth queen Nico did her first shows with The Velvet Underground. And the link between teutonic darkness and druggy american rock is obvious on board The Blue Angel Lounge. They sound like a band who wear shades and leather jacket 24-7, their psych rock has the lush fizzle of a pain killer sinking into a glass of water. Anton Newcombe of The Brian Jonestown Massacre is a fan and has toured with the band. If you’ve ever found his music just a little groovy, be sure to take a trip into the noisy bliss of The Blue Angel Lounge as well. </p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/fdc742e8cf.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/050490b3cd.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/the-blue-angel-lounge/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="20">
<artistName><![CDATA[BOMBINO]]></artistName>
<country>NE</country>
<scene><![CDATA[]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Hypnotic desert music]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext"> </p>
<p class="bodytext">”I love the desert”, Bombino says in the film about him. He's part of the desert nomads the Tuaregs whose music and whole way of life were threatened by the Niger and Mali regimes. </p>
<p class="bodytext">The regime took a strong stance against the song and dance of the whole population, and the guitar was seen as an icon of rebellion. But even during exile, Bombino has managed to secure a home through music. </p>
<p class="bodytext">The guitar player with the rock star potential has become an ambassador for peace through other means than violence. His raw and poetic guitar playing is like witnessing a West African Jimi Hendrix shrouded in desert cloths.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Nonesuch / Warner</p>
<p class="bodytext"></p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/1076b83962.jpeg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/fc88f204e0.jpeg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/bombino/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="21">
<artistName><![CDATA[THE BOTS]]></artistName>
<country>US</country>
<scene><![CDATA[]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Punk rock'n'roll duo.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">The brother duo The Bots master punk rock'n'roll, aiming for both the melodies and the carnal groove. As a matter of course, they find an unprecedented point on the colour scheme of retro rock, somewhere in between The White Stripes and The Black Keys.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Mikaiah and Anaiah Lei have fine-tuned their skills on the electric guitar and the drums since childhood – and they released their first album when they were 15 and 12, respectively. That was in 2009.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Today, they exude an almost unnatural authority, both regarding songwriting and stage show. The Bots are fully fledged in an age when most bands are still learning to crawl.</p>
<p class="bodytext"><br /></p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/ee77d40d39.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/6e9b4c5a59.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/the-bots/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="22">
<artistName><![CDATA[BROKE]]></artistName>
<country>DK</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Pavilion Junior]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Apocalyptic, electronic dance punk]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Mads Bergland and Simon Littauer picked the name Broke since they were on rock bottom financially and education-wise. As a picture, even, of their whole crisis-torn generation. Determined to challenge mainstream Denmark, the couple has replaced school books with apocalyptic, battered dance music. The electronic beats are brewed from kraut rock, disco and post punk in a steaming acid bath full of unhealthy fumes. </p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Fake Diamonds</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/cda3a8747f.png]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/a6b0ea6fe0.png]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/broke/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="23">
<artistName><![CDATA[MY BUBBA]]></artistName>
<country>IS/SE</country>
<scene><![CDATA[]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Tongue in cheek lullabies]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">My Bubba describe their songs as lullabies from the countryside. And though many of the catchy tracks have the same wooden colours as for instance First Aid Kit there are more than just forest soil under the feet of the Swede and the Icelander. ”Fuck The Pain Away” by the electro provocateur Peaches is among My Bubba’s favourite tracks to cover. Using acoustic guitar, harp and banjo the two girls deliver concerts full of surprises, humour and delightful, acoustic folk.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Fake Diamond</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/332ca67a55.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/599b4cf2a5.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/my-bubba/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="24">
<artistName><![CDATA[JAKE BUGG]]></artistName>
<country>UK</country>
<scene><![CDATA[]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Folk singer on the rise  ]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="MsoNormal">At almost frightening pace, Jake Bugg has cemented his name with a batch of solid tunes that sound as if they were written by a much older soul.</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">The young fellow has taken the stage as a young Bob Dylan and all the established stars are eager to sing his praise as well. </p>
<p class="MsoNormal">His songs take the best of 60s folk and 90s Brit rock and mould their own melodic blues.</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">Although the sources of inspiration are familiar, Jake Bugg is a refreshing brush of fresh air. Even the most nostalgic types will have to face the fact that classic songwriting is alive and well. </p>
<p class="MsoNormal">Label: Mercury / Universal</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/6071bf02be.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/9ed5e1ab01.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/jake-bugg/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="25">
<artistName><![CDATA[C2C]]></artistName>
<country>FR</country>
<scene><![CDATA[]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Turntable virtuosos.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Vinyl magic and turntables are rarely mentioned without someone also mentioning C2C. The illustrious spin doctors are now ready.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Prepare yourself and your dancing shoes for a turntable concert tightly packed with hip hop, soul, electronica and more genre acrobatics than we can mention before the start of the concert.</p>
<p class="bodytext">In recent years, the four Frenchmen have split up into two successful projects: Hocus Pocus and Beat Torrent have both visited Roskilde earlier.</p>
<p class="bodytext">After getting back together again, C2C have raised the stakes further. Their first proper album ever, <em>Tetra</em>, demonstrates an ambition beyond the DMC DJ team championship, which the four lads have won four times in a row.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: On and On / import</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>2</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/73bb1d3008.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/881895641c.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/c2c/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="26">
<artistName><![CDATA[TEGO CALDERÓN]]></artistName>
<country>PR</country>
<scene><![CDATA[]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[The king of reggaeton]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Reggaeton mixes Spanish rap, salsa, dancehall and other tropical beats. The genre has its origin in the poorest neighbourhoods of Puerto Rico. </p>
<p class="bodytext">Tego Calderón is responsible for boosting the genre among white people and Latinos outside the slum – a lot of people consider the guy with the curly afro haircut and the sunglasses the king of the genre. </p>
<p class="bodytext">We are proud to present Tego Calderón for the first time in Northern Europe. Fans of Latin pop as well as US hip hop are provided with a splendid chance to wriggle their asses together.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Jiggiri / Import</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/20ae9fbfae.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/615d7712a5.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/tego-calderon/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="27">
<artistName><![CDATA[CALEXICO]]></artistName>
<country>US</country>
<scene><![CDATA[]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Alternative country rock with New Orleans flavour]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">American country and Mexican mariachi have been the most important coordinates in Calexico’s across-the-border rock. </p>
<p class="bodytext">Since 1996, John Convertino and Joey Burns have played rustic serenades filled with the smell of gritty highways and scorched tex-mex grill spice for fans of both Bruce Springsteen and spaghetti western composer Ennio Morricone.</p>
<p class="bodytext"> On <em>Algiers </em>from 2012 the two gringos have ventured to the West Coast of Mississippi in motley New Orleans. Here we find traces of Haiti, Cuba and Africa surging in. The new impressions emphasize the notion of Calexico as a charming crossroads suited for very diverse musical orientations.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: On and On / Import </p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/9c4abd2011.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/f7b4a7ccfb.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/calexico-1/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="28">
<artistName><![CDATA[CAPTAIN FUFANU]]></artistName>
<country>IS</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Apollo Countdown]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[The hottest techno-duo in Rykjavik]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Two DJs have made quite an impact on the nightlife of Reykjavik. Captain Fufanu are two young lads playing minimal, deep techno. The duo is working on their debut album right now. Using their first tracks as anything to go by, the duo knows about bangers for the clubbers as well as colder, more atmospheric electronica. </p>
<p class="bodytext">Prepare yourself as the energy boost of Reykjavik hits Roskilde. </p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Reyk Veek / Import</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/10bcac5bba.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/33e5b7bb9c.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/captain-fufanu/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="29">
<artistName><![CDATA[CARLI]]></artistName>
<country>SE</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Apollo Countdown]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Eclectic dj and producer]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">He has crafted beats for Robyn who considers him a worthy exponent for tomorrow’s electronic music scene. Carli Løf is an overwhelmingly talented DJ and producer. The eclectic Swede has built up a CV bulging with transatlantic impact and VIP collaborators. </p>
<p class="bodytext">With a multicoloured clash of bass, rave and hiphop, Carli has been hailed as one of the major shooting stars of 2013. </p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Fool's Gold / Import</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/414740eac2.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/e620503aca.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/carli/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="30">
<artistName><![CDATA[CHELSEA LIGHT MOVING]]></artistName>
<country>US</country>
<scene><![CDATA[]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Noise rock with legendary lead singer]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Vintage hipster Thurston Moore has already changed alternative rock from within as Sonic Youth’s vocalist and guitarist. Even though this band is on hiatus, the ever youthful pioneer has no intention of leaving the stage to the kids. </p>
<p class="bodytext">Instead, Chelsea Light Moving sees a new fresh team taking the stage, keeping up the gritty, searing guitar rock. Chelsea Light Moving is sure to please old fans in worn out Sonic Youth T-shirts. But the new line-up might also lure a new generation into noise, punk and New York City.  </p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Matador Records / Playground</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>2</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/aed7f3d39d.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/bc6e89ba97.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/chelsea-light-moving/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="31">
<artistName><![CDATA[CHINESE MAN]]></artistName>
<country>FR</country>
<scene><![CDATA[]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Turntables galore  ]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Record label, band, musical brotherhood. Chinese Man is a lot of things - don’t expect any Chinese ancestry here, though. With a mashup of funk, house, jazz, reggae and hip hop the French DJ collective makes the party spin from their turntables. </p>
<p class="bodytext">Chinese Man are music lovers with a broad approach to turntablism and a penchant for obscure samples and crackling nostalgia. With visuals and vocalists on top of the versatile beats, you are certain to find a feast for your ears and eyes. </p>
<p class="bodytext">Prepare to twist your behind; 2013 is Year of the Snake in the Chinese calendar. </p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/10edece1fe.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/c55ab0252c.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/chinese-man/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="32">
<artistName><![CDATA[CHORDS]]></artistName>
<country>SE</country>
<scene><![CDATA[]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[R&B-ish, organic hip hop]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">He has pushed things forward on Sweden’s urban music scene. Lately Chords has resided in New York City. On his recent album <em>Looped State of Mind </em>the influence of the American, legendary city is palpable. R&amp;B, hip hop and urban pop are mingled by the hyper talented Swede in a manner that would leave both Drake and Kanye West nodding appreciatively. Despite calling his Brooklyn-produced album a “laptop record”, Chords takes the stage with a large live band, aiming for a thoroughbred concert experience. </p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Svenska Inspelningar / Universal</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/2082d18cab.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/14b9b55b42.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/chords-1/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="33">
<artistName><![CDATA[COMPADRE]]></artistName>
<country>SE</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Apollo Countdown]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Club music with Middle Eastern shade ]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">The night clubs go Middle Eastern when Compadre set fire to the beat and start a musical and absolutely un-bloody Jihad towards the hit lists. With attitude to spare, the trio’s grooves have spread in their native Sweden: Their early songs are a bass-heavy, neon yellow mixture of hip hop, Persian folk music and gritty pop that would make M.I.A. blush with pride.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Vicious Bitch / Import</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/68474f7fee.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/0d27d3c097.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/compadre/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="34">
<artistName><![CDATA[FELIPE CORDEIRO]]></artistName>
<country>BR</country>
<scene><![CDATA[]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Weird pop from Pará]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">He has been called one of Brazil’s most innovative pop artists and the feather light music of Felipe Cordeiro draws heavily on sensual dances like Lambada and Carimbó. However, the songwriter with the well-kept moustache will find more fans among lovers of alternative pop than fans of the 80s hit ”Lambada”. His acclaimed album is called <em>Kitsch Pop Cult</em> and the title encapsulates the nostalgic retro feel this tropical songwriter perfectly conjures up in his songs. Felipe Cordeiro plays stylish, psychedelic pop with a loving, albeit disrespectful, take on the musical traditions of his homeland.</p>
<p class="bodytext"> </p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/3605b2e117.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/8160a4c218.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/felipe-cordeiro/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="35">
<artistName><![CDATA[CRYSTAL CASTLES]]></artistName>
<country>CA</country>
<scene><![CDATA[]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Electro duo with grandiose gloom.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">With an arsenal of old analogue synthesizers, Canadian band Crystal Castles paint beautiful images of a cold world.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Ethan Kath and Alice Glass both come from a background in punk. They inject the energy into their trance-inspired electronica. Glass is in front – one moment angry and shrill, the next fervently sighing.</p>
<p class="bodytext">The band has turned down the shock effects from the early albums – and the latest, III, shows a triumphant greatness in the music.</p>
<p class="bodytext">What is left is a violently beating heart and an insistence that although the world may be relentless, the sound of it can still be beautiful as a snow queen.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Crystal Castles have toured almost non-stop past couple of years. Expect a band in great form hitting Roskilde this summer. </p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Fiction / Universal</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>2</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/e0f13a562f.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/21db3cfb20.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/crystal-castles/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="36">
<artistName><![CDATA[DAEDELUS – ARCHIMEDES SHOW]]></artistName>
<country>US</country>
<scene><![CDATA[]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Twisted electronica in the glow of the mirror ball.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Despite his classic noble gentleman's attire, Daedelus is not a man who prefers order and clean lines in his music.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Sugar-speedy jazz, chipmunk voices, disorienting beats and old, nostalgic sounds are just some of the elements that are reshaped in the American rhythm saboteur’s seemingly radioactive laptop.</p>
<p class="bodytext">To match the music, Daedelus has developed a cool stage show. A wall of mirrors combined with lights and projections create the impression of standing inside a giant mirror ball. This kind of magic cannot be done just anywhere, so we’re proud to present this at Roskilde.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Ninja Tune / VME</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/6b54c3e52e.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/8ac59c8317.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/daedelus-archimedes-show/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="37">
<artistName><![CDATA[DAKHABRAKHA]]></artistName>
<country>UA</country>
<scene><![CDATA[]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Trance-like, ethnic music mayhem.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">In trance-like, long songs, Dakhabrakha creates a self-confessed &quot;ethnic chaos&quot; of sensitive falsetto vocals, accordion, cello, bass-dark jazz and Ukrainian folk music.</p>
<p class="bodytext">The expression is spiritual, melodious and here and there almost a bit scary like the most shadowy corners of a remote bazaar.</p>
<p class="bodytext">The four-piece draws new zigzag lines between the continents – elements of both Indian, Arabic, African, Russian and Australian descent pop up along the way. People missing the American singer Jeff Buckley will also discover an Eastern European cousin in Dakhabrakha’s male singer, Marko Halanevych.</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/31149a1b1a.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/639e70a232.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/dakhabrakha/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="38">
<artistName><![CDATA[DANNY BROWN]]></artistName>
<country>US</country>
<scene><![CDATA[]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Manically eminent Detroit rapper.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">With his half-mad appearance, inimitable rap and eccentric choice of productions, Danny Brown is a much more spectacular acquaintance than the somewhat anonymous artist name suggests.</p>
<p class="bodytext">He has grown up in Detroit, is a self-confessed music geek and has continued the legacy of the cap-clad king of the city J Dilla in the company of Black Milk.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Danny Brown's lyrical universe often revolves around bad medications and the grim conditions of Motor City. His mental condition is not all that bad, however, as he leaves room for plenty of quivering women's thighs and hefty doses of humour.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Look forward to a hefty round in the ring with this dentally challenged rhyme dribbler whose musical backdrop alternates between sugar-coated soul and sparkling electronics.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Fool's Gold / import</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/ca1d2b1026.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/cfe7ab2224.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/danny-brown/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="39">
<artistName><![CDATA[DAWANGGANG]]></artistName>
<country>CN</country>
<scene><![CDATA[]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Folk music from China with a disturbingly western twist]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">The former punk rocker Song Yuhze formed Dawanggang after his travels in western China. The ensemble is rich in insight and ideas and has its musical foundation in the wailing tones of Chinese folk music. Yuhze combines these notes with something uniquely western – and quite disturbing. The narratives as well as the vast expanses of the countryside of the gargantuan nation is present in the music, but the experimenting, almost avant-garde, approach to the traditional sound is an equal mix between Scott Walker and The Beijing Opera.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Jaro / Import</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/58623b6413.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/6d109bb40b.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/dawanggang/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="40">
<artistName><![CDATA[DEAD CAN DANCE]]></artistName>
<country>AU</country>
<scene><![CDATA[]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Black legends of the 80es]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">On the comeback record Anastasis, Dead Can Dance, the black princes of the 80s, break a 16-year-long silence.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Roskilde Festival presents their first Danish concert ever, the only one of its kind in Scandinavia this summer.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Through a fog of chanting vocals, reverb and thick synthesizers, Dead Can Dance calls forth the bewitched sweetness of Arabian nights and the odours and steams of the Far East.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Brendan Perry and Lisa Gerrard chased their distinct, flickering muse back at a time when the ethnic provinces in the music felt way more remote than today. Now that Dead Can Dance are back to cast their spell, they do so as true pioneers. </p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: PIAS / Target</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>2</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/269e225213.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/27a5fcd559.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/dead-can-dance/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="41">
<artistName><![CDATA[DEAD FADER]]></artistName>
<country>UK</country>
<scene><![CDATA[]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Distorted, pitch black electronic music]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">John Cohen belongs in the darkest corner of electronic music, the place where the pop-interpreters of said genre (none mentioned, none forgotten) are in for a good flogging. Dead Fader’s music contains a dystopian, industrial tonality, which makes it sound like something that just might keep gnawing at your soul after you have returned from the festival longing for a good night’s sleep. Using abstract, distorted club music, noise, infernal volume levels, amputated sound bites and unveiled ugliness Dead Fader creates an energetic, electronic nightmare. Have a recess from the harmonies and choruses of the world.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Small But Hard / Import</p>
<p class="bodytext"> </p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/1ce94829c2.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/9bcd4489e4.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/dead-fader/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="42">
<artistName><![CDATA[DEAD RAT ORCHESTRA]]></artistName>
<country>UK</country>
<scene><![CDATA[]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Mystical and improvising folk trio]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Dead Rat Orchestra has been one of England’s most weird and innovative orchestras for a decade. Their colourful playground of instruments typically includes violin, accordion and a variety of guitars. But often the also employ wooden logs, axes, balloons, toys and what ever else is at hand. Despite the choice of instruments they continue to traverse the boundaries of genre without taking permanent residence anywhere in particular. Dead Rat Orchestra plays instrumental, semi-improvisational folk music, which here and there resemble an acoustic variant of the tour companions Godspeed You! Black Emperor.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Antigen / Import</p>
<p class="bodytext"> </p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/e36d27a4db.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/7627267155.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/dead-rat-orchestra/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="43">
<artistName><![CDATA[THE DILLINGER ESCAPE PLAN]]></artistName>
<country>US</country>
<scene><![CDATA[]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Challenging ultra-musical hardcore]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Hardcore, mathcore, metal, progressive rock. A myriad of genre labels have been glued to The Dillinger Escape Plan through their - soon - six sheets long career. </p>
<p class="bodytext">The quartet from New Jersey made their name with extreme metal that not only is raging, screaming and brutal, but also jazz virtuoso-like and filled with surprising genre detours. </p>
<p class="bodytext">Their live shows are chaotic and violent bursts of energy, where the complexities occasionally explode in a ferocity that has made the band's concerts legendary and infamous. The Dillinger Escape Plan has the same half perverse delight in breaking the rules, which also characterizes their friend and former business partner Mike Patton.</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/b4787e56c6.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/bbbfddfa1c.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/the-dillinger-escape-plan-1/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="44">
<artistName><![CDATA[DISCLOSURE]]></artistName>
<country>UK</country>
<scene><![CDATA[]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Electronic house duo with an ear for hits.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Two young brothers are climbing towards the top of the British electronic scene right now. They operate under the name Disclosure, and on their first single release they have paved the way for the future of pop, house and dubstep.</p>
<p class="bodytext">It's chic, urban and touches upon several hot spots on the electronic genre map. If you want to see what tomorrow brings you should definitely check out Disclosure.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Guy and Howard Lawrence's debut album doesn’t come out until the spring of 2013. Nevertheless, they have already been close to the UK top 10 with the pop song &quot;Latch&quot;.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: PMR / import</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>2</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/8f6743db54.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/d739f5934a.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/disclosure/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="45">
<artistName><![CDATA[DRÅPE]]></artistName>
<country>NO</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Pavilion Junior]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Roaring noise pop]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="MsoNormal">Norwegians know how to do shoegazing just right – roaring, dreamy guitar noise with yearning angelic vocals hovering on top. </p>
<p class="MsoNormal">Dråpe’s first EP is full of noise pop taking off on pink clouds for the upper part of the atmosphere. </p>
<p class="MsoNormal">In an interview, vocalist Hanne Olsen Solem recently expressed her hopes and dreams of playing Roskilde Festival and releasing an album. </p>
<p class="MsoNormal">2013 finds both dreams coming true. Their debut album – more pop and less noise, according to the band – is expected out when the Norwegians take our Pavilion Junior stage.</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">Label: Riot Factory </p>
<p class="MsoNormal"> </p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/0142a81d6e.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/e878fce20a.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/draape/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="46">
<artistName><![CDATA[DUBIOZA KOLEKTIV]]></artistName>
<country>BA</country>
<scene><![CDATA[]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Hard hitting Balkan rock collective ]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Ska, Balkan sounds, hip hop, rock, reggae, funk metal. Dubioza Kolektiv get around the genres in a manner comparable to their hectic tour schedule all over Europe. On first sight they may look like your imagined Balkan brutes. But Dubioza Kolektiv, if any, have fought the stereotypes as well as corruption, battling at the fronts in favor of peace and democracy. In many respects, be they political or musical, Dubioza Kolektiv could be considered an East European, brassy Rage Against The Machine, ready to shred the Roskilde night in pieces. </p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Menart / Import</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/f4399d22d0.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/3d9e97679a.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/dubioza-kolektiv/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="47">
<artistName><![CDATA[EFTERKLANG]]></artistName>
<country>DK</country>
<scene><![CDATA[]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Grandiose chamber pop ]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext"></p>
<p class="bodytext">Is it possible to become an audience favourite, making beautiful compositional music with high ceilings? If you’re Efterklang, it is. They have made audience members all over the world hold their breath back, playing fragile chamber pop with strong nuances and colours. And after Casper Clausen established himself as a lead singer, the solemn music has started to resemble the late works of Talk Talk.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Efterklang has signed with legendary 4AD. The trio from the small island of Als makes its fourth visit as an internationally acclaimed band despite the Danish-sounding band name, meaning reverberation. <br /> </p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: 4AD / Rumraket</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>2</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/7f079bcfbf.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/4f366a2c5d.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/efterklang-3/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="48">
<artistName><![CDATA[EIK]]></artistName>
<country>NO</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Apollo Countdown]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Atmospheric pop full of dreamy synthesizers  ]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Norwegian act Eik specialises in 80s-tinted nostalgia and colour-saturated soundscapes full of disco and synth pop. The duo, which turns into a quartet on stage, creates dreamy electronica full of gentle synths and wonderful minor tones with impressive ease. </p>
<p class="bodytext">Eik is a must-see for both electronica geeks and pop lovers who have worn out their copy of Best of the 80s.  </p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Planet Noise / VME</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/15fd87d817.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/1162f0ae8a.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/eik/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="49">
<artistName><![CDATA[EKKOZONE performs MUSIC FOR 18 MUSICIANS ]]></artistName>
<country>DK</country>
<scene><![CDATA[]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Minimalistic masterpiece performed by Danish ensemble]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Steve Reich’s kaleidoscopic masterpiece <em>Music for 18 Musicians</em> has only been performed on Danish soil once before. The dizzying and spherical minimalism of the concerto is a hit with music listeners of very different tastes but it is considered one of the composer’s most difficult pieces to play. Ekkozone has performed modern compositions under various monikers in both Europe and the USA before. Experience their interpretation of a piece by a trendsetting artist, whose influence has reached the post rock and experimenting electronica of our time as well.</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/d6be286aa3.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/04b591d517.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/ekkozone-performs-music-for-18-musicians/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="50">
<artistName><![CDATA[EL-P ]]></artistName>
<country>US</country>
<scene><![CDATA[]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Hip hop king of the underground]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">He rewrote the blueprint of alternativ hip hop in the 90s and 00s along with Company Flow, as a solo rapper and as a head of Def Jux. Today El-P enjoys regal status among those who favour and regard hip hop as a progressive art. His text universe is ignited by political anger, discontent and paranoia. We also cherish the verbose doomsayer for his productions, filled to the brim with dirt, grit, coldness and laser lights from the future. El-P has returned from hibernation with the roaring comeback record <em>Cancer 4 Cure</em>.  </p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Fat Possum / Cosmos Music</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/ff3ada6fde.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/cdd6421bb1.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/el-p-1/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="51">
<artistName><![CDATA[ELLIPHANT]]></artistName>
<country>SE</country>
<scene><![CDATA[]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Edgy, dirty dance floor queen]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Somewhere on the pink Richter scale between M.I.A. and Rihanna we find Elliphant. During no time Ellinor Olovsdotter has made a variety of media want to know more. Her pungent pop is dirt and rubs its shabby, synthetic beats in the face of its happy victim. A talented dance floor queen’s personal mixture of dancehall, techno and pop, inspired by trips to London and Goa. </p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/b630998361.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/d85d7fa813.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/elliphant/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="52">
<artistName><![CDATA[ELOQ]]></artistName>
<country>DK</country>
<scene><![CDATA[]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Gritty beats from one of the leaders of the hip-hop underground in Copenhagen]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Copenhagen’s answer to J Dilla has returned to Roskilde Festival to make some more noise – this time with a new album in the bag and international interest on the rise. Do musical genre monikers like trap, wonky and crunk give you clammy palms and tics around the eyes? No worries. Eloq can make even the uninitiated move their sneakers with his bubbly jacuzzi-mix of bass, gritty beats and high-pitched synthesizers. This venomous neon cocktail has made Eloq a leader figure in Copenhagen’s hip-hop scene as well as a beloved producer, dj and remixer.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Cheff</p>
<p class="bodytext"> </p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/e6c5499f9b.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/3b8884e1c6.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/eloq-1/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="53">
<artistName><![CDATA[ENSIFERUM ]]></artistName>
<country>FI</country>
<scene><![CDATA[]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Epic sword metal with blasting melodies]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Thor, Odin and Loke are shaking their curls somewhere in mighty Valhalla each time Ensiferum take the stage. The melodic Finns are one of the sharpest names of folk-oriented metal. Ancient Northern fire is blazing from the reactors when Ensiferum combine the rhythms and minor scales of folk dance with blasting choruses, bombast and plenty of fiery metal riffing. With 2012’s <em>Unsung Heroes</em>, Ensiferum have carved the writing on the wall in durable runes: They are true heroes of epic sword metal.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Spinefarm / Universal</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/530243da73.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/5db4da26af.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/ensiferum/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="54">
<artistName><![CDATA[FRANK FAIRFIELD]]></artistName>
<country>US</country>
<scene><![CDATA[]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Thoroughly rustic Americana]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p style="font-weight: bold;" class="bodytext">He is in his 20s, not from the 20s. Still, Frank Fairfield sounds like a poetic yokel from between the two Great Wars. </p>
<p class="bodytext">The young songwriter and music archaeologist lived more or less like a bum in California, but he was discovered by those able to recognize his potential. Today, he supports Fleet Foxes on tour and puts out acclaimed records of heart break, whiskey, poverty and impending collapse. The young gentleman garnishes his rustic Americana with plenty of banjo and potent violin.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Tompkin Square / Import</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/352984ae01.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/6cc8ff7f9b.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/frank-fairfield/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="55">
<artistName><![CDATA[FIDLAR]]></artistName>
<country>US</country>
<scene><![CDATA[]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Beer guzzling surf punk rock]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Beer, P**** and Punk music, anyone? FIDLAR is an acronym for Fuck It Dog, Life’s A Risk and their straightforward summer surf punk fits the skater attitude perfectly. Seize the day by its balls. It’s here and now. Jay Reatard and Joey Ramone aren’t here anymore; it is up to us now. The four potheads play no nonsense songs about cheap beers, skateboards and drugs. FIDLAR does not require a graduation diploma or a driver’s license as long as you are ready for a bunch of dirty, Californian Rock ’n’ Roll.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Mom + Pop/ Cooperative</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/d05bc0736c.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/a24b60b995.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/fidlar/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="56">
<artistName><![CDATA[FLATBUSH ZOMBIES]]></artistName>
<country>US</country>
<scene><![CDATA[]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Stoned horrorcore hip hop.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">It’s almost like Night of the Living Dead at Roskilde Festival.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Behind the name Flatbush Zombies you find a couple of creative potheads from the crimed-ridden area near Prospect Heights in Brooklyn. The gold teeth belong to Meechy Darko and Zombie Juice whose rap is based on four classic hip hop subjects: smoke, money, ladies and freshly baked waffles. Erick Arc Elliot produces the un-dead duo who has also rapped alongside A$AP Rocky.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Flatbush Zombies deliver philosophical horrorcore with a stoned twist: if <em>D.R.UG.S. </em>sounds like an uninspired title for a mixtape, please note that the title is an abbreviation of Death and Reincarnation Under God's Supervision.</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/971dfbcbc3.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/46956fd00d.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/flatbush-zombies/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="57">
<artistName><![CDATA[FLUME]]></artistName>
<country>AU</country>
<scene><![CDATA[]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Fragmented electronic chill-out]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Flume has made music since he was 13 years old. That is less than 10 years ago. Still this Australian talent sounds ready to sneak in between Flying Lotus and James Blake to name but a few examples. The producer and beat designer creates his own twisted and looping mix of edgy beats and dreamy, summer lazy music, which in its slow rhythms simultaneously contains electronic echoes of R&amp;B, dub step and pop. The otherwise rock oriented magazine Rolling Stone are among the fans of Flume. Show up and discover how the young Australian creates electronic music, which resonates beyond the confines of the genre.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Future Classic / Import</p>
<p class="bodytext"> </p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/18f1523f89.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/133b26ed66.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/flume/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="58">
<artistName><![CDATA[FRIENDLY BEASTLY COYOTE ]]></artistName>
<country>DK</country>
<scene><![CDATA[]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Moon-howling rave]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">The wolves have returned to the Danish peninsula of Jutland (true story). Friendly Beastly Coyote, too, yowls loud enough from his home in distant, Jutlandic Nykøbing Mors for the urban audience in Copenhagen to take notice. His electronic tracks were nominated for Underground Music Awards in 2012. At Roskilde Festival 2013, Friendly Beastly Coyote is sure to induce a rave that will have the wolves howling further in unison.  </p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/4630307aad.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/729c81898f.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/friendly-beastly-coyote/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="59">
<artistName><![CDATA[GEOMUNGO FACTORY]]></artistName>
<country>KR</country>
<scene><![CDATA[]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Groovy sitar music with ancient origins]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">”You can’t make innovations, if you don’t know the tradition”, says one of the members of Geomungo Factory. The quartet has a mission: To introduce the world to the string music of South Korea as played on the massive sitar instruments of that nation, which are strummed using a small stick of bamboo. The instruments, which are called Geomungo, date as far back as the 4th century. But there is a distinctly modern sound to the alien notes. The music is groovy and full of playful rhythms and the four Koreans play like a well-oiled clockwork. Geomungo Factory use both pedals and amplifiers on the old instruments to extract new nuances and surprising breakthroughs.</p>
<p class="bodytext"> </p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/26fc66271d.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/a084c8dbfa.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/geomungo-factory/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="60">
<artistName><![CDATA[GNUCCI]]></artistName>
<country>SE</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Apollo Countdown]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Edgy girl rapper with global outlook]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Swedish-born, self-proclaimed pussy-power rapper Gnucci finally takes the stage on her own, having served under the flags of prior Roskilde acts such as Spoek Mathambo, Mash Up International and Schlachthofbronx. </p>
<p class="bodytext">Her in-your-face and globally inspired rap has been through a small name change. After abandoning her artist surname Banana, it seems there is no peel left to slip in and that the time has come for us to get to know the gifted brunette entirely on her own terms.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Famalam / Sony Music</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/cf6455d644.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/51d9c5fed9.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/gnucci/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="61">
<artistName><![CDATA[GO GO BERLIN]]></artistName>
<country>SE</country>
<scene><![CDATA[]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Strong party rock]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">”Denmark’s strongest live act.” Thus Go Go Berlin dub themselves and from early on it has been clear that they posses more than mere self-confidence. The party rock unit have toured with bands such as the like-minded The Blue Van and during no time, Go Go Berlin have gathered a loyal fan base all over Denmark. This is classic rock’n’roll played with energy, nerve and lust for life. They make the crowds enthused with classic rock skills and are not about to compromise their ascent anytime soon, the debut album will be recorded in London. </p>
<p class="bodytext"> </p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/652f764c4e.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/c7f64b6d3f.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/go-go-berlin/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="62">
<artistName><![CDATA[GOAT]]></artistName>
<country>SE</country>
<scene><![CDATA[]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Funky trance rock with an African flavour.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext"><em>World Music</em> is the title of Goat’s much-hyped and critically acclaimed debut album from 2012. And the title is a clear indication of what you can expect from this masked, mysterious giant orchestra.</p>
<p class="bodytext">The Swedes play psychedelic rock that sounds as if it were cooked in equal parts bong water, Swedish wild strawberries and African extracts.</p>
<p class="bodytext">With electric guitar, accordion, organ and a well-developed sense of funk and trance, Goat invites us on a wild ride towards a gaudy parallel world. A magical place filled with bright colours, where musical genres have evaporated, and hips just keep on wiggling.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Take the goat by the horns and dance.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Stranded / import</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/ee9dc3987f.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/80b79a4d49.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/goat/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="63">
<artistName><![CDATA[GOATWHORE]]></artistName>
<country>US</country>
<scene><![CDATA[]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Rotten, eclipsed thrash]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">The foaming swamps of Louisiana have created few beasts as rotten and hideous as Goatwhore. The 15-year-old quartet’s fifth album is called <em>Blood for the Master</em>. Without too many detours or errands, the record demonstrates the mastery Goatwhore have developed, during a career of intensive touring making Bob Dylan’s Never Ending Tour look like a stroll with his guitar around the local pub. Goatwhore kick ass in a hostile mix with black, death and thrash ingredients: For these Southern boys it’s just good, ol’ heavy metal at the end of the day. Watch out for this goat, people, it has foam around its mouth and bloody murder in its eyes. </p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Metal Blade/Target</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/53d6299dbd.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/7474a93d60.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/goatwhore/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="64">
<artistName><![CDATA[JOHN GRANT]]></artistName>
<country>US</country>
<scene><![CDATA[]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Brutally heartbreaking songs with an electronic touch]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">John Grant guested Roskilde Festival 2011 in the wake of his breakthrough album, <em>Queen of Denmark</em>, treating his audience with intimate piano version of his 70’es-esque ballads. On his new album <em>Pale Green Ghosts</em> this brutally honest bohemian has directed his gaze at the 80es and electronic music without abandoning his brutally heartbreaking song craft. The former lead singer of long-overlooked The Czars enjoys an uplifting momentum these days, making him a likely candidate to a larger stage this time around. </p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Bella Union / Cooperative</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/085833c26f.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/f7bf648a18.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/john-grant-1/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="65">
<artistName><![CDATA[LAUREL HALO]]></artistName>
<country>US</country>
<scene><![CDATA[]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Dystopian dance music with pitfalls ]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext"><em>Quarantine</em>, Laurel Halo’s breakthrough, is a work with enough pitfalls, loops and textures to become record of the year with the musical gourmets at The Wire magazine. On this album, she abducted dance music and took it somewhere altogether new. When Laurel Halo takes the stage, she does so with a more pumping show. Here you recognise the Brooklyn producer’s techno and dance foundation more strongly. At the same time, her set is sure to reveal her flair for experimentation and claustrophobia. </p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Hyperdub / Import</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/d34ed8a594.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/b1d278c25e.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/laurel-halo/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="66">
<artistName><![CDATA[HATEBREED]]></artistName>
<country>US</country>
<scene><![CDATA[]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Metallic hardcore punk]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Since 1994 they have made mosh pits everywhere red-hot. Hatebreed visit Roskilde Festival for the first time since 2004.</p>
<p class="bodytext">The Americans breed their own monster with balls of steel, iron gills and fiery eyes. ‘Celtic Frost hardcore’ front man Jamey Jasta dubs the genre, conveying a mix of thrash and hardcore sure to make any healthy lad or lady ready to romp. </p>
<p class="bodytext">Hatebreed have just released a new album, The Divinity of Purpose - featuring, according to the quotable singer, “all pit, no shit”. We'll let them prove this at Roskilde, consider yourself invited as well. </p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Sony Music / Nuclear Blast</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>2</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/b27c6c17e3.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/bceb22043c.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/hatebreed-1/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="67">
<artistName><![CDATA[THE HELIOCENTRICS]]></artistName>
<country>UK</country>
<scene><![CDATA[]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Psychedelic jazz funk collective from the far reaches of the Milky Way]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext"><em>13 Degrees of Reality</em> - the latest album by The Heliocentrics – draws on music from more than 13 different places. The psychedelic funk collective mixes Latin American, African, German and British sources of inspiration – from Miles Davis to James Brown. And that leaves out the inspiration from the rest of the Milky Way: The Heliocentrics obviously share their enthusiasm for outer space with jazz legend and main source of inspiration Sun Ra. The Heliocentrics travel – partially improvising – into a glowing constellation of genre, thumping bass, beats and syncope; a dimension full of blinking colours and dissolved consciousness.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Now-Again / Import</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/5fbe8a4510.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/3cd595de19.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/the-heliocentrics/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="68">
<artistName><![CDATA[HIGHASAKITE]]></artistName>
<country>NO</country>
<scene><![CDATA[]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Alternative pop in full war paint.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">With thumbs up from Pitchfork, Bon Iver and a devoted Norwegian music press, Highasakite is ready to become the new major Nordic music act.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Their alternative pop is filled with hit potential and catchy melodies. &quot;Indian Summer&quot; has already spread its heavy-hearted sweetness on the radio. The song is almost a signature song for the Norwegians who like to play concert wearing Indian outfits.</p>
<p class="bodytext">with her characteristic sitar in front, Ingrid Helene Håvik is a Nordic star both as a vocalist and a front woman.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Highasakite has the right mix of sugar and acid in their music to rise far up towards the sky.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Riot Factory / EMI</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/dae837d328.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/faf0a314eb.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/highasakite/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="69">
<artistName><![CDATA[CHRISTIAN HJELM ]]></artistName>
<country>DK</country>
<scene><![CDATA[]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Effortless pop in Danish]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">The bright voice of Danish alt rockers Figurines is breaking new ground. On <em>Før Vi Blev Lette </em>Christian Hjelm sings in Danish and writes catchy songs with the same ease as he creates crooked guitar rock with his more internationally oriented band. The debut album is full of effortless pop tunes and has both won him new fans as well as calmed the old ones. Christian Hjelm has bravely chosen to travel down a different route. He already deserves to be mentioned alongside other Danish song writers such as Nikolaj Nørlund, Peter Sommer and Jens Unmack.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Playground</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/1f19e87f83.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/549df52173.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/christian-hjelm/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="70">
<artistName><![CDATA[HOBA HOBA SPIRIT]]></artistName>
<country>MA</country>
<scene><![CDATA[]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Marock’n’roll]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext"> </p>
<p class="bodytext">Marock’n’roll. That's the title of their collection of greatest hits. And it sums up Hoba Hoba Spirit quite well. With journalist and social critic Reda Allali in front, the band has been part of a minor Moroccan music revolution. </p>
<p class="bodytext">Since the band switched on the amplifiers in the late 90s, they have combined rock and the tones of ancient Morocco in a way that has practic allyturned them into a national treasure.</p>
<p class="bodytext">The fearless music collective combine traces of The Clash, Bob Marley and North African gnawa rhythms in their own melodic and accessible music. With its criticism of modern society, Hoba Hoba Spirit could serve as the perfect soundtrack to the Arab Spring.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Hot Lunch / Import</p>
<p class="bodytext"></p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/71c635ffca.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/2f33633c92.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/hoba-hoba-spirit/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="71">
<artistName><![CDATA[HOLY OTHER]]></artistName>
<country>UK</country>
<scene><![CDATA[]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Dark, atmospheric electronica.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">House, moody R&amp;B and British dubstep are just some of the elements in Holy Other’s darkened sound that has placed him under the genre banner witch house.</p>
<p class="bodytext">With copy-pasted ghostlike vocals, clicking rimshots and keyboards in minor, the critically-acclaimed British producer paints a picture of a quiet, slow sunrise over the hometown of Manchester.</p>
<p class="bodytext">But in the middle of the semidarkness and the grey-blue tones, Holy Other also presents a beauty – a perfect soundtrack for silent, euphoric walks in empty streets at night.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Tri Angle / import</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/36a9fec930.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/7a40e4d287.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/holy-other/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="72">
<artistName><![CDATA[ICE CREAM CATHEDRAL]]></artistName>
<country>DK</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Pavilion Junior]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Otherworldly dream pop]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">With a great ear for golden melodies, Ice Cream Cathedral move self-assuredly in the air-thin part of the atmosphere. On their first album<em> The Drowsy Kingdom </em>the Copenhagen trio has found their own niche between synthesizers, nostalgic retro pop and warm streams of new age, drawing an independent line like the vapor trail from an  aeroplane on a clear blue sky. Anja T. Lahrman’s crystal clear vocals secure the human presence in a music electrically charged with sadness and dream.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Oh! My</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/ed245a9138.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/a8907f73ac.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/ice-cream-cathedral/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="73">
<artistName><![CDATA[ICEAGE]]></artistName>
<country>DK</country>
<scene><![CDATA[]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Nihilistic post punk]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">With pure punk attitude and powerful live shows Iceage have become the first row of &quot;new way of Danish fuck you” while enjoying considerable international interest. Their second album, <em>You’re Nothing</em>, proves their nihilism and pessimism to be fully intact. At the same time they have increased not only the icy coldness but also the experiments in their tamed explosion of (post) punk and hardcore. Their despairing mayhem pounds and scorns against everything, everybody, all of it, in an aggressive ice storm. Iceage are certainly angry and full of young disillusion, yet also possess a certain charming devil-may-care that only true talents get away with.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Escho</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/91b2d7cb9e.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/5adc5c3c20.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/iceage-2/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="74">
<artistName><![CDATA[INDIANS]]></artistName>
<country>DK</country>
<scene><![CDATA[]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Psychedelic pop in wide screen
]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">When the light singing voice of Indians was announced for Roskilde Festival 2012, this new project was shrouded in secrecy. In 2013 things look very different.</p>
<p class="bodytext">The solo project of Søren Løkke Juul is now an international success signed with iconic record label 4AD. Influential music media such as NME and Pitchfork praise the Dane’s debut record Somewhere Else.</p>
<p class="bodytext">With a broad palette, the versatile musician creates weightless pop, combining acoustic folk with psychedelic electronica and atmospheric soundscapes.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: 4AD / Playground</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/6e32c5fc32.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/ec2c3a20f2.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/indians-3/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="75">
<artistName><![CDATA[INGRID feat. LYKKE LI, PETER BJORN AND JOHN, MIIKE SNOW, COCO, J. ÅHLUND and GUESTS]]></artistName>
<country>INT</country>
<scene><![CDATA[]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Illustrious pop collective]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Over loads of black coffe, an impressive sample of Sweden’s most successful pop acts decided to take music matters in their own hands. The label and collective Ingrid became the result. And although Lykke Li, Peter Bjorn And John, Miike Snow, American sidekick Coco and J. Åhlund certainly deliver on their own they have unfurled an umbrella together allowing new ideas, songs and whims to blossom. So far, Ingrid have only made highly selected club shows. For Roskilde Festival they are creating an unique music event, packed with surprises and visual delights. The line-up will take the stage as one large band and treat us with both fresh compositions and well-known hits served in new ways. </p>]]></description>
<prioritet>2</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/003107b44f.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/efe7379305.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/ingrid-feat-lykke-li-peter-bjorn-and-john-miike-snow-coco-j-aahlund-and-guests/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="76">
<artistName><![CDATA[JAM CITY]]></artistName>
<country>UK</country>
<scene><![CDATA[]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Futuristic, violent nightclub music.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Do robots and androids go to nightclubs sometime in the future? If they do, they might dance, sweat petrol and kiss each other to music reminiscent of Jam City.</p>
<p class="bodytext">With the debut album <em>Classical Curves,</em> the young London producer Jack Latham has created a piece of electronic futurism. Filled with zigzagging melody samples, distorted forms and shattered glass. Somewhere inside the shining chrome you find a wreckage of soul, house, techno and pop.</p>
<p class="bodytext">But Latham reinvents, mutates and transforms it all as if Gyro Gearloose were let loose behind a mixing console. Get ready to dance as if it were 2099.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Night Slugs / import</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/6d0e68bbb2.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/f89d9c8e49.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/jam-city/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="77">
<artistName><![CDATA[JOEY BADA$$]]></artistName>
<country>US</country>
<scene><![CDATA[]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Young hip hop hope from Brooklyn.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">He is very young, has only just celebrated his 18th birthday. But Joey Bada$$ is a New York rapper on fire.</p>
<p class="bodytext">He is part of Pro Era, a young group of hip hoppers who seems to have a well-developed love for A Tribe Called Quest, Nas and Wu-Tang Clan.</p>
<p class="bodytext">This crew may be New York's equivalent of Los Angeles' Odd Future, and Joey Bada$$ is one of the Brooklyn collective's most noted members. Please welcome one of the fresh voices.</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/e755d5c213.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/9e15cdfe55.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/joey-bada/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="78">
<artistName><![CDATA[KADIE ELDER]]></artistName>
<country>DK</country>
<scene><![CDATA[]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Elegant, electronic pop]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Anders Rask, front man and singer of Kadie Elder, has a background in folk music, but Kadie Elder finds the young Dane’s bursting with electricity and crackling power. This is clear on the band’s first single “Widen Rift”, introducing an electronic pop full of lush production and ingenious detail. Join Kadie Elder from the very beginning. </p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: 20Thirteen</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/677cd39b15.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/90e427f6f0.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/kadie-elder/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="79">
<artistName><![CDATA[KAKA]]></artistName>
<country>DK</country>
<scene><![CDATA[]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[The rising star of Danish dancehall]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Danish dancehall is undergoing a boost of Babylonian proportions. Please welcome the genre’s rising star: Kaka. His flow mood has placed him squarely in the centre of the rasta-coloured map of Denmark. Songs like ”Dansk Dancehall” has placed Kaka in the front lines ready to make summer smiles and funky dance moves appear everywhere. With Kaka at the helm the genre looks set for a long life of Jamaican riddims and real Copenhagenesque one-liners.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Donkey Recs</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/6d5e749073.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/a60a5e487f.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/kaka/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="80">
<artistName><![CDATA[KARPE DIEM]]></artistName>
<country>NO</country>
<scene><![CDATA[]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Hip Hop with loads of humour and humanism]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="MsoNormal">A Hindu and a Muslim, Chirag Patel and Magdi Ytreeide, two very untraditional Norwegians of different heritage than European have really seized the day. Karpe Diem are more or less national heros, in the eyes of all who wish for a tolerant and benevolent Norway. The two guys play festive pop and straight forward hip hop with Nordic phrases and sympathetic views combined with large amounts of humour. The duo has produced a long line of hit singles like it was oil from the underground. Even on stage these two guys are already a kind of veterans despite the fact that they are only around 30 years old. </p>
<p class="MsoNormal">Label: Sony Music Norway / Import</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/7feebd4844.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/07e70eb5b4.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/karpe-diem/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="81">
<artistName><![CDATA[MARIE KEY]]></artistName>
<country>DK</country>
<scene><![CDATA[]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Airy, Danish-language pop from a sharp pen.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">With the tongue in her cheek and a dose of genuine poetry mixed in her pen, Marie Key has established herself as one of the most original songwriters and lyricists in Denmark. On stage she also knows how to balance tears and laughter on a knife-edge.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Her first albums had a predominantly acoustic expression. On the last two albums, she has developed a more electronic sound that has catapulted the curly head towards the pink universe of pop and the radio.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Marie Key is a refreshing and different acquaintance. Both when she dives into simple and heavy themes.</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">Label: Sony Music</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/1cb316d56a.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/c378053de8.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/marie-key/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="82">
<artistName><![CDATA[KID KOALA]]></artistName>
<country>CA</country>
<scene><![CDATA[]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Virtuoso turntable jester]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">He is a jester wearing several caps: Away from his turntables Kid Koala moonlights as a graphic novelist and designer. Ask any music nerd, though, and his trademark will forever be his virtuoso skills at the record players: He uses his turntables as a melodic instrument, bending a single long note under the needle at different speeds, thus creating a seasick, psychedelic and jazzy sound all of his own. On his latest record, <em>12 Bit Blues</em>, Kid Koala puts blues music under the needle, but this guy can take any genre and dip it in his own luminous paintbox.  </p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Ninja Tune / VME</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/9f58e7117f.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/0d66132bf2.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/kid-koala/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="83">
<artistName><![CDATA[KING KRULE]]></artistName>
<country>UK</country>
<scene><![CDATA[]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Depression tunes from East London.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="MsoNormal">Judging from his first, self-titled EP, King Krule might end up as the voice of his generation. And the skinny, redheaded teenager does not paint a bright picture of England for generation 1994.</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">With an age-corroded baritone at the centre, he mumble-sings quiveringly raw songs about hopelessness, sounding as if they were written by the most notorious pessimist and heavy smoker at your local pub.</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">King Krule serves up the gloomy forecasts in a melodic blend of blues, jazz and reverb-wrapped pop. Previous projects from the East London troubadour also indicate a familiarity with dubstep and hip hop – however, all this is just the first outline drawn by a despondent, great talent.</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/70c18d9ee7.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/9c12d2d0ff.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/king-krule/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="84">
<artistName><![CDATA[KING TUFF]]></artistName>
<country>US</country>
<scene><![CDATA[]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Melodic garage rock]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Straightforward rock’n’roll is Kyle Thomas’ true calling despite duties in a series of very different bands. This productive slacker writes laidback garage rock tunes shining like a Cadillac; these songs will make you forget about ever feeling older than 17. All the tunes are written, sung and served with an attitude that incarnates 60es and 70es melodic golden age of rock. Prepare for a dose of rock from a major talent, who’s obviously head over heels in love with the genre.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Sub Pop / Target</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/30570c3c00.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/26f660cdd1.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/king-tuff/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="85">
<artistName><![CDATA[KOTTARASHKY & THE RAIN DOGS]]></artistName>
<country>BG</country>
<scene><![CDATA[]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Modern Balkan beats]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Balkan and Eastern Europe is more than hectic, high-speed wedding music. Kottarashky &amp; The Rain Dogs take us to the cosmopol of Sofia as of right now.</p>
<p class="bodytext"> Kottarashky broke through with the laptop-based <em>Opa Hey!</em> With the backing band The Rain Dogs he wanted to introduce a more organic approach.</p>
<p class="bodytext">The dexterous orchestra serves a chilled brew of East European folk music, dub, funk and soul, and Aleksandar Dobrev’s clarinet secures nerve, verve and beauty in the laid-back movements.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Kottarashky &amp; The Rain Dogs is music with a slow pulse, like drifting through modern Sofia on a summer day. </p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Asphalt Tango / Import</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/a36386c57e.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/f8e1164b55.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/kottarashky-the-rain-dogs/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="86">
<artistName><![CDATA[KRAFTWERK]]></artistName>
<country>DE</country>
<scene><![CDATA[]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Pioneers of electro do unique 3D show]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Imagining electronic music without Kraftwerk is practically impossible. The legends from Düsseldorf were the first modern band to use electronic instruments solely.</p>
<p class="bodytext">The seminal band created the soundtrack for our computer world and were the inspiration for a wide range of musical genres such as electro, synthpop and techno.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Kraftwerk return to Roskilde Festival with their extraordinary 3D show, which has carried away London’s Tate Modern as well.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Roskilde Festival hands out glasses to the audience, securing a visual space age feeling worthy of the future-minded computer sounds.   </p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Astralwerks / EMI</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>1</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/285cbe10e8.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/de936a8616.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/kraftwerk-1/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="87">
<artistName><![CDATA[KRAR COLLECTIVE ]]></artistName>
<country>ET</country>
<scene><![CDATA[]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Electric, danceable lyre rock]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Krar is the name of a kind of lyre, an Ethiopian descent of string instrument said to have been played even way back in ancient Egypt. Despite the long ancestry, the aged instrument has never sounded as it does in the hands of Krar Collective. With a bucketful of electricity vocalist and virtuoso Temesegen Tareken make the strings light up and spark in your ears. He is backed up by Genet Asefa and Amare who enrich the hypnotic string tones with song, dance, exclamations of joy, hand claps and highly physical drumming. The music of Krar Collective collects parts of its sound in the traditional, religious ceremonies of Ethiopia, still you sense from the rocking, even funky, pulse that the trio is currently residing in London. </p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/66f2e8b3ea.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/e74c2f36b1.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/krar-collective/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="88">
<artistName><![CDATA[KREATOR]]></artistName>
<country>DE</country>
<scene><![CDATA[]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[German thrash classic]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Thrash metal acts as a source of eternal youth for several of the genre's classic bands. Just look at Kreator, German metal kings who after more than 30 years into their career still makes the stage boil. </p>
<p class="bodytext">Since the early 80s, the Germans have been spitting out albums that have enrolled their sound in the genre's DNA. The last one is the <em>Phantom Antichrist</em> from 2012, showing a band in self-assured great shape. </p>
<p class="bodytext">All of you that just at one time or another have considered long hair or denim vest: come and test your endurance of thrash metal of the old school, stuffed to overflowing with sublime riffs, blistering guitar solos and sprinting drums.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Sony</p>
<p class="bodytext"> </p>]]></description>
<prioritet>2</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/75aaf86e2a.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/a61be9dc14.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/kreator-1/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="89">
<artistName><![CDATA[KVELERTAK]]></artistName>
<country>NO</country>
<scene><![CDATA[]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Metallic hardcore punk with humour and hooks.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">The Norwegians tighten the grip. Kvelertak has made the international audience gasp for air with their blend of hardcore punk, black metal and erection-inducing garage rock.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Even though the lyrics about <em>fimbulwinter</em>, mead and bloodlust are sung in a true Stavanger dialect, the international audience has really taken the band to heart. Kvelertak adds a shot of humour and more straightforward rock to the sinister Norway.</p>
<p class="bodytext">With a new album on the way from Kvelertak, the weather forecast reports a musical thunderstorm over Northern Europe, which will make everything go black – even in the back rows.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Indie Recordings / import</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>2</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/7d3bf03705.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/36769a2aff.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/kvelertak-1/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="90">
<artistName><![CDATA[K-X-P]]></artistName>
<country>FI</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Apollo Countdown]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Punk rock with a mechanical heart]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">How trashy and whacked-out can you play electronic rock? Using German favorites like Kraftwerk and Neu! as starting points, K-X-P take the formula even further. </p>
<p class="bodytext">On their second album the band has intensified the punk intensity, still the German-sounding mechanics rummages persistently underneath the bulldozer beats of the Finns. </p>
<p class="bodytext">Their live shows are journeys into a black maelstrom where the music’s malignant and industrial gravity emerges clearly like black smoke against the summer sky. </p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Melodic / Import</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/09f16f05dc.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/0d06eba8de.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/k-x-p/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="91">
<artistName><![CDATA[KENDRICK LAMAR]]></artistName>
<country>US</country>
<scene><![CDATA[]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[The new hip hop king of the West Coast]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">After promising run-ups, Kendrick Lamar has now made the leap into the list of grand hip hop acts. good kid, m.A.A. d. city is recognised as the work of a major artist and already considered a bona fide masterpiece.</p>
<p class="bodytext">And the Nordic audience has already witnessed how he masters his craft in a live setting as well, laidback, with superior improvisations and vintage hip hop magic oozing from each syllable and stanza.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Kendrick Lamar has given classic hip hop a major comeback. Mr. “ya bishhh” raps about his family and the streets, leaving hip hop lovers with a sweet itch in the soul reminiscent of yesteryear’s West Coast hip hop majesties.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Interscope / Universal</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>2</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/742b219eb7.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/5172b50923.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/kendrick-lamar/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="92">
<artistName><![CDATA[LEMÂITRE]]></artistName>
<country>NO</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Apollo Countdown]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Warm, Francophile electro]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Maybe Oslo is actually the Paris of the North?</p>
<p class="bodytext">Ulrik Denizou Lund and Ketil Jansen founded Lemâitre in 2010. Judging from their electro-acoustic instrumentation and warm disco feeling, they aim to become the Norwegian equivalent to French acts such as Justice, Phoenix and Daft Punk. </p>
<p class="bodytext">And from California to Lithuania, people have noticed the two childhood friends. The international audience will surely continue dancing when Lemâitre this year release another ep of organic electro beats, called Relativity 3.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Sony Music</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/57f5020c89.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/27e2e549ba.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/lemaitre/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="93">
<artistName><![CDATA[DAVID LINDLEY ]]></artistName>
<country>US</country>
<scene><![CDATA[]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Guitar wizard with a spectacular resume]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Playing gigs with Leonard Cohen, Crosby &amp; Co., Dolly Parton and not least Jackson Browne and Warren Zevon has made David Lindley a legend among musicians. The roguish American virtuoso and collector of instruments has had a remarkable solo career on the sideline. In the late 60s he formed Kaleidoscope, which is easily described as the first western world music band in history. Today this unique character combines rock, reggae and much more in his own crooked mixture – played on an arsenal of string instruments collected since the very beginning of his more than 45 year long career.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label:</p>
<p class="bodytext"> </p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/570ea6b4a0.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/90ff1582b8.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/david-lindley/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="94">
<artistName><![CDATA[LINKOBAN]]></artistName>
<country>DK</country>
<scene><![CDATA[]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Grime hip-hop a la Copenhagen]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">The legendary American critic Robert Christgau described Linkoban’s flow as better than that of many native English speakers. The great praise was but a single voice in the chorus of enthusiasm after her concert at Pavilion Junior last year. Linkoban hails from Copenhagen but her music and the edgy performance simultaneously reeks of London, New York, Tokyo and Singapore. Cheap rave synths, ghetto beats and the atmosphere of Japanese horror movies walk hand in hand when Linkoban gives us the sound of grime in the 10s: Equal parts horror, dancehall and radioactive pop.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Superbillion / Playground</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/ae39fddeb4.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/0cbbd4edeb.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/linkoban-3/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="95">
<artistName><![CDATA[LOWER]]></artistName>
<country>DK</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Pavilion Junior]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Hostile postpunk from upcoming Danes]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">”It was almost annoying how good they were.” The words come from punk brothers Iceage after witnessing Lower’s first gig. </p>
<p class="bodytext">With their discordant and hostile postpunk, Lower are one of the most promising names on Copenhagen’s underground punk scene. </p>
<p class="bodytext">Depressive, even desperate the music may be. But Lower are also part of a very uplifting chapter in the tale of Danish punk. </p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Escho</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/b0bc4c2e67.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/38a959bc66.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/lower/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="96">
<artistName><![CDATA[THE LUMINEERS]]></artistName>
<country>US</country>
<scene><![CDATA[]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Stamp-and-clap folk rock from shooting stars]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">At some concerts singing along and bursting out in excitement seem just natural. This is the case in the company of The Lumineers. </p>
<p class="bodytext">Their stomp-and-clap folk rock is conquering the world at the moment. And it's no surprise that Marcus of Mumford &amp; Sons hailed The Lumineers a personal favourite. </p>
<p class="bodytext">The band's self-titled debut was released last year and has along with a number of life-affirming concerts turned into a shooting star, not least due to their love ode &quot;Ho Hey&quot;.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Front man Wesley Schultz' voice has a soulful sound that will take you from tragedies to swinging in the chandeliers. </p>
<p class="bodytext">The Lumineers is a band that should be playing in a small living room. The demand brings a need for a more spacious stage but no matter what, the intimacy of the music will surely fill the space underneath the tent canvas. </p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Decca / Universal</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/174a9715be.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/f1f7a2713d.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/the-lumineers/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="97">
<artistName><![CDATA[MASKINEN]]></artistName>
<country>SE</country>
<scene><![CDATA[]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Swedish electro heroes]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">The partners who run Maskinen are close to achieving royal status in Sweden – not only because they crossed swords with the royal family on the platinum selling single ”Krossa alla fönster”. Their mixture of bass, rap, rave, baile funk and pop has turned the Swedish party sensation into a national treasure – their Wu Tang-like logo has even become a favourite tattoo template among the beautiful Swedish people. Now Maskinen is rolling across the sound: The two boys are ready to prove why their name is written in capital letters on Swedish festival posters.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Pope / Import</p>
<p class="bodytext"> </p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/f60b47a9b7.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/b17189612e.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/maskinen/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="98">
<artistName><![CDATA[MEHER & SHER ALI]]></artistName>
<country>PK</country>
<scene><![CDATA[]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Allah-devoted trace]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">The 700-year-old music genre Qawwali is best described as Isalimc gospel. Meher &amp; Sher Ali belongs at the top end of the genre. Departing from the Sufi-tradition, in which music is a tool to approach the divine, the two Pakistanis sing and play their way towards the diverse heart of Allah. The Tabla drum and the harmonium along with the chanting vocals make up some of the characteristics of the music. The brothers and their ensemble achieve an ecstasy, which can make even the most unreligious into believers – in the music if nothing else.</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/bfaf1223b4.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/73fd3816f5.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/meher-sher-ali/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="99">
<artistName><![CDATA[MERIDIAN BROTHERS]]></artistName>
<country>CO</country>
<scene><![CDATA[]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Latin for weirdos]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">The sextet of Meridian Brothers do avantgarde pop from another dimension. The foundation is Latin and tropical rhythms from their homeland.</p>
<p class="bodytext">In a bubbling witch's brew of sunshine and madness, band leader Eblis Álvarez takes us into his vision of Latin America. </p>
<p class="bodytext">The crooked sounds are made out of lounge-like organs, seasick rhythms and steel brass. Latin king Tito Puente would recognise some of the tones – avant-garde pirates such as The Residents would recognise others, as would nutty composers such as Karlheinz Stockhausen.</p>
<p class="bodytext">A semi-bizarre blend you will discover to be surprisingly addictive.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Soundway / Import</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/1a7816efe4.png]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/edf4a321df.png]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/meridian-brothers/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="100">
<artistName><![CDATA[METZ]]></artistName>
<country>CA</country>
<scene><![CDATA[]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Purifying guitar mayhem]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Ever feel a longing for really dirty and gritty guitar rock? Metz have been listening to your prayers. The Canadian trio is inspired by the most ear-bleeding guitar rock of the 90es. Since 2007 they have been refining their mayhem and finally in 2012 the selftitled debut record was ready. <em>Metz</em>, of course, is released on Sub Pop, legendary, original home of Nirvana. Catchy earworms or pop bangers are not Metz’ main concern. Instead, they aim to shake their audience through by the joy-inducing friction from guitars, bass and drums.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Sub Pop / Target</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/5759478b27.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/74ac35db87.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/metz/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="101">
<artistName><![CDATA[MIGUEL]]></artistName>
<country>US</country>
<scene><![CDATA[]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[The new golden boy of R&B]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Miguel is a central part of the encouraging boost R&amp;B is currently going through. The genre has been high jacked from glittery music videos and given back it’s soul and heart. Miguel is a womanizer and sexy MF with a weakness for female thighs and cleavage. At the same time he is a progressive musical mind who clearly wish to continue the tradition of Marvin Gaye and Prince; complete with psychedelic rock arrangements and soulful song writing. The wonder boy Miguel commands a full package of stage presence, sex appeal and snappy dance moves. Prepare to be seduced.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: RCA / Sony Music</p>
<p class="bodytext"> </p>]]></description>
<prioritet>2</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/a76d0610b4.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/66c302a9aa.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/miguel/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="102">
<artistName><![CDATA[KILLER MIKE]]></artistName>
<country>US</country>
<scene><![CDATA[]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Politically charged Southern hip hopper]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext"><em>R.A.P. Music</em>, the title of Killer Mike’s most recent and best album, is, tellingly enough, short for ’Rebellious African People’s Music’. Working with Brooklyn magus El-P, Killer Mike has sharpened his attack and made a meteor-like hip hop record. His politically charged hip hop universe is shivering with tongue-sharp rap, sparkling attitude and futuristic beats. Dirty south hip hop with a touch of alternative New York. Killer Mike’s status as inspired protest hip hopper in the tradition of Public Enemy has never been as lethally strong as right now.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Grind Time Official / Import</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/6f63072a5f.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/41e582168f.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/killer-mike/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="103">
<artistName><![CDATA[MOKOOMBA]]></artistName>
<country>ZW</country>
<scene><![CDATA[]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Festive and life-affirming Afro pop]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="MsoNormal">Zimbabwe’s maybe greatest music export right now is charming an international audience with their uplifting songs. Mokoomba, fronted by Mathias Muzaza's lush voice, were raised in the small village of Victoria Falls as a part of the Tonga minority.</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">Countries such as Zambia, Angolo and South Africa were never that far away, though. Maybe here we find the explanation for their brew of Southern, African traditions, filled to the brim with swaying hips, hand claps and festive brass. With the language and rhythms of their own minority as a starting point, they even add funk, pop and Latin rhythms. </p>
<p class="MsoNormal">The end result is dance music with universal appeal, almost certain to leave listeners happy and with a nice suntan.</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">Label: Zig Zag World / Import</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/ae449e48ac.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/567d92c52a.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/mokoomba/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="104">
<artistName><![CDATA[MOTHER LEWINSKY]]></artistName>
<country>DK</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Pavilion Junior]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Violin based pop.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Using the violin as its spinning fulcrum, Mother Lewinsky creates a different pop imprint full of cheeky ambushes and surprising twists. </p>
<p class="bodytext">The three masterminds behind this grand live orchestra all play in other bands – Tako Lako, Mescalin, Baby and Surf in Stereo – but use Mother Lewinsky as a playground where they can explore the potential in using strings to create a delicious pop sound. </p>
<p class="bodytext">Alternative rock and classical music have been enjoying a serious flirt for a while now. Mother Lewinsky is a superior Danish example of a band marrying up these two genres to create something bigger than the sum of its parts.</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/7b30f83f99.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/75725400a3.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/mother-lewinsky/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="105">
<artistName><![CDATA[MYKKI BLANCO]]></artistName>
<country>US</country>
<scene><![CDATA[]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Spectacular punk rapper]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Michael David Quattlebaum Jr. attacks mainstream culture wearing full make-up and takes the stage as ’teenage female rapper’ Mykki Blanco. Being a flamboyant transvestite rapper, he angers anyone who sees hip hop as a bastion for “real men”. On a bed of dirty electronic, Mykki Blanco offers a tour into the (very) alternative night life. A provocative show which aims to sabotage the differences between man and woman, theater and reality, punk and hip hop.</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/f60b47a9b7.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/b17189612e.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/mykki-blanco/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="106">
<artistName><![CDATA[MØ]]></artistName>
<country>DK</country>
<scene><![CDATA[]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Gritty pop princess]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">The international music world is picking up on how to write Danish letter Ø. This is largely due to MØ, Denmark’s most sparkling meteor of 2013. During no time, she has sneaked herself onto the global arena, which has met her with loving arms like a new Grimes or Lykke Li. Despite the virginal artist name (‘mø’ is an Old Norse word for a woman unwed), Karen Marie Ørsted is no fragile violet. Her glamouros pop songs have an urban, gritty attitude, and MØ is able to use her lush voice for rapping as well as singing.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Sony Music</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/c07b45158f.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/3dcd42e735.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/moe/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="107">
<artistName><![CDATA[THE NATIONAL]]></artistName>
<country>US</country>
<scene><![CDATA[]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Melodic and mournful baritone rock ]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">When The National did Roskilde Festival in 2007, their emotional and mournful rock was still a well-kept secret among the chosen few. Their stock kept going up after this concert and a mutual, loving relationship between Denmark and the Brooklyn-based band emerged. </p>
<p class="bodytext">In 2013 they take Roskilde Festival with a brand new record, Trouble Will Find Me, in their backpack – several prior works, like Boxer and Alligator, are already considered contemporary classics. </p>
<p class="bodytext">The National know how to depict modern life at its most despairing. Baritone Matt Berninger is a lyricist and singer who bears comparison to the likes of Leonard Cohen and Morrissey. </p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: 4AD / Playground</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>1</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/5d87174ff9.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/c7fa3244f1.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/the-national-2/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="108">
<artistName><![CDATA[NAVNELØS]]></artistName>
<country>DK</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Pavilion Junior]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Poetic chamber rock]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Playing ambitious chamber rock, Navneløs (Danish for nameless) visit classical music, post rock and jazz without ever quite settling down. At one point the music is minimalistic. Suddenly pompous. Soon, often, breathtakingly beautiful. With cello, piano, steel brass, noisy guitars and the strong vocals of Lin Rosenbeck, Navneløs beautifully evade the tyranny of categories.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Indieaner</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/d7e3441ce1.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/6514da3008.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/navneloes/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="109">
<artistName><![CDATA[NAZORANAI]]></artistName>
<country>INT</country>
<scene><![CDATA[]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Doom-noise from dark masterminds.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">The Japanese dark lord Keiji Haino has joined forces with the Australian Oren Ambarchi and the American Stephen O'Malley who has previously shrouded Roskilde in darkness with Sunn O))).</p>
<p class="bodytext">Don’t expect a sunnier performance this time.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Nazoranai takes you on a trip far into a mind where madness is screaming and the darkness is unending. Haino’s guitar sounds as if it were stringed with barbed wire, and his madman vocals contribute to the nightmare.</p>
<p class="bodytext">With extremely long song titles and songs that never want to end, you are taken into a darkness blacker than the Roskilde night.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Ideological Organ / Import</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/c65862301d.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/eb0e55920a.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/nazoranai/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="110">
<artistName><![CDATA[NUBANOUR]]></artistName>
<country>EG</country>
<scene><![CDATA[]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Percussion based, ancient music]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">The Nubian tribes originally lived in Egypt and the Sudan close to their beloved river; the Nile. The famous body of water is the heart, pulse and soul in Nubanour’s music. Using their special tambourine-like frame drums as the core, the white-clad ensemble sings about the joys and sorrows of their people. Unfortunately the latter takes up most of the repertoire. The music of Nubanour has a droning, chant-like quality rooted in centuries of ordeal. In their groovy and captivating music, clapping and dance we encounter an exiled people yearning to return to the well of their origin.</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/65c2e6b172.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/b62a23dc22.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/nubanour/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="111">
<artistName><![CDATA[NUMBERS feat. RUSTIE, JACKMASTER, ONEMAN, SPENCER, DEADBOY, REDINHO and SOPHIE]]></artistName>
<country>UK</country>
<scene><![CDATA[]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[The best electronic sounds from Glasgow and beyond]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">The lads behind Numbers started their careers with a club in a basement under an Indian restaurant outside of Glasgow. They were too young to attend clubs themselves.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Today they are important figures. Numbers is a fusion of three influential Glasgow labels. No genre barriers are present here.</p>
<p class="bodytext">On this Roskilde tour de force we get techno, electro, hip hop, UK funky, dubstep - you name it. Numbers and their entourage attack the dogmas of electronic music in an irreverent manner. Still, you sense a strong veneration towards classics such as Daft Punk and Chase 500. </p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Numbers / Import</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/06fb53558e.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/4c01009458.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/numbers-feat-rustie-jackmaster-oneman-spencer-deadboy-redinho-and-sophie/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="112">
<artistName><![CDATA[OF MONSTERS AND MEN]]></artistName>
<country>IS</country>
<scene><![CDATA[]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Magnificent, grandly orchestrated folk pop]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Of Monsters And Men's grandly orchestrated folk pop is loaded with hands-in-the-air joy of life, clapping of hands and wonderful sound of horns, and it has fallen right into the grace of an international audience.</p>
<p class="bodytext">The five man collective of multi-instrumentalists fills the space of the stage with a feeling of community, which is the perfect match for the joyous crowd at a festival in the summer. </p>
<p class="bodytext">The voices of Nanna Bryndís Hilmarsdóttirs and Ragnar “Raggi” Þórhallssons suit each other beautifully and with their dark nature poetry they create an unmistakably Icelandic feel. Of course, the Icelanders already consider Of Monsters And Men a national treasure.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Universal Republic / Import</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>2</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/28d7d77c13.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/3901aa5921.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/of-monsters-and-men/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="113">
<artistName><![CDATA[ONDATRÓPICA]]></artistName>
<country>CO</country>
<scene><![CDATA[]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Tropical cornucopia]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Mario Galeano from Colombia and Will Holland from Great Britain have gathered a regular dream team to explore the tropical sounds of Colombian music. The sun-drenched mixture is full of accordion, saxophone, congas and piano. Younger musicians add elements of dub and hip hop while some of the most skilled players from Latin music’s 70es heyday are playing as well. The South African folk music of cumbia is central in the mix, but other styles from the same region are present as well. This party is full of warm vibes, aimed at both your ears and dancing shoes.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Soundway / Import</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/848016fc8e.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/bbf2c76492.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/ondatropica/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="114">
<artistName><![CDATA[OVERTHROW]]></artistName>
<country>NO</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Pavilion Junior]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Aggressive metal punk.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Stavanger in western Norway spits out a steady, black stream of metal bands.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Attention has grown around Overthrow, especially after the debut album <em>Adjust to Darkness</em> saw the light of day. Their sonic punch-in-the-stomach has triggered positive comparisons to Converge, Cancer Bats and, of course, the other darkened fellow townsmen in Kvelertak.</p>
<p class="bodytext">With an aggressive mix of metal, hardcore punk and genuine rock'n'roll, Overthrow makes your blood boil and your muscles flex.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Indie Recordings / import</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/fae2c8fc8d.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/50e756bd31.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/overthrow/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="115">
<artistName><![CDATA[PÄÄ KII]]></artistName>
<country>FI</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Pavilion Junior]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Rock’n’roll punk sung in Finnish]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">They sing in their strange mother tongue. Still, Pää Kii are living the punk philosophy better than many of their English peers.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Despite lacking a rehearsal room, they have been nominated for a Nordic Music Prize for their energetic and fast-selling debut album.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Pää Kii – Finnish for shut up – is straightforward punk in the vein of the genre’s 70s heyday. Devoid of detours of any kind. The rocking and rolling punk songs make you want to wear a Ramones leather jacket and take Finnish 101.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Stupido / import</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/388df2a844.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/5ea1f304e5.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/paeae-kii/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="116">
<artistName><![CDATA[PARQUET COURTS]]></artistName>
<country>US</country>
<scene><![CDATA[]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Crumpled, punkish guitar rock]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">”The Fall meets Neil Young.“ This is the bizarre way Parquet Courts at one point described their own sound. With a neat mixture of punk and indie rock from both sides of the Atlantic, the New York-based band has waltzed from the obscure underground into the spotlight among 2013’s hottest newcomers. These fellas have their own sloppy way of playing crumpled guitar rock. With itchy guitars and febrile vocal rants inspired by Heaven-knows-what-or-who, Parquet Courts may very well end up as idols among music lovers with a penchant for the permanently crooked.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: What's Your Rupture? / Import</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/6ffc64a939.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/e799031e49.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/parquet-courts/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="117">
<artistName><![CDATA[PINKUNOIZU]]></artistName>
<country>DK</country>
<scene><![CDATA[]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Global mosaic rock]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Pink noise: A fitting description of Pinkunoizu. An experimenting, wild and exotic sound coated in the sugar of melody as opposed to the grating white noise. Inspirations and references flutter like a malfunctioning compass: A moment in a lounge in Japan is followed by mass in a Catholic monastery which in turn is followed by a trip down a mosquito-infested, African river. This delirious mash of post punk, pop, jazz and krautrock has won the Danes recognition beyond national borders. Pinkunoizu: A nutritional form of candyfloss you actually want to consume.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Full Time Hobby</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/d47fef7ff4.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/eee8ea1a55.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/pinkunoizu/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="118">
<artistName><![CDATA[PISSED JEANS]]></artistName>
<country>US</country>
<scene><![CDATA[]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Hardcore punk for your inner Neanderthal]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Sometimes the internal Neanderthal makes a sound. Pissed Jeans is an embittered, annoyed punk band who were put in the world to please the dissatisfied cave dweller with a copious amount of angry, noisy hardcore punk. Look forward to some cleansing war music played by a bunch of everyday people, who know what it feels like to be standing in the rush hour train going home from a dead end job with a full bladder and empty stomach. Using crushing riffs and ritualistic destruction these Americans almost succeed in making it beautiful to be among those, who always seem to pick the slow line in the supermarket.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Sub Pop / Target</p>
<p class="bodytext"> </p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/ccc0e3cbc0.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/bde7badca6.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/pissed-jeans/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="119">
<artistName><![CDATA[POSTILJONEN]]></artistName>
<country>SE/NO</country>
<scene><![CDATA[]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Azure dream pop]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">With a heart laden with melancholy memories of summer Postiljonen aim their sights at yours. The Swedish/Norwegian trio deal with azure dream pop – the air thick with evaporated water from the Mediterranean and dreams of love as fragile as soap bubbles. Postiljonen skilfully tickle the eternally nostalgic summer-centre of our hearts using soothing synthesizers, 80s-like productions and vocals wrapped in effects and fog.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Hybris / Import</p>
<p class="bodytext"> </p>
<p class="bodytext"> </p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/5f0d817e59.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/d2db25722d.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/postiljonen/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="120">
<artistName><![CDATA[QUADRON]]></artistName>
<country>DK</country>
<scene><![CDATA[]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Sexy satin pop]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">”I was raised on breast milk and Sade”. The quote is from Quadron singer Coco O. Sure enough the Danish duo are born with a flair for the creation of sexy satin soul and R&amp;B. With a crisp and delicate sound, the other half of Quadron, producer and multi-instrumentalist Robin Hannibal, is currently among the strongest and most successful producers and arrangers in Scandinavia. Prince and Adele have already pronounced themselves among Quadron’s fans. The Danes are working on a new album and are moving towards a more up-tempo version of the soft tones.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Epic</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/a392fb1d8b.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/e5eb4ed987.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/quadron/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="121">
<artistName><![CDATA[QUEENS OF THE STONE AGE]]></artistName>
<country>US</country>
<scene><![CDATA[]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Hormone-laden, much-loved cactus rock.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">2013 will clearly be a new landmark year for Queens of the Stone Age. Fans have longed for new material from these sought-after stone agers since 2007 – incidentally the same year they last visited Roskilde Festival.</p>
<p class="bodytext">According to front man Josh Homme, the new album is a return to the band's early virtues – even with Dave Grohl behind the drums again.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Queens of the Stone Age’s psychedelic heavy rock reeks of both cactus acid, sex and petrol. At the same time they have conquered the airwaves with hits that have made the Neolithic gang one of the most beloved rock groups of the 21st century.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Rekords Rekords / import</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>1</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/40df26386d.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/bd9fa8d745.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/queens-of-the-stone-age-3/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="122">
<artistName><![CDATA[KRISTINA RENEÉ]]></artistName>
<country>DK</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Pavilion Junior]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Singer/songwriter with an electronic touch]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Using piano, acoustic guitar and some cool electronics as stepping-stones Kristina Renée has taken the first steps towards creating a name for herself among lovers of pop music with an element of Nordic soul. She is a singer/songwriter of the melancholic kind. The songs from her first release are melodious, thoughtful and celestial in a way, which makes it difficult to imagine that they were not written in the Arctic regions of the world. Still, she points out in an interview that her coming full-length debut may point in another direction entirely. </p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Sony Music</p>
<p class="bodytext"> </p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/6be8a05618.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/b3459a78d6.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/kristina-renee/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="123">
<artistName><![CDATA[REWOLMER ]]></artistName>
<country>DK</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Apollo Countdown]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Electronica of crackling beauty]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="MsoNormal">Jeppe Lauritzen places his own style somewhere between atmospheric ambient and clubbier sounds. His drowsy electronica is surrounded by distorted voices with edgy rhytms underneath. </p>
<p class="MsoNormal">Rewolmer is music suited for both daydreaming and introspective dancing. With his EP <em>Error Perfect</em> Rewolmer has captured the attention of blog media both abroad and in his own country. Crackling, synthetic beauty the way it is only produced in the laboratory of electronic music. </p>
<p class="MsoNormal">Label: SoundEscape</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/4328ea01fb.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/9460a690cf.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/rewolmer/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="124">
<artistName><![CDATA[RIHANNA]]></artistName>
<country>BB</country>
<scene><![CDATA[]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Super pop star and young diva.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Recent years have brought us few pop divas of Rihanna's caliber.</p>
<p class="bodytext">With a frequent stream of albums – a new one, <em>Unapologetic</em>, has just been released – she has planted her stilettos firmly at the top of the game when it comes to R&amp;B, pop and hip hop. Any American rapper with the right ambitions has also sung with the girl with the iconic voice.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Rihanna's charisma, sharp dance moves and long line of hits dominate a show filled with glamour, sex appeal and inescapable choruses.</p>
<p class="bodytext">The birth year is 1988. Nevertheless, Rihanna is already an experienced performer with a bountiful and varied song catalog. Ready to make the whole area in front of the Orange Stage sing and dance along.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Def Jam / Universal</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>1</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/966f05fd12.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/4ebf030db2.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/rihanna/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="125">
<artistName><![CDATA[HENRY ROLLINS - SPOKEN WORD]]></artistName>
<country>US</country>
<scene><![CDATA[]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Intelligent and embittered entertainment in the company of hard-core legend]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">A legendary hard-core singer, actor, pacifist, comedian, and journalist … the list goes on. Henry Rollins has brought his toned physique, wide jawline and hyper active mind to most of the arenas of the world: Older festival guests remember him from Black Flag, the (slightly) younger audience will recall the crossover-hit ”Liar”, some will have seen him in acting parts in <em>Sons of Anarchy</em> and <em>Lost Highway</em> and fans of comedy and spoken word will have laughed during his amazing monologues. At this year’s Roskilde Festival he will give no fewer than four performances in which he will demonstrate his brutal wit and political indignation. Enjoy an intelligent break from the music in the company of a great personality.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: 2.13.61 / Import</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>2</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/301507a4a5.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/864d1798fc.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/henry-rollins-spoken-word/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="126">
<artistName><![CDATA[MARTIN RYUM]]></artistName>
<country>DK</country>
<scene><![CDATA[]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Classical 60s poetry in fresh musical clothes]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">The reality-loving lyrics of Inger Christensen prompted Martin Ryum to put music to the words of the late poet. The former guitarist and singer from the noise rock band Speaker Bite Me comes out of a too long hiatus when he sits dawn at his piano to combine his interpretations of Christensen with songs from his first solo album <em>Uden Garanti</em>. Besides Christensen and her floating words from beyond, the very much alive Signe Høirup Wille-Jørgensen from Speaker Bite Me and Maria Laurette Friis from Tys Tys make up the ensemble.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Auditorium</p>
<p class="bodytext"> </p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/0a2cd3cb0d.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/939ac01e58.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/martin-ryum-1/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="127">
<artistName><![CDATA[SAVAGES]]></artistName>
<country>UK</country>
<scene><![CDATA[]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Blackened post-punk]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Savages have won over a hungry audience due to a batch of brutal shows. They are four girls on stage, playing raw post-punk with the same gory bite as Joy Division, Siouxsie and the Banshees and The Birthday Party when they gave birth to the genre. </p>
<p class="bodytext">The black-clad punk sisters have chosen to focus intensely on their live shows with only a single out, their debut album arrives later this year.</p>
<p class="bodytext">With determined ferocity, Savages raise the black flags in 2013.  </p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Pop Noire / Import</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/121836855b.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/f5d93886eb.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/savages/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="128">
<artistName><![CDATA[SCHULTZ & FOREVER]]></artistName>
<country>DK</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Pavilion Junior]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Intimate folk-singer with backing band]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Jonathan Schultz and his acoustic guitar create a vibrant presence in his home recordings using sparkling finger play and gritty, existential nerve. The 18-year-old kid steps on stage with a complete band making his folk-inspired song rise towards the canvas dome above. His music is reminiscent of a young Bob Dylan despite Jonathan Schultz’ claims to be more inspired by R. Kelly.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Cracki / Playground</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/9d5ebc0159.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/7ad89532cf.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/schultz-forever/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="129">
<artistName><![CDATA[SEKUOIA]]></artistName>
<country>DK</country>
<scene><![CDATA[]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Lingering electronica]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Sekuoia’s crackling and lingering electronica has already had him signed with acclaimed Berlin label Project: Mooncircle. Sekuoia combines the organic with the electronic in a dreamy meltdown. Dry beats, synth washes and copy/pasted vocals conjure echoes of both dubstep and atmospheric ambient. The painterly soundscapes of the young Dane are equal parts night club after midnight and stalactite cave at dawn.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Project Mooncircle</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/44711a70d2.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/7f8b13bf94.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/sekuoia/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="130">
<artistName><![CDATA[SIGUR RÓS]]></artistName>
<country>IS</country>
<scene><![CDATA[]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Delicate future rock.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">One of the world’s most ethereal and delicate rock bands is finally back at Roskilde Festival – for the first time since 2006.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Sigur Rós find their symphonic future rock in an air-void space, only accessed by astronauts and abstract painters. The unmistakable Icelandic mixture of sad angelic singing, big reverb and profound organ sounds is more delicate than newly fallen snow.</p>
<p class="bodytext">The joy and redemption will even greater when front man Jónsi now and again rocks out on the electric guitar. Sigur Rós – Icelandic for victory rose – have sown something quite unique in the middle of the flower bed of rock music.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: XL / Playground</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>1</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/14f61e97d5.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/4b3db3f6a8.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/sigur-ros-2/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="131">
<artistName><![CDATA[SIMIAN MOBILE DISCO]]></artistName>
<country>UK</country>
<scene><![CDATA[]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Respected electro duo]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="MsoNormal">Since the beginning of the new millenium, James Ford and Jas Shaw have combined dance-friendly club music, experimental techno and pop bangers featuring celebrities joining in on the chorus. </p>
<p class="MsoNormal">Simian Mobile Disco used to be a (kind of) rock group called Simian. Gradually, however, the disco version came to rule the show and fill the dance floors. On their latest album, <em>Unpatterns</em>,  Simian Mobile Disco have toned down the guest vocalists and serve up a purer distillation of techno, acid house and bass.</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">It's clear why Simian Mobile Disco have become VIPs merging the best of electronic music capitols such as London, Detroit and Chicago.</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">Label: Wichita / VME</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>2</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/96cb78a4d6.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/c8ac8a0ece.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/simian-mobile-disco/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="132">
<artistName><![CDATA[SLIPKNOT]]></artistName>
<country>US</country>
<scene><![CDATA[]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Here comes the pain.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="MsoNormal">Almost 15 years after their debut album, Slipknot has become one of the world's greatest metal bands – on a par with much older icons. With a series of raging metal albums and unforgettable stage shows, they have conquered the central spot in the bloodstained kings’ court.</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">The grotesque, masked vigilantes take the audience on a journey to hell’s burning ravines where all members commit themselves 101 % in the service of doom.</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">In 2013 Slipknot crowns few, chosen festival posters, including Roskilde Festival.</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">Prepare yourself and your limbs for a cleansing experience stretched to the breaking point with manic horror, tough riffs and surprisingly melodic choruses.</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">Label: Roadrunner / Warner</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>1</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/4c23b7534b.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/19e463ecbe.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/slipknot-2/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="133">
<artistName><![CDATA[SO-SO ECHO]]></artistName>
<country>DK</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Pavilion Junior]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Luxury pop with urban atmosphere]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">With January 2013 on their birth certificate, So-So Echo is very much a new acquaintance. They declined playing American mastodon festival SXSW to evolve and refine their product. And what a product it is. The Danish trio plays gorgeous, electronic pop oozing chilly elegance. Full of 80s nostalgia and stylish pink, but also an atmosphere of urban lights seen through tears. </p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/779335f4b4.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/b867e6a43f.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/so-so-echo/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="134">
<artistName><![CDATA[SOHN]]></artistName>
<country>UK</country>
<scene><![CDATA[]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Lonely electronica from promising Englishman]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">“I’m an old-school songwriter who happens to love electronic instruments”. This is Sohn’s description of himself. His lonely version of electronica has quickly become a minor sensation on the Internet. Unlike many of his pc-based producer colleagues he sings over the edited, often mind-blowingly beautiful productions. It gives the music an intimate, organic and almost R&amp;B- or Soul-like feel. Sohn is rapidly becoming one of the hottest names in the equally hot flow of neo-soul and white, moody R&amp;B.</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/6f2a28e7a6.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/5a88a14cc9.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/sohn/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="135">
<artistName><![CDATA[SOLBRUD]]></artistName>
<country>DK</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Pavilion Junior]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Atmospheric black metal]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Denmark hasn’t got a black metal rep as large as its Nordic neighbors. Solbrud may alter that fact. With long, atmospheric numbers, the young band creates a world of fabled, mythological darkness you don’t want to leave again at all. </p>
<p class="bodytext">Lead singer Ole Luk’s guttural screaming vocals leave no doubt that this is primitive black metal attacking with the characteristic, choking density. At the same time, there is also a core of melodic beauty in the middle of the mud storm of guitar, bass and drums. </p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Euphonious / VME</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/e54fa102e2.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/e39972fcd9.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/solbrud/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="136">
<artistName><![CDATA[SÖNDÖRGÖ]]></artistName>
<country>HU</country>
<scene><![CDATA[]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Virtuoso, Slavic folk music centered on strings]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">The music of the Roma people does not have to played using horn ensembles. Söndörgö has had their breakthrough on the European roots-scene with a teeming concoction of harmonies from the southern Slavic regions, inspiringly transplanted to the bands home north of Budapest. The lively music is played and performed almost solely on the tambura; a regional stringed instrument whose potential is milked to the last drop. The virtuoso group of brothers and cousins has transferred their ancestral music to a present gear. This ensemble of well-playing fiery souls will give us a delightfully updated performance of the regions folk music.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Harmonia Mundi / Import</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/bd9e158530.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/8f0f893d1f.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/soendoergoe/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="137">
<artistName><![CDATA[THE SOUL REBELS]]></artistName>
<country>US</country>
<scene><![CDATA[]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Horn music from New Orleans]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">An average of 250 live performances a year has earned The Soul Rebels a description as a thoroughly well practised ensemble. Their musical origin is the horn music played at funeral marches in New Orleans and they play a mix between traditional music and soul, funk, jazz and hip-hop. These gentlemen separate from more traditional brass bands by often letting vocals accompany the glistening notes. The Soul Rebels stir the generic gumbo while syncopes sputter, flash and writhe through the sparkle of trombones and tubas. Backed by a socially conscious hip-hop attitude and a wealthy musical tradition this band is ready to give the world a party version of New Orleans.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Rounder / Import</p>
<p class="bodytext"> </p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/53d7f20c3b.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/b2fbcebe12.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/the-soul-rebels/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="138">
<artistName><![CDATA[ANDY STOTT]]></artistName>
<country>UK</country>
<scene><![CDATA[]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Atmospheric electronica with a heavy bass]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">The bewitched trance of Andy Stott takes you to a room, where every inch is more compact than an atomic bomb. The Brit specializes in dubstep, minimal techno and electronica. Often you can sense the bass more than hear it, the black-hearted beats are mildly worrying but also seemingly beyond gravity like the beautiful gymnast that graces the cover of breakthrough album <em>Luxury Problems</em>. Here, Andy Stott has crafted his most beautiful and approachable epos to date. His ghostly electronica is unreal and aboveground but also, due to the bass, a decidedly physical encounter. </p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Modern Love / Import</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/e9d2072d81.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/0523a63321.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/andy-stott/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="139">
<artistName><![CDATA[SUICIDAL TENDENCIES]]></artistName>
<country>US</country>
<scene><![CDATA[]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Old-school hardcore]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Despite keeping in shape by playing live things have been quiet around Suicidal Tendencies with regards to making new albums lately. But 2013 is set to be a special year for front man Mike Muir (aka Cyco Mico) and his entourage of pumped up homeboys. The album 13 is the first in as many years and includes – you guessed it – 13 searing tracks which all demonstrate why Suicidal Tendencies is an institution. Not only the lead singer has long ago become a myth in the flesh; the guitarist Dean Pleasants is close to becoming a legend in his own right based on his funky grooves and eloquent solos. Whether you enjoy hardcore, thrash metal or skate punk, you HAVE to experience tracks like ”Institutionalized” and ”I Saw Your Mommy” live, before you kick off your sneakers for good.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Suicidal / Target</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>2</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/bf27856e30.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/819eee254e.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/suicidal-tendencies-1/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="140">
<artistName><![CDATA[SUMMER HEART]]></artistName>
<country>SE</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Apollo Countdown]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Soothing, sun-drenched synth pop]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">The beach, the sun, the waves. The music of David Alexander has a thing about summer.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Most of his songs are full of that sunlight people in Scandinavia only get to enjoy a few months each year. This gives the music its own shimmering, mournful beauty as synths, guitars and effect-drowned vocals weave a tapestry of drowsy summer memories, imaginary or real.  </p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Nomethod / Import </p>
<p class="bodytext"> </p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/172ddeb117.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/939c7cec5d.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/summer-heart/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="141">
<artistName><![CDATA[SUUNS]]></artistName>
<country>CA</country>
<scene><![CDATA[]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Curly experimental rock]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Canada’s ability to spawn original alternative bands seldom lets the country down.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Suuns are the expeimental types; imagine Radiohead born and raised in Montreal instead of Oxford.</p>
<p class="bodytext">In spite of the heavy electronic touch on their albums, they are primarily a rock band of the bold and adventurous kind with a penchant for jamming themselves into a cloud of electronica, krautrock and post-rock.</p>
<p class="bodytext">A new album called Images Du Futur is due in March. Suuns prepare to catch new souls in their hypermusical spiderweb.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Secretly Canadian / Import</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/a9a9cb5c71.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/f12114a543.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/suuns/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="142">
<artistName><![CDATA[THE SWORD]]></artistName>
<country>US</country>
<scene><![CDATA[]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Classic hard rock with muscular riffs]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">With muscular riffs and a tight rhythm section, The Sword have become one of the most consistent heavy metal bands these days. </p>
<p class="bodytext">Fans of both sludge and stoner metal bands of recent times and worshippers of Black Sabbath are left in good hands with The Sword. These tough guys from Austin, Texas have a tight grip on the virtues of classic hard rock. </p>
<p class="bodytext">On their latest record Apocryphon, the main theme is Christianity’s banned texts of unholy wisdom. These boys have only one thing they hold sacred: The guitar riff in all its might and glory. </p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Napalm / Target</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/08e192deb5.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/7e9c2aeb91.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/the-sword/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="143">
<artistName><![CDATA[SYND OG SKAM]]></artistName>
<country>DK</country>
<scene><![CDATA[]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Mad, crooked post-punk.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Danish punk orchestra Synd Og Skam has arrived like a morning breeze.</p>
<p class="bodytext">So far, the noble savages have only released one EP, which was greeted with awed reviews from both critics and the public. Synd Og Skam share a vibe of having their backs against the wall and nothing to lose.</p>
<p class="bodytext">With pure poetry in Danish and semi-improvised post-punk, the Danes stir a very touching mélange of genres which is utterly dedicated to their own highly crooked vision of music and life.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Synd Og Skam, ladies and gentlemen, an imaginative, cryptic and very beautiful encounter.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Af med hovedet</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/d8e8be24bb.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/e301bfed29.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/synd-og-skam/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="144">
<artistName><![CDATA[TALBOT]]></artistName>
<country>EE</country>
<scene><![CDATA[]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Extremely heavy doom metal from the Baltic]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">They call themselves the heaviest duo on Earth. Using only bass, drums and some keyboards Talbot breaks down the gates of the underworld making a maelstrom of black matter engulf you, the innocent and curious music lover. And, yes – you did read that correctly. There are no guitars to be found anywhere. The two Estonians set new standards for the genre of doom metal making it even more remorseless and steaming cold than even the Baltic Sea.</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/806364aff8.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/831ef20f0e.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/talbot/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="145">
<artistName><![CDATA[THEN COMES SILENCE ]]></artistName>
<country>SE</country>
<scene><![CDATA[]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Gothic noise rock]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Based in a dogma of total anonymity this Swedish band play their gothic noise rock cloaked in shadows. The self-titled debut album was fittingly released in the fall. In it the black silhouettes display their control of grinding guitars, booming bass and world-weariness. It is loud; it is noisy, like Black Rebel Motorcycle Club in Halloween-masks. It is evidence of the amount of psychedelic nuances found in the colour black.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Novoton / Import</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/a097be95ff.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/4498e2d183.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/then-comes-silence/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="146">
<artistName><![CDATA[THROES + THE SHINE ]]></artistName>
<country>AO/PT</country>
<scene><![CDATA[]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Rock + kuduro]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext"><em>Rockuduro</em>, Throes + The Shine call their debut record, the title offers a good description of a brand new music genre: A surprising rendezvous between alternative guitar rock and kuduro, the up-tempo dance music of Angola. This double band is a fully organic mashup introducing the song and rap of kuduro on top of guitar tones and drums from bearded indie kids. Throes + The Shine may be one of the first African-sounding dance bands to appear naturally along with American acts like Battles and HEALTH, as they’ve done in the past.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Lovers &amp; Lollypops / Import</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/1046b2c2dd.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/eddddefa90.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/throes-the-shine/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="147">
<artistName><![CDATA[TORKELSEN]]></artistName>
<country>NO</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Apollo Countdown]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Instrumental electronica]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Röyksopp meet Boards of Canada in the sound world of Norwegian producer Torkelsen, who’s currently enjoying international acclaim. </p>
<p class="bodytext">With elements of glitch, instrumental hip hop and frostbitten soundscapes, the young beat smith has evolved a Scandinavian electronica more shimmering than the ice caps. On other releases, like <em>Torsnes Beats vol. 2</em>, the beats have more energy, “dirt and lo-fi elements”, according to Torkelsen himself. </p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Sellout! Music / Import</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/4314e731b0.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/a3eade464f.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/torkelsen/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="148">
<artistName><![CDATA[ROKIA TRAORÉ]]></artistName>
<country>ML</country>
<scene><![CDATA[]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[North African diva and global music star]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">She pays her third visit to Roskilde Festival this year. And a voice like that of Rokia Traoré is an even greater need today than ever before.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Today she serves as a voice for not just Mali, but the entire African continent. Her forthcoming album is called Beautiful Africa and has regular PJ Harvey wingman John Parish producing.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Rokia Traoré uses West African traditions as a stepping stone, but her live shows first and foremost embody the funky and electric Africa. You can also tell that the diplomat's daughter has listened to music from all over the globe throughout her life.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Nonesuch / import</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>2</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/a85abf7202.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/cf13b1000c.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/rokia-traore-2/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="149">
<artistName><![CDATA[ÁSGEIR TRAUSTI]]></artistName>
<country>IS</country>
<scene><![CDATA[]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Singer/songwriter on his way up ]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">He may be the hottest new Icelandic act right now. Ásgeir Trausti’s songs are well on their way to reach the world outside the volcanic island.</p>
<p class="bodytext">The classical trained talent’s music is based on naked, beautiful songs, written and played on his acoustic guitar and spiced up with electronic features.</p>
<p class="bodytext">At Roskilde Festival he will bring a full band. The band version of the concerts includes musicians who normally play in his older brother’s reggae band Hjálmar.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Sena / import</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/a4351952b3.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/2448f6e8c3.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/asgeir-trausti/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="150">
<artistName><![CDATA[TRAVELLING TRIBES]]></artistName>
<country>DK</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Pavilion Junior]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Psychedelic globalists]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">With ever-moving foothold in both alternative rock and global sounds, Travelling Tribes have made their way into a Copehagen scene of psychedelica unafraid to make the musical paint box merge altogether. Tribal percussion, foreign melodies on the cello, synthesizers and impressionistic guitars are along for the ride when this bold collective cross the continents and head for the remote villages. </p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: ILK</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/7300e8f0e0.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/e992b83e93.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/travelling-tribes/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="151">
<artistName><![CDATA[TREMORO TARANTURA]]></artistName>
<country>NO</country>
<scene><![CDATA[]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Improvisational noise orchestra for the adventurous]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">90 % improvisation. Tremoro Tarantura play their music ”on location” and never enter a studio. As a consequence they are led on their journey into the storm of noise- and avant-garde rock music by any impressions or ideas that may come to them in the spur of the moment. The Norwegian improvisers share nationality with appraised orchestras like the post jazz band Supersilent. We can expect a cacophony of sound from all the colours of the musical rainbow – according to one source the Norwegians find their inspiration everywhere from AC/DC, the harsh composer Penderecki and the velvety Frenchman Serge Gainsbourg.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Fysisk Format / Import</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/9cd9ad157d.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/57489c2503.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/tremoro-tarantura/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="152">
<artistName><![CDATA[TRULS]]></artistName>
<country>NO</country>
<scene><![CDATA[]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Alternative rock icon takes over R&B]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">R&amp;B and alternative rock has been giving each other flirtatious looks for quite some time. Truls Heggero has taken the final step and decided to get into the bed with urban, glittery pop music. The celebrated songwriter, vocalist and composer won the appraisal of the audience working with Lukestar, who played at Roskilde Festival in 2011. The Norwegian falsetto towered above guitar-laden power pop with a Nordic feel. As of now the guitar strings are less prominent and replaced by booty shaking electronic pop and soul. Judging by initial responses this brave change of clothing will continue to please fans of the big man’s former bands.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: EMI Norge / Import</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/30c1d0eb48.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/134765c839.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/truls/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="153">
<artistName><![CDATA[TURBONEGRO]]></artistName>
<country>NO</country>
<scene><![CDATA[]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Punky garage rock with devil horns and hard-ons]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">The Denim-Demons of Turbonegro are back at Roskilde for the first time since 2005. A new lead singer has joined the fray and the barks of Tony Sylvester has given the Norwegians a fresh shot of punk in the jugular, which is very evident on the comeback album <em>Sexual Harrassment</em>. Rarely has garage rock with devil horns and a permanent hard-on been played better than by this pack of crazed dogs. Turbonegro is set to save rock music with a set of guitar solos which will give you whiplash and pure and simple energy stuffed with shooters and kinky sex – and they will send it back where it belongs: In the arms of the Devil himself.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Volcom Entertainment / Import</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>2</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/869f0b5582.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/b978bd09fa.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/turbonegro-3/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="154">
<artistName><![CDATA[TYRANNY]]></artistName>
<country>FI</country>
<scene><![CDATA[]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Draggingly slow Funeral Doom]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Funeral Doom is a subgenre in extreme metal, in which everything sounds like it is played in slow motion. The music marches like a funeral procession towards annihilation. The Finnish duo Tyranny is one of the strongest lineups in the genre. Their extremely prolonged mini-symphonies depict the lot of the human race as seen from the icy cold perspective of eternity. Tyranny’s vocals are dragged from the blackest reaches of the cosmos, the guitar riffs and minor keyed keyboards drags the music to the limit of imagination without stalling the march of darkness completely.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Firebox / Target</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/12ffa70194.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/a2daa41489.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/tyranny/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="155">
<artistName><![CDATA[UNCLE ACID & THE DEADBEATS ]]></artistName>
<country>UK</country>
<scene><![CDATA[]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Devious hard rock from the cellar tombs
]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">With a mixture of darkly psychedelic hard rock and heavy metal, Uncle Acid &amp; The Deadbeats have gathered what is practically a small cult around their name. </p>
<p class="bodytext">There is a hefty groove behind the zip of the leather trousers and the boys from Cambridge seem inspired by gory horror flicks, Charles Manson and their old Alice Cooper and Black Sabbath vinyls. <em>Mind Control</em>, the band’s third record, will see the light of day soon. </p>
<p class="bodytext">Uncle Acid &amp; The Deadbeats will be a revelation for everybody with a penchant for memorable melodies and nostalgic fuzz guitars. </p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Rise Above / Target</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/9d9465576c.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/98c81eafdc.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/uncle-acid-the-deadbeats/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="156">
<artistName><![CDATA[UNKNOWN MORTAL ORCHESTRA]]></artistName>
<country>NZ/US</country>
<scene><![CDATA[]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Swampy, melodic acid rock]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">The poppy acid rock songs of Ruban Nielson made the world want a piece of him, before his trippy sugar cubes were even ready for consumption.</p>
<p class="bodytext">This year’s follow-up album, <em>II</em>, has just arrived. It carries on with flickering sunshine, laid-back nonchalance and heartwarming melodies. <em> </em></p>
<p class="bodytext">Unknown Mortal Orchestra gazes reverently at late The Beatles and early Pink Floyd, and the acid trip also has a slack, home-made vibe reminiscent of a young Beck. </p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Jagjaguwar / Cosmos</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/57207520c9.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/781396f3af.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/unknown-mortal-orchestra/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="157">
<artistName><![CDATA[URBAN CONE]]></artistName>
<country>SE</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Pavilion Junior]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Melodic synth pop]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">With enthustiastic live shows and well-timed releases, Urban Cone have moved into position as the new wonder boys of Swedish pop. The international blog community has taken notice, as well. Urban Cone’s dance friendly synth pop shows love of The Human League and other neon classics. At the same time, Urban Cone are gifted with an acute ear for pop tunes so characteristic of the Swedes. </p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Universal Music Sweden / Import</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/88048753c1.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/66660e7422.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/urban-cone/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="158">
<artistName><![CDATA[UZ]]></artistName>
<country>US</country>
<scene><![CDATA[]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Masked bass-avenger]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Flosstradamus, Toddla T and Diplo have praised him. Everyone from the dj/producer Dave Nade to the porn actress Jessie Andrews have claimed to be the person behind the mask – the true ƱZ. Like Batman or Banksy, ƱZ  lives in the shadows and makes the imagination put in extra hours. The mysterious individual paved the way for perhaps the first musical genre born exclusively on the Internet: Trap is a wild mix of digital bass, dubstep and house. The cartoon-like music has been raised in the schizophrenic greenhouses of YouTube and Soundcloud and ƱZ belongs to the crème de la crème of the crazy beat makers of the 10s.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Jeffree's / Import</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/8f76c400d5.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/4445934770.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/uz/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="159">
<artistName><![CDATA[MARCOS VALLE]]></artistName>
<country>BR</country>
<scene><![CDATA[]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Brazilian pop pioner]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Since 1963, Marcos Valle has been a pioner of Brazilian music. He has combined Western pop music, soul and jazz with bossa nova and other genres bursting with vitamin D. With his gentle, conversing voice he makes the snug music glow with well-being and ease. Underneath, however, there is also a political bite. The cozy music with its breezy flutes, groovy guitars, Hammond organ and jazzy electric piano has claws found in the lyrics. Marcos Valle deserves a place as one of Brazil’s major icons alongside Gilberto Gil and Caetana Veloso.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Far Out / Import</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/9420097d6a.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/9add42763d.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/marcos-valle-1/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="160">
<artistName><![CDATA[VANLIGT FOLK]]></artistName>
<country>SE</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Pavilion Junior]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Darkly industrial post punk]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">With inspiration from 80s no wave, post punk and dark industrial, Vanligt Folk have already won several Swedish black hearts. </p>
<p class="bodytext">DAF, Nitzer Ebb and Einstürzende Neubauten are just a few of the benchmarks that have been deduced from the trio’s self-titled EP. Cold synths and ominous cold war atmosphere played and sung with insisting endurance. </p>
<p class="bodytext">With only one EP, we have only seen the early shapes of the black swan Vanligt Folk may turn into. </p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Progress Productions / Import</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/3ea5366f40.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/b713a9375a.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/vanligt-folk/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="161">
<artistName><![CDATA[VATICAN SHADOW]]></artistName>
<country>US</country>
<scene><![CDATA[]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Islamist-inspired industrial techno.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Dominick Fernow focuses on the war on terror with his Vatican Shadow project. With electronic loops, he takes us into a world of Islamic uprising, military buildup and blood-dripping partisan warfare.</p>
<p class="bodytext">The American's disturbing electro is dark, dystopian and industrial – yet, the whole universe is recognisable from news channels’ restless broadcasting.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Vatican Shadow is not the versatile American's only project. He also records under the name Prurient and is head of the trendsetting record label Hospital Productions.</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/d43d4caf2f.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/fe5b7d17bd.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/vatican-shadow/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="162">
<artistName><![CDATA[VINNIE WHO]]></artistName>
<country>DK</country>
<scene><![CDATA[]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Funky prince of pop]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">You have to be made of stone to not want a pair of golden shoes, a suit and plenty of hair gel when Vinnie Who takes the stage with copious amounts of synths and soprano vocals. Niels Bagge, which is the real name behind the disco comet, keep drawing fresh souls towards the mirror ball-light, where good melodies and delicate movements of the hip just keep going. At 2013’s <em>Midnight Special</em> it will be made clear that the talented singer and songwriter intends to stay. An uncompromising will to make intelligent disco has given Vinnie Who the title of funky pop prince of Denmark.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: EMI</p>
<p class="bodytext"> </p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/e11d0a811b.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/ba793e753d.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/vinnie-who-1/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="163">
<artistName><![CDATA[VOLBEAT]]></artistName>
<country>DK</country>
<scene><![CDATA[]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Galloping Elvis metal.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Rock, roll and metal in perfect harmony has been the foundation that has helped Volbeat all the way to the top.</p>
<p class="bodytext">On an unparalleled ride towards the top of the metal scene, the lads have developed a unique blend of melodic stadium heavy rock, packed as tight straw bale with equal parts power and hit potential.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Today they don’t bow and scrape to anyone on the European metal scene. The US is also conquered. Tour buddies and source of inspiration, Metallica, are now friends of the band.</p>
<p class="bodytext">In 2013, Volbeat will make another impact. A new, galloping rock album is released this spring.</p>
<p class="bodytext">The homecoming at Roskilde Festival will be a proud reunion with some local heroes whose world domination is about to be a reality.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Universal</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>1</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/5af3800a73.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/a2252972b9.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/volbeat-3/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="164">
<artistName><![CDATA[VOODOO GLOW SKULLS]]></artistName>
<country>US</country>
<scene><![CDATA[]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Chilli-infused ska punk]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">”Shoot the Moon” Voodoo Glow Skulls proclaim in one of their classic songs. The style defining collective has aimed for the sky since 1988. Their songs roar along in a fiery hurricane of punk, ska and trombones – like Bad Religion, Sick Of It All and The Specials rolled into one pumped up orchestra. Using political aggression, humour and the characteristically Californian mixture of Spanish and English, Voodoo Glow Skulls has showed no intention of slowing down despite a 25 year long career. Look forward to being run over when Voodoo Glow Skulls let the black magic explode during the late hours of Roskilde Festival.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Smelvis / Import</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/0816c92ebc.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/11e2c37255.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/voodoo-glow-skulls-1/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="165">
<artistName><![CDATA[WHEN SAINTS GO MACHINE]]></artistName>
<country>DK</country>
<scene><![CDATA[]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Flamboyant, electronic pop.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">Flamboyant band When Saints Go Machine opened the Orange Stage in 2010 with their electronic, velvety pop. International music media have also taken note of the Copenhagen dandies fronted by the incomparably versatile singer Nicholas Vonsild in front.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Their impressionistic sound is permeated by a desire to experiment. Yet, the melodies and delicate sway of the hips are never abandoned. And their latest single &quot;Mannequin&quot; demonstrates that the towering ambition is unlikely to be lowered on the upcoming album.</p>
<p class="bodytext">When Saints Go Machine continues to win new fans among both audiences and critics. An elegant swan with neatly painted feathers.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: EMI</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/c7aad9559b.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/e70b683b94.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/when-saints-go-machine-2/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="166">
<artistName><![CDATA[MATTHEW E. WHITE]]></artistName>
<country>US</country>
<scene><![CDATA[]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Heart warming soul rock]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">On his breakthrough album <em>Big Inner</em> Matthew E. White mixes soul, jazzy soft rock and folk in a way that makes listening to the record feel like having your bones warmed by the sun. The music could be described as gospel for hipsters and doubters. But Mr. White’s songs sizzle with an amount of American musical history, enough to make the long tracks seem thrumming with reality and sincerity. Matthew E. White transfers the album to the stage accompanied by the heavily armed Spacebomb. The young master and his backing band will make sure to hit you squarely in the softest part of your solar plexus with every trembling tone.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Domino / Playground</p>
<p class="bodytext"> </p>
<p class="bodytext"> </p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/477deced17.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/81989a90bd.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/matthew-e-white/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="167">
<artistName><![CDATA[JONATHAN WILSON]]></artistName>
<country>US</country>
<scene><![CDATA[]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Mellow folk rock with a scent of California]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">If Jonathan Wilson’s Californian, autumn-colored rock songs don’t sound like the work of a debutant it may be due to the fact that he moonlights as a session musician for legends such as Jackson Browne and Robbie Robertson of The Band. However, this guy is just as well off on his own. </p>
<p class="bodytext">Jonathan Wilson’s psychedelic songs combine country, folk and rock with a scent of Laurel Canyon, 1968. At the same time, you can tell that this artist was born in the 70s. Wilson is a contemporary songwriter who deserves to be mentioned alongside Bon Iver and Midlake.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Bella Union / Cooperative</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/0015d5877f.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/9ce1d7ac5b.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/jonathan-wilson/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="168">
<artistName><![CDATA[WINTERGATAN]]></artistName>
<country>SE</country>
<scene><![CDATA[]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Electronic music box.]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="MsoNormal">Listening to Wintergatan is like a journey into the world of a shimmering music box with a bunch of mainly electronic musicians as guides. </p>
<p class="MsoNormal">The brain behind Detektivbyrån, who played Roskilde Festival 2007, is also the main man here. </p>
<p class="MsoNormal">And even though only two songs are shared with the public so far, Wintergatan displays a flair for poetic sound images not unlike those of Frenchman Yann Tiersen. </p>
<p class="MsoNormal">Barrel organ-esque tones dominate the innocent and mildly mournful soundscapes. The Swedes will release their debut album this spring. </p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/169c50914e.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/a263fafe59.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/wintergatan/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="169">
<artistName><![CDATA[THE WOKEN TREES]]></artistName>
<country>DK</country>
<scene><![CDATA[Pavilion Junior]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[Ominous post punk]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">With an acute sense of style, The Woken Trees have impressed music lovers with their self-assured debut album <em>NNON</em>. Their post punk update sounds like Joy Division heading for some occult mass at midnight: The bleakness of Manchester replaced with the claustrophobia of the deep woods. Moodily, they dwell on their evil bass lines, insisting rhythms and jarring guitars. Take a trip into The Woken Trees’ black labyrinth. Even on the brightest of Roskilde summer days, the sun will have a hard time finding its way.   </p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: Fuzz Club</p>]]></description>
<prioritet>3</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/93be7de318.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/af6aa027c6.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/the-woken-trees/]]></link>
</item>
<item id="170">
<artistName><![CDATA[BOBBY WOMACK]]></artistName>
<country>US</country>
<scene><![CDATA[]]></scene>
<tidspunkt><![CDATA[]]></tidspunkt>
<timestamp><![CDATA[]]></timestamp>
<original_timestamp><![CDATA[]]></original_timestamp>
<text><![CDATA[The Last Soul Man]]></text>
<description><![CDATA[<p class="bodytext">He was ready to abandon music, but Gorillaz persuaded him to sing on <em>Plastic Beach</em> as well as our Orange Stage in 2010. Anyone present heard a majestic soul voice. Among the last, against all odds, still standing titans of the golden era. A voice trembling with more experience than most people achieve or care for in a lifetime. Now this great artist takes the stage on his own, bringing his first solo record for the last 18 years in his rucksack. <em>The Bravest Man In The Universe </em>was produced by Damon Albarn among others, the record combines vintage soul and contemporary British sounds. Don’t miss this meeting with a great voice and true one of a kind.</p>
<p class="bodytext">Label: XL - Playground</p>
<p class="bodytext"> </p>]]></description>
<prioritet>2</prioritet>
<tab text="" color="#E74313" textColor="#FFFFFF" />
<imageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/d237efb916.jpg]]></imageUrl>
<mediumimageUrl><![CDATA[typo3temp/pics/e55e3f86c7.jpg]]></mediumimageUrl>
<link><![CDATA[band/singleband/bobby-womack/]]></link>
</item>
</bandPreview>